[
  {
    "id": "1919",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:33",
    "question": "The word Liahona only appears once in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1920",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "The word Liahona appears how many times in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "Once",
    "options": ["Once", "Twice", "Thrice"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1921",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book does the word Liahona first appear?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "1922",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "The Liahona conta1ned_____that pointed the way Lehi and his company should travel.",
    "answer": "Spindle",
    "options": ["Spindle", "Spindles", "No Spindles"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2568",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:11&Mos17:20",
    "question": "According to Alma1; Abinidi is considered to be the first prophet in Nephite history to die from fire because of his beliefs and also because of his belief in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2964",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:1",
    "question": "In what year of the judges did King Mosiahdie?_____",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "(2)", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2965",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:1",
    "question": "In the Book of Alma:  Mormon wrote that King Mosiah had “warred a good warfare, walking uprightly before God”.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2966",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:2",
    "question": "In the first year in the reign of Alma in the judgment-seat, there was a man brought before him to be judged, a man who was_____, and was noted for much strength.",
    "answer": "Large",
    "options": ["Small", "Overweight", "Large"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2967",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:3",
    "question": "The man that was brought forth to Alma to be judged had gone about among the people, preaching to them which he determ1ned to be the word of_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2968",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:3",
    "question": "The man was also bearing down against the church; declaring that every_____ and teacher should become popular; and that they should not labor with their hands.",
    "answer": "Priest",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2969",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:3",
    "question": "The man also declared that every priest and teacher should be supported by whom?  The",
    "answer": "people",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2970",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:4",
    "question": "The large man also testified unto the people that all mankind should be saved in the_____ day. And that they need not fear or tremble.",
    "answer": "Last",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2971",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:4",
    "question": "The large man also said that the Lord had created all men, and had also redeemed all men; and, in the end, all men should have eternal life.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2972",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the large man did teach these things so much that many of the _____ believed his words, that they began to support him and give him money.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Priests", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2973",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:6",
    "question": "The large man began to be lifted up in the pride of his heart, and to wear_____ apparel.",
    "answer": "Costly",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2974",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:6",
    "question": "The large man began to establish a church after the manner of his preaching.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2975",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as the large man was going about the land, he met a man who belonged to the church of_____, and he was teacher in the church.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2976",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:7",
    "question": "The large man started to contend with the man of the church sharply, that he might lead away the people of the church; but the man withstood him, admonishing him with the words of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2977",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:8",
    "question": "What was the name of the man that admonished the large man with his words?",
    "answer": "Gideon",
    "options": ["Abinidi", "Samuel The Lamanite", "Gideon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2978",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:8",
    "question": "Gideon was the man that was an instrument in the hands of God in delivering the people of King_____ out of bondage.",
    "answer": "Limhi",
    "options": ["Benjamin", "Limhi", "Mosiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2979",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:9",
    "question": "The large man was wroth with Gideon; because Gideon was stricken with many years he could not defend himself and the large man slew him with his_____.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["Sword", "Knife", "Tomahawk"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2980",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:10",
    "question": "The large man was taken by the people to what Nephites’ judge to be judged according to the crimes which he had committed?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2981",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:11",
    "question": "The large man stood before Alma2 and pleaded for himself with much_____.",
    "answer": "Boldness",
    "options": ["Arrogance", "Moxie", "Boldness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2982",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:12",
    "question": "What did Alma2 say to the large man that he had introduced to the people for the first time?",
    "answer": "Priestcraft",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2983",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told the large man that he was not only guilty of priestcraft, but had endeavored to enforce it by the sword.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2984",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:12",
    "question": "What did Alma2 say to the large man would prove to be the entire destruction of the people if they would to embrace it?",
    "answer": "Priestcraft",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2985",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told the large man that he had not only shed the blood of a righteous man, but the blood of a man that had done much good among the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2986",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:14",
    "question": "Alma did not condemn the large man to die according to the law which was given to them by King Mosiah.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2987",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:15",
    "question": "The name of the large man who had slew Gideon with his sword was_____.",
    "answer": "Nehor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2988",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:15",
    "question": "What was the name of the hill which the people took Nehor to die; and he suffered an ignominious death?",
    "answer": "Manti",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2989",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:15",
    "question": "Before Nehor died he acknowledge between the heavens and the earth that what he had taught the people was contrary to the word of_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2990",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:16",
    "question": "When Nehor died it put an end to priestcrafts.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2991",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:16",
    "question": "There were many people who loved the_____ things of the world, and they went forth preaching false doctr1nes in order to get rich and to obtain honor from the people.",
    "answer": "Vain",
    "options": ["Good", "Pretty", "Vain"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2992",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:17",
    "question": "During the time of Alma2 as the chief judge, liars were punished; therefore they pretended to preach according to their belief.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2993",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:17",
    "question": "During the time of Alma the chief judge he could punish people for their beliefs.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2994",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:18",
    "question": "Murder was punishable by death during the time that Alma2 the chief judge was the peoples’ judge.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2995",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:19",
    "question": "And it came to pass that those that did not belong to the church of God began to persecute those that did belong to the church of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2996",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:22",
    "question": "Many of those that did not belong to the church of God began to be proud and contend with their adversaries, even unto blows; they would smite one another with their_____.",
    "answer": "Fists",
    "options": ["Swords", "Fists", "Knives"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2997",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:23",
    "question": "The fighting between the people of the church and those that were not of the church occurred in what year of Alma2’s reign?",
    "answer": "2nd",
    "options": ["1st", "2nd", "3rd"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2998",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:24",
    "question": "Because of the fighting many of the peoples hearts were hardened, and their names were_____ out, and they were remembered no more among the people of God.",
    "answer": "Blotted",
    "options": ["Erased", "Scratch", "Blotted"]
  },
  {
    "id": "2999",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:25",
    "question": "The people of the church suffered much persecution; nevertheless, they were_____ and immovable in keeping the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "Steadfast",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3000",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:26",
    "question": "During this time in Nephite history all the people were equal, and they did all labor, every man according to his own strength.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3001",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:27",
    "question": "The people imparted of their substance, every man according to that which he had, to the poor, and the needy, and the_____; and they did not were costly apparel.",
    "answer": "Afflicted",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3002",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:29",
    "question": "Because of the stead1ness of the people of the church they began to be exceedingly rich, having abundance of all things whatsoever they stood in need of.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3003",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:30",
    "question": "Because of their prosperity the people did not send any away that were naked, or that were hungry, or that were sick.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3004",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:31",
    "question": "The people that did not belong to the church were more wealthy than the people that did belong to the church of God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3005",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:32",
    "question": "Those who did not belong to the church of God indulge in sorceries, idolatry or idleness, and in babblings.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3006",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:32",
    "question": "The law was not enforced on the people that did wickedness and committed robberies.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3007",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma1:33",
    "question": "And it came to pass that by exercising the law upon the people that committed crimes; people began to not commit crimes, and therefore, there was peace again among the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Lehi", "Nephi", "Samuel The Lamanite"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3008",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma1:2",
    "question": "During the fifth year of the reign of the judges there began to be contention among the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3009",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:1",
    "question": "What was the name of the man that came among the Nephites during the fifth year of the reign of the judges that was very cunning and wise as to the wisdom of the world?",
    "answer": "Amilici",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3010",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma1:15 & Alma2:1",
    "question": "Amilici was after the order of_____ who had slew Gideon and was executed according to the law.",
    "answer": "Nehor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3011",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:2",
    "question": "Because Amilici was very cunning he drew away many people and they began to be very powerful.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3012",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:2",
    "question": "The very powerful people that Amilici had on his side desired to make him the_____ over the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "King",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3013",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:3",
    "question": "The people of the church of God were alarmed because they knew that according to Nephite law, such things- as electing a king must be established by the voice of the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3014",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:4",
    "question": "Amlici was not a wicked man and did not want to destroy the church of God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3015",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:4",
    "question": "Amlici is considered to be one of the four Anti-Christ’ in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3016",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:7",
    "question": "The voice of the people did not favor_____ and he was not made king over the people.",
    "answer": "Amlici",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3017",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:9,10",
    "question": "Amlici was made king over some of the people and he stirred his people to anger against their brethren and to take arms against them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3018",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:10",
    "question": "Amlici wanted to make some of the Nephites as his_____.",
    "answer": "Subjects",
    "options": ["Subjects", "Slaves", "Laborers"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3019",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:11",
    "question": "The people that were under the rule of Amlici were called_____; and the rest of the people were called Nephites, or the people of God.",
    "answer": "Amlicites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3020",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:12",
    "question": "The Nephites armed themselves with cimeters, stones, slings, and with_____, to go to battle against the Amlicites.",
    "answer": "Swords",
    "options": ["Guns", "Axes", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3021",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:16",
    "question": "Because_____ was the chief judge and governor of the Nephites; he went at the head of his armies to do battle with Amlici and his armies.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3022",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:18",
    "question": "Who strengthened the hand of the Nephites that they slew many of the Amlicites?",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3023",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:20",
    "question": "When Alma and his armies could no longer pursue Amlici and his armies they pitched their tents in the valley of_____ that was called after the name of the man that Nehor had slain with his sword.",
    "answer": "Gideon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3024",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:21",
    "question": "Alma sent spies to follow the remnant of the Amlicites that he might know of their plans and their plots.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3025",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:24",
    "question": "The spies that Alma sent to watch the Amlicites were astonished because the Amlicites had jo1ned forces with the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Lamanites", "Ismaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3026",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites departed out of the valley of Gideon towards their city, which was the city of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["Sidon", "Zarahemla", "Minon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3027",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:27",
    "question": "As the Nephites were crossing the river_____, the Lamanites and Amlicites, which were as numerous as the sands of the sea; came upon them to destroy them.",
    "answer": "Sidon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3028",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:28",
    "question": "Because the Nephites had prayed mightily to the Lord, he heard their cries and did strengthen them and the Lamanites and Amlicites did fall before them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3029",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:29",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 fought with_____ with the sword, face to face and contended mightily, one with another.",
    "answer": "Amlici",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3030",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:30",
    "question": "Because Alma2 was a man of God he exercised much faith and cried to the Lord to spare his life so that he could be an instrument in his hands and preserve the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3031",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:31",
    "question": "What kind of weapon of war did Alma2 use to slay Amlici?",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["Knife", "Gun", "Sword"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3032",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:31",
    "question": "Alma2 was strengthened by the Lord and he slew_____ with his sword.",
    "answer": "Amlici",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3033",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:32",
    "question": "Alma2 also contended with the king of the Lamanites but he fled and sent his guards to contend with Alma2",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3034",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma2:37",
    "question": "What is the name of the wilderness that was infested by wild and ravenous beasts that the Lamanites and Amlicites fled to?",
    "answer": "Hermounts",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3035",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma2:38",
    "question": "Many of the Lamanites and Amlicites did not die because of their wounds when the fled into the part of the wilderness called Hermouts",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3036",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2:38",
    "question": "Many of the dead Lamanites bodies were devoured by the wild beasts and also by what birds of prey?",
    "answer": "Vultures",
    "options": ["Hawks", "Eagles", "Vultures"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3037",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that many of the bodies of the Lamanites and Amlicites who had been slain were cast into the waters of Sidon and their bones are in the depths of the_____.",
    "answer": "Sea",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3038",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:4",
    "question": "What color was the mark that the Amlicites had marked themselves on the forehead to distinguish them from the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Red",
    "options": ["Red", "White", "Blue"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3039",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:4",
    "question": "Not only had the Amlicites mark themselves with the color red on their foreheads they had also shaved their heads like the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3040",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:",
    "question": "The heads of the Lamanites were shaved and they were naked except for the parts that were covered by their armor.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3041",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:6",
    "question": "The skins of the Lamanites were_____, according the mark which was set upon their fathers, which was a curse upon them because of their transgression and rebellion against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Dark",
    "options": ["Black", "Brown", "Dark"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3042",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:6",
    "question": "The names of the brothers that the Lamanites fathers rebelled against were-Nephi, Jacob, Joseph, and_____.",
    "answer": "Sam",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3043",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:7",
    "question": "The Lord God set a mark upon Laman and Lemuel, and also the sons of Ismael, and the Daughters of_____.",
    "answer": "Ismael",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3044",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:8",
    "question": "The Lord set a mark upon the Lamanites that their seed might be distinguished from the seed of their brethren, that thereby he might preserve his people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3045",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:8",
    "question": "The Lord also set a mark upon the Lamanites that they might not mix and believe in the incorrect_____ of their fathers; which would prove their destruction.",
    "answer": "Traditions",
    "options": ["Religion", "Beliefs", "Traditions"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3046",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that whosoever did mingle his seed with that of the_____ did bring the same curse upon his seed.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3047",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:11",
    "question": "Those that believed in those records which were brought out of Jerusalem, and also in the traditions of their fathers were called Lamanites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3048",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:11",
    "question": "Those that believed in the correct traditions of their fathers according to the records which were brought from Jerusalem and kept the commandments of God were called_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3049",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:12",
    "question": "What is the name of the people that have kept the records which are true of their people, and also of the Lamanite people called?",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3050",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:14",
    "question": "The word of the Lord was fulfilled when he told Nephi:”the Lamanites have I cursed, and I will set a mark on them that they and their seed may be separated from thy seed”.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3051",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:14",
    "question": "The mark or curse that the Lord set upon the Lamanites will not last forever, except they repent of their wickedness and turn to the Lord that he may have mercy upon them.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3052",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:18",
    "question": "The Amlicites did not know that they were fulfilling the word of the Lord when they began to mark themselves in their foreheads.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3053",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:18",
    "question": "The_____ had come out in open rebellion against God; therefore it was expedient that the curse should fall upon them.",
    "answer": "Amlicites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3054",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:19",
    "question": "Mormon writes that the Amlicites brought upon themselves the curse; and so does every man that is cursed bring upon himself his own comdemnation.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3055",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:22",
    "question": "The second time the Lamanites came to battle with the Nephites; Alma did not go to battle against them because he was afflicted with a_____.",
    "answer": "Wound",
    "options": ["Wound", "Cold", "Bad Back"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3056",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma3:26",
    "question": "In one year there were thousands and tens of thousands of souls sent to the eternal world, that they might reap their rewards according to their works, whether they were good or whether they were_____.",
    "answer": "Bad",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3057",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma3:26",
    "question": "The souls that went to the eternal world were to reap eternal happiness or eternal misery, according to the spirit which they listed to obey, whether it was a good spirit or a bad one.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3058",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma3:27",
    "question": "For every man receives wages of him whom he listens to obey, and this is according to the words of the_____ of prophecy.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Angel", "Spirit", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3059",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:3",
    "question": "Because many people believed that it was the judgments of God sent upon them because of their wickedness and their abominations; they were awakened to a remembrance of their duty.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3060",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:4",
    "question": "The people began to establish the church more fully and many were baptized by Alma2 in the waters of_____, because he had been consecrated a high priest.",
    "answer": "Sidon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3061",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:5",
    "question": "There were about 3,500 souls that had united themselves to the church of God and were baptized in the waters of Sidon.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3062",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:6",
    "question": "The people of the church began to wax proud because of their exceeding riches, and in their f1ne silks, and their f1ne-tw1ned l1nen, and their gold and silver.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3063",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:7",
    "question": "Because the people had begun to wax proud, _____ and his teachers, and priests, and elders of the church were sorely grieved for the wickedness which they saw that had begun among their people.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3064",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma4:8",
    "question": "Alma2 saw with great sorrow that the people of the church began to be lifted up in the pride of their_____.",
    "answer": "Eyes",
    "options": ["Hearts", "Eyes", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3065",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:8",
    "question": "Alma2 saw with great sorrow that the people also began to set their hearts upon riches and upon the vain things of the world.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3066",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:8",
    "question": "Those that belonged to the church of God began to persecute those that did not believe according to their own pleasure.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3067",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:9",
    "question": "Alma2 saw that there began to be great contentions among the people of the church because of their pride.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3068",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:9",
    "question": "There were envyings, strife, malice, persecutions, and pride even to exceed the pride of those that did not belong to the_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Church",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3069",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:10",
    "question": "The wickedness of the people of the church began to be a great stumbling-_____ to those who did not belong to the church; therefore the church began to fail in its progress.",
    "answer": "Block",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3070",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:11",
    "question": "In the commencement of the 9th year Alma2 saw the example of the wickedness of the church began to lead those who were unbelievers from one iniquity to another, thus bringing on the destruction of the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3071",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:12",
    "question": "Because of the inequality among the people; some were lifting themselves in their pride.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3072",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:12",
    "question": "Because of the inequality of people some began despising others, and turning their backs upon the needy, and the naked, and those that were hungry.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3073",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:13",
    "question": "Some of the people succored those who stood in need of succor, such as imparting their substance to the poor and needy, and suffering all manner of afflictions, for Christ’s sake, who should come according to the spirit of prophecy.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3074",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:14",
    "question": "Some of the people were not looking forward to the day when Christ would come retaining a remission of their sins.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3075",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:14",
    "question": "Some of the people were filled with joy because of the_____ of the dead, according to the will and power and deliverance of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Resurrection",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3076",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma4:16",
    "question": "Alma2 selected a_____ man among the elders of the church, and gave him power according to the voice of the people, to enact the laws according to the laws which had been given.",
    "answer": "Wise",
    "options": ["Large", "Ignorant", "Wise"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3077",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma4:17",
    "question": "The wise man that Alma2 selected to be a chief judge; and sat at the judgment-seat to judge and to govern the people was_____.",
    "answer": "Nephihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3078",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:18",
    "question": "Alma2 also granted Nephihah the office of high priest over the people of the church.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3079",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:19",
    "question": "Alma2 granted the judgment-seat to Nephihah so that he himself might go forth among the Nephites to preach the word of God unto them, to stir them up in remembrance of their duty.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3080",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:19",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted to pull down by the power of_____ all the pride and craft1ness and contentions which were among his people.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3081",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma4:20",
    "question": "When Alma2 delivered up his judgment-seat to Nephihah he conf1ned himself wholly to the high priesthood of the holy order of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3082",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma4:20",
    "question": "Alma2 also gave his testimony of the word, according to the spirit of_____ and prophecy.",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "options": ["Goodness", "Revelation", "Knowledge"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3083",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:1",
    "question": "What was the name of the land where Alma2 first went to deliver the word of God before he went to other places?",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3084",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:7",
    "question": "Because of Alma2’s words the people changed their hearts and were awakened out of a deep sleep or in a midst of darkness, and awoke unto God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3085",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:9,13",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that those that his father_____ had taught had broken the chains of hell which encircled them and had broken the bands of death because the faith in his words.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3086",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:13",
    "question": "Because the people in Alma the Elder’s life had a change of heart and did humble themselves and put their_____ in God and were faithful until the end; they were saved.",
    "answer": "Trust",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3087",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:15",
    "question": "Alma the Younger asked the people if they had exercised faith in the redemption of Jesus Christ who had created them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3088",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:15",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the people if they looked forward with an eye of_____, and view their mortal body raised in immortality, and this corruption raised incorruption.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Faith", "Soberness", "Clarity"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3089",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:20",
    "question": " Alma2 asked the people if thought they could be saved when they had yielded themselves to become subjects of the_____.",
    "answer": ["devil", "satan"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3090",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that no man can be saved except his_____are washed white and purified until they are cleansed from all stain.",
    "answer": "Garments",
    "options": ["Pants", "Robes", "Garments"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3091",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the only person who could clean their garments was Jesus Christ through his blood and that should come to redeem his people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3092",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:24",
    "question": "Alma2 said that murderers and also those that are guilty of all manner of wickedness can not have a place to sit down in the kingdom of God, with Abraham, with Isaac, and with_____.",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3093",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:27,28",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the people if they had kept themselves blameless before God within themselves and had been sufficiently humble, and if they had also been stripped of pride.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3094",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people if they had not been stripped of their pride they cannot be prepared to meet God; behold you must prepare quickly for the kingdom of heaven is soon at_____.",
    "answer": "Hand",
    "options": ["Hand", "Their Feet", "Daybreak"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3095",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:31,",
    "question": "Alma2 said if told the Nephites if they mock their brethren and persecute them they were not prepared to meet their God and the time is at hand that he must repent or he cannot be saved.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3096",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:32",
    "question": "Woe unto all workers of iniquity; repent, for the Lord_____ has spoken it!",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3097",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:33",
    "question": "Behold, the Lord sends an_____unto all men, for the arms of mercy are extended towards them, and he says:”Repent, and I will receive you”.",
    "answer": "Invitation",
    "options": ["Card", "Invitation", "Text Message"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3098",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:34",
    "question": "The Lord has said:”Come unto me and you shall partake of the fruit of the tree of_____; and shall eat and drink of the bread and the waters freely”.",
    "answer": "Life",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3099",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:35",
    "question": "Come unto me and bring forth works of_____, and you shall not be hewn down and cast into the fire of endless torment.",
    "answer": "Righteousness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3100",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:36",
    "question": "For behold, the time is at hand that whosoever brings forth not good fruit; or whosoever does not the works of righteousness, the same have cause to wail and mourn.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3101",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:37",
    "question": "Those that have professed to have known the way of righteousness and have nevertheless gone astray, as sheep having no shepherd, the Lord is still calling after you, but you will not hearken unto his voice!",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3102",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:38",
    "question": "The Lord still calls you which is the name of Christ; and if you will not hearken unto the voice of the_____ shepherd, to the name by which you are called, behold, you are not the sheep of the good shepherd.",
    "answer": "Good",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3103",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:39",
    "question": "According to Alma2; if we are not the fold of the good shepherd, we are of the Devil’s and his fold.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3104",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:40",
    "question": "Alma2 has said that whatsoever is good comes from God, and whatsoever is evil comes from the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3105",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:41",
    "question": "If a man brings forth good works he has hearkened unto the voice of the good shepherd, and follows him, and whosoever brings forth evil works, the same is a_____ of the devil.",
    "answer": "Child",
    "options": ["Person", "Child", "Woman"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3106",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:42",
    "question": "If we follow the devil our wages are of him; therefore, we receive death, as to the things pertaining unto righteousness, being dead unto all_____ works.",
    "answer": "Good",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3107",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:43",
    "question": "Alma2 spoke with the energy of all his soul to the Nephites and plainly that they could not err, and had spoken according to the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3108",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:44",
    "question": "Alma2 was called to speak after this manner, according to the_____ order of God, which is Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3109",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:44",
    "question": "Alma2 was not commanded to testify unto his people the things which had been spoken by their fathers concerning the things which are to come.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3110",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:46",
    "question": "Alma2 knew that the things which he had spoken to the Nephites were true because they were made know to him by the Holy_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3111",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:46",
    "question": "Alma2 had fasted and prayed many days in order that he might know the truth of the things he told the Nephites for himself.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3112",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:46",
    "question": "Alma2 knew the things which he told the people were true because they had been manifested to him by God by and his Holy Spirit which was the spirit of revelation.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3113",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:47",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that the things which had been revealed to him and the words which had been spoken by their fathers were true according to the spirit of_____ which was in him.",
    "answer": "Prophecy",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3114",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:48",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that he knew whatsoever thing he told them concerning that which is to come was true; and he said unto them that he knew that Jesus_____ shall come.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3115",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:48",
    "question": "Alma2 said to the Nephites that Jesus Christ was the only begotten son of God the Father, full of mercy, grace and truth.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3116",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:48",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that Jesus Christ would come to take away the sins of the_____, and the sins of every man who steadfastly believed in his name.",
    "answer": "World",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3117",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:49",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that he was called to preach unto his beloved brethren, and to every one that dwelled in the land both old and young, both bond and_____.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["Imprisoned", "Free", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3118",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:50",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that they must be born again, and repent, and all the ends of the earth, for the kingdom of heaven is soon at hand.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3119",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:50",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that the Son of God comes in his glory, in his might, majesty, power and dominion.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3120",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:50",
    "question": "Behold the glory of the King of all the earth; and also the King of heaven shall very soon sh1ne forth among all the children of_____.",
    "answer": "Men",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3121",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:51",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to repent; for except you repent you can nowise inherit the kingdom of_____.",
    "answer": "Heaven",
    "options": ["Planets", "Stars", "Heaven"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3122",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:52",
    "question": "Behold, the ax is laid at the root of the tree; therefore every tree that does not bring good fruit shall be hewn down and cast into the fire.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3123",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:52, 2Nep9:16, Mos3:27",
    "question": "The lake of fire and brimstone is a fire that cannot be consumed and is unquenchable.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3124",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:53",
    "question": "Alma2 told his beloved brethren not to lay aside the things which he had said and not to trample the Holy One under their_____.",
    "answer": "Feet",
    "options": ["Feet", "Legs", "Bodies"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3125",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:54",
    "question": "Those that have humbled themselves and do walk after the holy order of God, have been brought into the church and have been sanctified by the Holy_____, and they do bring forth good works which are meet for repentance.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3126",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:56",
    "question": "Those that persist in wickedness, these are they who shall be hewn down and cast into the fire except they speedily repent.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3127",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:57",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that those who were desirous to follow the voice of the good_____, to come out from the wicked people and separate themselves from them and to touch not unclean things.",
    "answer": "Shepherd",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3128",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:57",
    "question": "The words of the Lord were fulfilled when he said that the wicked shall mingle with the names of his people.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3129",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:58",
    "question": "What is the name of the book in which the names of the righteous is written on?",
    "answer": "Life",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3130",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma5:60",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people not to let no ravenous_____ enter among them, that they may be destroyed.",
    "answer": "Wolf",
    "options": ["Dog", "Raccoon", "Wolf"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3131",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:61",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that he spoke by way of commandment unto them in the language of him that had commanded him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3132",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma5:61",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Nephites not to observe to do the words which he had spoken unto them.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3133",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma5:62",
    "question": "Alma2 told those that did not belong to the church that he spoke to them by way of invitation, saying:'Come and be baptized unto repentance, that you also may be partakers of the fruit of the tree of_____'.",
    "answer": "Life",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3134",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma6:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that those who did not belong to the church and did not repent of their wickedness and humble themselves before God-the same were rejected.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3135",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma6:3",
    "question": "Those that did not humble themselves before God and repent; their names were blotted out, that their names were not numbered among those of the righteous.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3136",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma6:5",
    "question": "Mormon wants us to understand that the word of God was liberal unto all, that none were deprived of the privilege of assembling themselves together to hear the word of_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3137",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma6:7",
    "question": "After Alma2 had taught those in the city of Zarahemla he departed and left and went into the valley of Gideon to teach the people in the city of_____.",
    "answer": "Gideon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3138",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma6:8",
    "question": "Alma2 taught the people in the city of Gideon the truth of the word which had been spoken by his fathers, and according to the spirit of prophecy and his testimony of Jesus Christ the Son of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3139",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:1",
    "question": "In chapter seven of the Book of Alma; Alma2 delivers to the people in the city of Gideon the words which are written according to his record.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3140",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Gideon that he could not come sooner unto them because he had been conf1ned to the_____-seat, having had much bus1ness.",
    "answer": "Judgment",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3141",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people in the city Gideon that it was through much mercy that the Lord had granted unto him to come and teach them",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3142",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:3",
    "question": "Alma2 had hoped to find the people of the city of Gideon blameless before him, and that they were not in the awful dilemma that their brethren were in the city of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3143",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:4",
    "question": "The people in the city of Gideon had given Alma2 exceedingly great joy of knowing that they were established again in the way of the_____ and in his righteousness.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3144",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:5",
    "question": "Alma2 had much afflictions and sorrow because of the condition the people of Zarahemla were in.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3145",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:7",
    "question": "Alma2 went and declared the word of God to the people of the city Gideon and told them of many things to come.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3146",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of many things to come, but the thing that was more important than any other, was that the time was not to far distant that the_____ would live and come among his people.",
    "answer": "Redeemer",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3147",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that he did not mean that the Redeemer would come among them at the time of his dwelling in the mortal tabernacle; because the Spirit had not made it know unto him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3148",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Gideon that he did know that the Lord God has power to do all things which are according to his_____.",
    "answer": "Word",
    "options": ["Word", "Prophets", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3149",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people in Gideon that the Spirit had said to cry unto them and repent, and prepare the_____ of the Lord, and walk in his paths which are straight.",
    "answer": "Way",
    "options": ["Road", "Way", "Path"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3150",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:9",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell the people in Gideon that the Lord, the Son of God; would soon come to the earth.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3151",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Gideon that the Son of God would be born in what land? which was the land of their forefathers.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3152",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the name of the mother of the Son of God would be named what?",
    "answer": "Mary",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3153",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Gideon that Mary would be a virgin and a chosen vessel, who shall be overshadowed and conceive by the power of the Holy_____, and bring forth a son, even the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Ghost",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3154",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God would go forth, suffering pains and afflictions and temptations of every kind.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3155",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God’s would suffer that the word might be fulfilled which said that he would take upon him the pains and the sickness of his people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3156",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God would take upon him death, that he may loose the_____ of death which bind his people.",
    "answer": "Bands",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3157",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God would take upon him the infirmaties of his people, that his bowels may be filled with mercy, according to the_____.",
    "answer": "Flesh",
    "options": ["Body", "Flesh", "Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3158",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God would suffer all things that he may know according to the flesh how to succor his people according to their infirmities.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3159",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the_____ knows all things; nevertheless to Son of God would suffer according to the flesh that he might take upon him the sins of his people.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Spirit", "Satan", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3160",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the Son of God would take upon himself the sins of his people; that he may blot out their transgressions according to the power of his deliverance; and that this was his testimony.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3161",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:14",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell the people in the city of Gideon that they must repent and be born again or they could not inherit the kingdom of heaven.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3162",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to come and be_____ unto repentance; that they may be washed from their sins, and to have faith on the Lamb of God, who will take away the sins of the world.",
    "answer": "Baptized",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3163",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Son of God is not mighty to save and to cleanse his people from all unrighteousness.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3164",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:15",
    "question": "Alma2told the people to come forth, and show God that they were willing to repent of their sins and enter into a_____ with him to keep his commandments, and witness it unto him by going into the waters of baptism.",
    "answer": "Covenant",
    "options": ["Pact", "Oath", "Covenant"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3165",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that those that were baptize and keep the commandments of God would have_____ life, according to the testimony of the Holy Spirit, which testified unto him.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3166",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:19",
    "question": "Alma2 said I perceive that you are in the paths of righteousness",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3167",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites that the Lord never varies from that which he has said; neither does he turn from the right to the left, or from that which is right to that which is wrong.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3169",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord can enter anything that is filthy and anything that is unclean can also be received into the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3170",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said “and it shall be at the last day, that he who is filthy shall remain in his filth1ness",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3171",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people many things so that he could awaken them to a sense of their_____ to God; that they may walk blameless before him, and walk in his holy order after they had received him.",
    "answer": "Duty",
    "options": ["Right", "Duty", "Acceptance"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3172",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to be humble and be submissive and gentle; easy to be entreated; full of patience and long-suffering; being_____ in all things.",
    "answer": "Temperate",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3173",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites to be diligent in keeping the commandments of God at all times; asking for whatsoever things that they stand in need of, both spiritual and_____.",
    "answer": "Temporal",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3174",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:23",
    "question": "Alma2 tells us that we should always return thanks to God for whatsoever things we receive from him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3175",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma7:24",
    "question": "Alma2 says that we should have faith, hope, and_____, and then we will always abound in good works.",
    "answer": "Charity",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3176",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma7:25",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people in Gideon that there have been holy prophets since the world began.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3177",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma7:27",
    "question": "Alma2 wished that the people Gideon would have the_____ of God rest upon them and their houses, lands, and all they possess, according to their faith and good works.",
    "answer": "Peace",
    "options": ["Spirit", "Peace", "Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3178",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:1",
    "question": "All the things that Alma2 taught the people in the city of Gideon are written down for the record.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3179",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:1",
    "question": "After Alma2 taught the people in Gideon he returned home to his own_____ in the city of Zarahemla to rest himself from the labors which he had performed.",
    "answer": "House",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3180",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:3",
    "question": "Alma2 began to teach the people in the land of Melek which was on the west of the river_____ and on the west by the borders of the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Sidon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3181",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:6",
    "question": "After Alma2 finished his work at the land of Melek, he departed, and traveled for_____ days and came upon the city which was called Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "Three",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3182",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:7",
    "question": "It was the custom of the_____ to call their lands, and their cities, and their villages after the name of him who first possessed them; and so it was with the land of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3183",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:9",
    "question": "Because_____ had gotten a great hold upon the hearts of the people of the city of Ammonihah they would not hearken unto the words of Alma.",
    "answer": ["Devil", "Satan", "Adversary"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3184",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:10",
    "question": "Alma2 labored much in the spirit,_____ with God in mighty prayer; that he would pour out his Spirit upon the people who were in the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "Wrestling",
    "options": ["Tangling", "Fighting", "Wrestling"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3185",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:11",
    "question": "The people in the city of Ammonihah recognized Alma and knew that he was a high priest over the church.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3186",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:11",
    "question": "Because the people recognized Alma2 they would not believe in what they thought were foolish traditions in the church.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3187",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:12.",
    "question": "The people of Ammonihah knew that Alma had delivered his judgment-seat over to_____; therefore they said that he had no power over them.",
    "answer": "Nephihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3188",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:13",
    "question": "The people of the city of Ammonihah withstood all of Alma2’s words and reviled him, and spit on him, and caused that he should be_____ out from their city.",
    "answer": "Cast",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3189",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:14",
    "question": "Alma2 was being weighed down with sorrow, wading through much tribulation and anguish of the soul, because of the wickedness of the people who were in the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3190",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:14",
    "question": "While Alma2 was journeying toward the city of Aaron an_____ of the Lord appeared unto him and commanded that he return to the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["Messenger", "Follower", "Angel"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3191",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:16",
    "question": "Alma2 was told by the angel of the Lord to preach to the people of Ammonihah that if they did not repent, he would destroy them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3192",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:17",
    "question": "The Lord said that the people of Ammonihah were studying at this time that they may destroy the_____ of the people.",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["Liberty", "Welfare", "Laws"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3193",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:17",
    "question": "The people of Ammonihah were destroying the laws which were contrary to the statues, and judgments, and commandments which he had given unto his people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3194",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:18",
    "question": "When Alma2 went unto the city of Ammonihah for the second time, he entered the same way he did the first time.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3195",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:19",
    "question": "When Alma2 entered Ammonihah the second time he was hungry and asked a man:  Will you give a humble_____ of God something to eat?",
    "answer": "Servant",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3196",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:20",
    "question": "The man that fed Alma2 was a_____ and knew that Alma2 was a holy prophet of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Nephite",
    "options": ["Lamanite", "Zoramite", "Nephite"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3197",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:20",
    "question": "The man that fed Alma2 knew who he was because an angel of the Lord had told him in a_____; and he knew that Alma would be a blessing unto him and his household.",
    "answer": "Vision",
    "options": ["Text Message", "Vision", "Hallucination"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3198",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:21, 22",
    "question": "What was the name of the man that fed Alma2 bread and meat, and he was filled?",
    "answer": "Amulek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3199",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:24",
    "question": "Alma2 told Amulek that he was the high priest over the church and that he was called to preach the word of God to the people of Ammonihah, but they would not receive him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3200",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ that he was blessed for taken him in and feeding him because he was hungry and had fasted for many days.",
    "answer": "Amulek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3201",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:27",
    "question": "Alma2 only tarried with Amulek for one day before he began to preach the people of the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3202",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Ammonihah did wax more gross in their iniquities.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3203",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma8:30",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek went forth among the people of Ammonihah to declare the words of God unto them; and they were filled with the Holy_____.",
    "answer": "Ghost",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3204",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma8:31",
    "question": "The Lord gave Alma2 and Amulek much power that they could not be conf1ned in_____; neither was it possible that any man could slay them.",
    "answer": "Dungeons",
    "options": ["Dungeons", "Cages", "Jails"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3205",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma8:31",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek did not exercise their power until they were bound in bands and cast into prison so that the Lord might show forth his power in them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3207",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:3",
    "question": "Alma2 taught the people of_____ that the earth should pass away; and they did not believe his words and did not understand what he meant.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3208",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:4",
    "question": "Alma2 prophesied to the people in the city of Ammonihah that the city would be destroyed in one day and they did not believe him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3209",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:5",
    "question": "The people of Ammonihah did not know_____ and that he could do such marvelous works because they were a hard-hearted and stiffnecked people.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3210",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:7",
    "question": "The people of the city of Ammonihah tried to lay their hands on Alma but could not.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3211",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of Ammonihah that they were a wicked and perverse generation and how quickly had they forgotten the traditions of their_____ and the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "Fathers",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3212",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people in the city of Ammonihah that if it wasn’t for the Lord’s_____ power, and his mercy and long-suffering towards them, they would have been cut off from the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "Matchless",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3213",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the Lord had commanded them to repent or they could nowise inherit the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3214",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma9:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that if they did not repent he would visit them in his anger, and in his fierce_____ he will not turn away.",
    "answer": "Anger",
    "options": ["Temper", "Anger", "Moment"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3215",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the words of the Lord were verified when he said that Lamanites had been cut off from the presence of the Lord when they started with their transgressions.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3216",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma9:16",
    "question": "Because the Lord has made many promises to the_____ he will be merciful unto them and prolong their existence in the land.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Ismaelites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3217",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:17",
    "question": "Alma2 said that at some period of time the Lamanites will be brought to believe in the word of the Lord, and he will be merciful unto all who call in his name.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3218",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:19",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the Lord would not suffer that they should live in their iniquities to destroy his_____.",
    "answer": "People",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3219",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:20",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the people of_____ were highly favored of the Lord and were favored above every other nation, kindred, tongue, or people.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3220",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Nephites had not been visited by the Spirit of God; having conversed with angels, and have been spoken unto by the voice of the Lord.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3221",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma9:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if the Nephites should transgress contrary to the light and knowledge which they do have, it would be far more tolerable for the_____ than for them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Ismaelites", "Lamanites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3222",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:24",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people of the city of Ammonihah that the promises of the Lord were extended to the Lamanites, but they were not unto them if they transgressed.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3223",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the Son of God would come in not so distant days in all his glory; and his glory would be full of grace, equity, truth, and full of patience.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3224",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma9:30,31",
    "question": "Because Alma2 told the people in the city of Ammonihah that they were in a fallen state and a hard-hearted and stiffnecked people, they were angry with him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3225",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma9:34",
    "question": "Amulek also began to preach to the people who were in the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3226",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10-2",
    "question": "Amulek was the son of_____, who was the son of Ishmael, who was a descendent of Aminadi.",
    "answer": "Giddonah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3227",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:2",
    "question": "Amulek was a descendent of Aminadi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3228",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:2",
    "question": "What is the name of the prophet who interpreted the writing which was upon the wall of the temple, which was written by the finger of God?",
    "answer": "Aminadi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3229",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:3",
    "question": "Aminadi was a descendent of Nephi, who was the son of Lehi, who came out of the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3230",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:3",
    "question": "Lehi was a descendent of Manasseh, who was the son of_____ who was sold into Egypt by the hands of his brethren.",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3231",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10-4",
    "question": "Amulek told the people that he was a man of no small reputation among those that knew him; and had many relatives and friends, and had acquired many riches by his industry.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3232",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:5",
    "question": "Amulek said that he had known and seen the mysteries and marvelous power of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3233",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma10:6",
    "question": "Amulek told the people of Ammonihah that he was called many times but did not hear because he had hardened his_____.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Soul", "Heart", "Spirit"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3234",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:7",
    "question": "As Amulek was traveling to see a beloved relative of his, an_____ of the Lord told him to return to his own house; because he would feed a prophet of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3235",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:8",
    "question": "Amulek did not obey the angel of the Lord when he was told to return to his house and feed a prophet of the Lord.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3237",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:10,11",
    "question": "Amulek told the people that the Lord had blessed him and his family and his kinsfolk while Alma2 had dwelled in his house.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3238",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:13",
    "question": "Some of the people of Ammonihah tried to question Alma2 and Amulek to try to catch them in their words; that they might witness against them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3239",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:13",
    "question": "The people of_____ wanted to question Alma2 and Amulek to try to catch them lying so that they could be slain or cast them into prison.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah-",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3240",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:14",
    "question": "What was the profession of the men that tried to destroy and catch Alma2 and Amulek in their words?",
    "answer": "Lawyers",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3241",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma10:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the lawyers began to question Amulek that thereby they might make him_____ his words, or contradict the words which he spoke.",
    "answer": "Cross",
    "options": ["Eat", "Stumble", "Cross"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3242",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:17",
    "question": "The lawyers of the city in Ammonihah did not know that_____ knew of their designs and could also read their thoughts.",
    "answer": "Amulek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3243",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:17",
    "question": "Amulek did not call the lawyers of the city of Ammonihah hypocrites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3244",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:17",
    "question": "Amulek said that the lawyers of Ammonihah were laying the foundation of the_____; because they were laying traps and snares to catch the holy ones of God.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3245",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:19",
    "question": "Amulek made a reference to King_____ when he told the people that he had said if the time should come that the people chose iniquity, they would be ripe for destruction.",
    "answer": "Mosiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3246",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma10:22",
    "question": "Amulek told the people that if it was not for the_____ of the righteous, who were in the land; the Lord would have visited them with utter destruction.",
    "answer": "Prayers",
    "options": ["Fastings", "Gifts", "Prayers"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3247",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:23",
    "question": "Amulek told the people of Ammonihah that if they did not repent the Lord would visit them in his anger and be smitten by fam1ne, pestilence, and by the_____.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3248",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Ammonihah were angrier with Amulek because of the words that he had told them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3249",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:24",
    "question": "The people of Ammonihah said that Amulek had reviled against their laws which were just, and also to their wise lawyers who they had selected.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3250",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:25",
    "question": "Amulek told the people why they had let_____ get such a hold upon their hearts and yielded themselves to him that he may have power over them.",
    "answer": "Satan",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3251",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma10:31",
    "question": "What was the name of the lawyer who had accused Amulek and Alma2 the most of breaking their laws?",
    "answer": "Zeezrom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3252",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma10:32",
    "question": "The lawyers’ objective was to get gain; and they got gain according to their employment.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3253",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:1",
    "question": "It was the law of King Mosiah that every man who was a judge of the law, or those who were appointed to be judges should receive wages according to their labors.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3254",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:2",
    "question": "If a man owed another man and he would not pay that which he owed, it was his right to complain to the judge of the land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3255",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma11:2",
    "question": "If a man did not pay his debts he would be stripped, or be cast out from the land among the people as a thief and a_____.",
    "answer": "Robber",
    "options": ["Bad Guy", "Robber", "Scoundrel"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3256",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:3",
    "question": "According to the Nephite way of coins and measures; a sen1ne of gold for a day is equal to a senum of silver for a day.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3257",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:4",
    "question": "The_____ did not value their coins after the manner of the Jews who were at Jerusalem; neither did they measure after the manner of the Jews.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3258",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:20",
    "question": "The lawyers of Ammonihah would stir the people to riotings, and all manner of wickedness, that they might be employed by the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3259",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:20",
    "question": "There were no such things as law suits among the Nephites during the time of Amulek and Alma2.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3260",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:21",
    "question": "Zeezrom was an expert in the devices of the_____; that he might destroy the things which were good.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3261",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:22",
    "question": "_____ began to question Amulek; and Amulek told him that he would not say anything that was contrary to the Spirit of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3262",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:22",
    "question": "Zeezrom tried to bribe_____ with six onties of silver to deny the existence of a Supreme Being.",
    "answer": "Amulek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3263",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:24",
    "question": "Zeezrom did not know that God existed.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3264",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:26,28",
    "question": "Zeezrom asked Amulek if there was a true and living_____; and if only one existed.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3265",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:31",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that he believed there was a God because and an_____ of the Lord had told him.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3266",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:34",
    "question": "Zeezrom asked Amulek if God would save his people in their sins.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3267",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:34",
    "question": "Amulek told_____ that God could not save his people in their sins because he would be denying his word.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3268",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:35",
    "question": "Zeezrom accused Amulek of having the authority to command God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3269",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:39",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that the Son of God was the very Eternal_____ of heaven and of earth, and of all things that exist.",
    "answer": "Father",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3270",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:39",
    "question": "Amulek also told Zeezrom that the Eternal Father was the beginning and the end, the first and the_____.",
    "answer": "Last",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3271",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:40",
    "question": "Amulek said that those who believe in the Son of God are they that shall have eternal life and salvation comes to no one else.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3272",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:41",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that those that are wicked remain as though there had been no redemption made.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3273",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:41",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that the day will come when the wicked shall rise from the dead and stand before God, and be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3274",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:42",
    "question": "Amulek said that the death of our bodies is called_____ death; and the death of Christ shall loose the bands of this temporal death and all shall be raised from this temporal death.",
    "answer": "Temporal",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3275",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:43",
    "question": "Amulek told Zeezrom that the_____ and the body shall be reunited again in its perfect form; both limb and joint shall be restored to its proper frame.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3276",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:43",
    "question": "Amulek tells us that we shall be brought to stand before God, knowing all the things we each know, and have a recollection of all our guilt.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3277",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:44",
    "question": "Amulek said that the restoration shall come to all, both young and old, both male and female, both the wicked and the righteous, and both_____ and free.",
    "answer": "Bond",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3278",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:44",
    "question": "Amulek said that not every single person will be brought before the bar of Christ the Son, and God the Father, and the Holy Spirit, which is one Eternal God to be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3279",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:45",
    "question": "Amulek spoke to Zeezrom concerning the death of the mortal body, and also concerning the resurrection.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3280",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma11:46",
    "question": "When Amulek finished with his words the people began to be astonished, and also_____ began to tremble.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3281",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma11:46",
    "question": "Once Amulek finished answering the questions that Zeezrom had put before him and also finished speaking to him, Alma2 chose not to write anymore of his words.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3282",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:1",
    "question": "When Alma2 saw that the words of_____ had silenced Zeezrom, he began to speak unto him and testified of his words.",
    "answer": "Amulek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3283",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:5.6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Zeezrom that the Adversary and exercised his power in him and had laid a snare to catch the people; and subject them to his will.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3284",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:6",
    "question": "The adversary wanted to encircle_____ and the people with his chains, that he might chain them down to everlasting destruction, according to the power of his captivity.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3285",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:7",
    "question": "When Alma2 had spoken his words to Zeezrom, he began to tremble more exceedingly because he had become more convinced of the power of_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3286",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:7",
    "question": "Zeezrom had become convinced that Alma2 and Amulek knew the thoughts and intents of his heart; because the Lord had given power unto them that they might know these things according to the spirit of prophecy.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3287",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Zeezrom began to inquire of_____ and Amulek diligently, that he might know more concerning the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3288",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Zeezrom that it is given unto many to know of the_____ of God, but they are laid under a strict command.",
    "answer": "Mysteries",
    "options": ["Mysteries", "Thoughts", "Ideas"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3289",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:9",
    "question": "The mysteries of God are imparted only according to the portion of his word which he grants to the children of men, according to the heed and_____ which they give unto him.",
    "answer": "Diligence",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3290",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:10",
    "question": "The more we harden are hearts; the less portion of the mysteries of God we will receive.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3291",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:10",
    "question": "Those that do not harden their hearts; to him is given a greater_____ of the word, until it is given unto him to know all the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": "Portion",
    "options": ["Helping", "Portion", "Abundance"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3292",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:11",
    "question": "According to Alma2, the chains of hell mean:  To those that is given the lesser portion of the word until they know nothing concerning his mysteries; and then they are taken captive by the devil, and led by his will down to destruction.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3293",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Zeezrom that our words will condemn us, all our works will condemn us; and our_____, and we shall not be found spotless.",
    "answer": "Thoughts",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3294",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that because of all the things that will condemn us; we will be happy and glad if we could command the rocks and the_____ to fall upon us to hide us from his presence.",
    "answer": "Mountains",
    "options": ["Hills", "Volcanoes", "Mountains"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3295",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that we cannot hide from the Lord but must come forth and stand before him in his glory, power, might, majesty, and dominion and acknowledge that his judgments are just.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3296",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that we must also acknowledge that God is just in all his works.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3297",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God is merciful unto the children of men, and that he has all the power to save every man that believes in his name and brings repentance unto him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3298",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said the second death is spiritual death, then is the time that whosoever died in his sins, as to temporal death, shall also die a spiritual death; and shall die as to things pertaining unto_____.",
    "answer": "Righteousness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3299",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:17",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the lake of fire and brimstone ascends up forever and ever; and then is the time comes that they shall be cha1ned down to an everlasting destruction, according to the power and captivity of_____.",
    "answer": "Satan",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3300",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:19",
    "question": "When Alma2 had finished and made an end to his speaking the people began to be more astonished.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3301",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:20",
    "question": "What was the name of the man who was a chief ruler over the people in the city of Ammonihah who began to question Alma2?",
    "answer": "Antionah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3302",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:20",
    "question": "Antionah asked Alma2 what he meant when he said that man should rise from the dead and be changed from his mortal to an immortal state that the soul can never die.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3303",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:21",
    "question": "At what direction in the Garden of Eden did God place cherubim and a flaming sword that so that Adam and Eve would not enter and partake of the tree of life, and live forever.",
    "answer": "East",
    "options": ["West", "East", "South"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3304",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told Antionah that_____ did fall by the partaking of the forbidden fruit, according to the word of God; and by his fall, all mankind became a lost and fallen people.",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3305",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if Adam had partaken of the fruit of the_____ of life at that time, there would have been no death to man and the Lord’s word would have been void.",
    "answer": "Tree",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3306",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:24",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the time that is granted unto man to prepare to meet God is called a_____ state.",
    "answer": "Probationary",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3307",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma-12:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if our first parents could have gone forth and partaken of the tree of life they would have been miserable forever, having no preparatory state.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3308",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:27",
    "question": "Alma2 said that it was appointed unto men that they must die; and after death, they must come to be_____.",
    "answer": "Judged",
    "options": ["Knighted", "Crowned", "Judged"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3309",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:28",
    "question": "After God appointed that these things should come unto men, he saw that it was expedient that man should know concerning the things which he had appointed unto them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3310",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:29",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God sent_____ to converse with men, who cause men to behold his glory.",
    "answer": "Angels",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3311",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:30",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God conversed with men, and made it know unto them the plan of_____, which had been prepared from the foundation of the world.",
    "answer": "Redemption",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3312",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:31",
    "question": "Men first transgressed the first commandments as to things which were temporal, and becoming as Gods, knowing good from_____.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3313",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:31",
    "question": "By becoming like Gods, men placed themselves in a state to act, or be placed in a state to act according to their wills and pleasures, whether to do evil or to do_____.",
    "answer": "Good",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3314",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma12:33",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God did call all men, in the name of his Son saying:  If you will repent, and harden not your hearts, then will I have mercy upon you, through m1ne Only Begotten_____.",
    "answer": "Son",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3315",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma12:34",
    "question": "Alma2 said that those who repent and harden not their hearts shall have the claim to mercy though the Only Begotten Son, unto a remission of his_____; and these shall enter into the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["Deeds", "Bad Deeds", "Sins"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3316",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:36",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Nephites if they hardened their hearts; their iniquity would provoke the Lord to send his wrath upon them in the first provocation.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3317",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:36",
    "question": "The first provocation can also mean to describe things that are temporal.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3318",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma12:37",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Nephites to also remember the Lord’s second commandments which he had given them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3319",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma13:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told his brethren to remember that the Lord God orda1ned_____, after his holy order, which was after the order of his Son, to teach them unto the people.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Priests", "Lawyers", "Judges"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3320",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said that that the priests of the Lord were called and prepared from the_____ of the world according to the foreknowledge of God.",
    "answer": "Foundation",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3321",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma13:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord’s priests were called to this holy calling on account of their_____, while others would reject the Spirit of God on account of the hardness of their hearts and blindness of their minds.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Riches", "Intelligence", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3322",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the high priesthood was not a holy calling but more of a calling of a status symbol.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3323",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that the high priesthood was called after the order of his Son, which order was from the foundation of the world; or in other words, being without beginning of days or end of years.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3324",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:7",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the high priesthood was prepared from eternity to all_____, according to God’s foreknowledge of all things.",
    "answer": "Eternity",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3325",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the priests were orda1ned after this manner:  Being called with a holy calling, and orda1ned with a holy ordinance, and taking upon them the high priesthood of the holy order, which has no beginning or end.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3326",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that brethren that are called become high priest forever, after the order of the_____, the Only Begotten of the Father, who is without beginning of days or ends of years.",
    "answer": "Son",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3327",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said that those that were orda1ned became high priest of God; and it was on account of their faith and repentance, and their righteousness before God, choosing to repent and work righteousness rather than to_____.",
    "answer": "Perish",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3328",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the high priesthood was called after this holy order, and were sanctified, and their garments were washed white through the_____ of the Lamb of God.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3329",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:12",
    "question": "Alma 2said that those whose garments were made white became pure and spotless before God, and could not look upon sin except it was with abhorrence.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3330",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said there were many, an exceedingly great many who were made pure and entered into the rest of the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3331",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Melchizedek the high priest was special and that he was a high priest after another holy order.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3332",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that their father Abraham paid one-tenth part of all that he possessed to what high priest?",
    "answer": "Melchizedek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3333",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma13:17",
    "question": "What was the land called that Melchizedek was a king over?",
    "answer": "Salem",
    "options": ["Waters Of Mormon", "Salem", "Ammonihah"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3334",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:17",
    "question": "The people in the land of Salem had waxed strong in iniquity and abominations and had all gone astray; they were full of all manner of wickedness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3335",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:18",
    "question": "Because_____ had exercised mighty faith and preached to the people about repentance, they did repent; and he did establish peace in the land in all his days.",
    "answer": "Melchidezek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3336",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:18",
    "question": "Another name for Melchizedek was the prince of peace, because he had established peace once again in the land of Salem; and he did reign under his father",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3337",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:18",
    "question": "In the Book of Mormon and in the Book of Alma, it is written by Mormon the name of the father of Melchizedek.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3338",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:19",
    "question": "There were many before_____, and also there were many afterwards, but none were greater; therefore, of him they have more particularly made mention.",
    "answer": "Melchizedek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3339",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:21",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Alma2 had said these words unto them, he stretched forth his hand unto them and cried with a mighty voice, saying:  Now is the time to repent for the day of salvation draws near.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3340",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:22",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the voice of the Lord, by the mouth of his angels, declare unto all nations that they may have glad tidings of great joy.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3341",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:22",
    "question": "Alma2 said the voice of the Lord, by the mouth of his angels, declare and sound these glad tidings among all his people, even to them that are scattered abroad upon the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3342",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the angels declare glad tidings of great joy and that they are made known unto us in plain terms; that we may understand, that we cannot err.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3343",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:24",
    "question": "Alma2 said that angels are declaring things for the purpose of preparing the hearts of the_____ of men to receive the word of the Lord at the time of his coming.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3344",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:25",
    "question": "Alma2 wished that the only Begotten Son of God would come in his day; nevertheless, he said that he would rejoice sooner or later.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3345",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:25",
    "question": "Alma2 said he knew when the only Begotten Son of God would come unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3346",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the coming of the Lord would be made known unto just and_____ men, by the mouth of angels, at the time of his coming.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3347",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the just and holy men would let the people know of the coming of the Lord so that the words of their fathers would be fulfilled, according to that which they have spoken concerning him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3348",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told his brethren that he wished from the inner most part of his heart and with great anxiety even unto pain; that they would hearken to his words, and cast off their sins, and not_____ the day of their repentance.",
    "answer": "Procrastinate",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3349",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma13:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to humble themselves before the Lord, and call on his holy name, and watch and_____ continually, that they may not be tempted above that which they could bear.",
    "answer": "Pray",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3350",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma13:29",
    "question": "Alma2 also told his brethren to have faith in the Lord; having a hope that they would receive_____ life; having the love of God always in their hearts, that they may be lifted up at the last day and enter into his rest.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["Gifts", "Long", "Eternal"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3351",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma13:31",
    "question": "All the words that Alma2 spoke to the people are written in the Book of Alma.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3352",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:1,2",
    "question": "After Alma2 had finished speaking to the people; many of them believed in his words and repented; but the most part of them desired to destroy Alma and Amulek.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3353",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:3",
    "question": "The people were angry with Alma2 and Amulek because they had testified so plainly against their_____, and they sought to put them away privily.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["Lustfulness", "Ignorance", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3354",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people took Alma2 and Amulek and bound them with strong_____, and took them before the chief judge of the land.",
    "answer": "Cords",
    "options": ["Wires", "Cords", "Duct Tape"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3355",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:5",
    "question": "The people went forth and witnessed against Alma2 and_____; testifying that they had reviled against the law, and their lawyers and judges of the land.",
    "answer": "Amulek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3356",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Zeezrom was not astonished by the words that had been spoken by the people.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3357",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:6",
    "question": "Zeezrom knew concerning the blindness of the minds of the people which he had caused by his lying words; and his soul began to be harrowed up under a consciousness of his own guilt.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3358",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____ began to cry unto the people, saying:  Behold, I am guilty, and Alma2 and Amulek are spotless before God.",
    "answer": "Zeezrom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3359",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:7",
    "question": "The people cast Zeezrom out from among them and spit on him; and sent men to cast_____ unto all those that believed in his words and also the words of Alma2 and Amulek.",
    "answer": "Stones",
    "options": ["Arrows", "Rocks", "Stones"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3360",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:8",
    "question": "The people that believe in the words of Alma2 and Amulek were cast into the fire, and also brought forth their records which conta1ned the Holy Scriptures, that they might also be burned and destroyed by fire.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3361",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:10",
    "question": "Amulek wanted to stretch forth his hands and exercise the power of_____ which was in him and Alma2 and save the people from the flames.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3362",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Amulek that the Spirit constra1ned him not to save the people because the Lord received them unto himself and that the blood of the innocent would stand as a witness against them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3363",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the chief judge of the land came and stood before Alma2 and Amulek as they were bound and smote them with his_____ upon their cheeks.",
    "answer": "Hand",
    "options": ["Whip", "Hand", "Cane"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3365",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:16",
    "question": "The chief judge of the land that hit Alma2 and Amulek on the cheek was of the order and faith of_____ who slew Gideon.",
    "answer": "Nehor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3366",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:18",
    "question": "Many judges and lawyers and priest came to question Alma2 and Amulek when then were cast into prison for_____ days.",
    "answer": "Three",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3367",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:18-20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 and Amulek answered all the questions that were put before them by the judges, lawyers, and priests.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3368",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:21",
    "question": "Many people did come gnashing their teeth and_____ on Alma and Amulek.",
    "answer": "Spitting",
    "options": ["Swearing", "Spitting", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3369",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:22",
    "question": "The people withheld food and water and took Alma2’s and Amulek’s clothes; and they were also bound with strong cords and conf1ned in prison.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3370",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:25",
    "question": "The chief judge and all the judges, lawyers, priests, and teachers that had questioned Alma2 and Amulek before came forth and asked them to deliver themselves if they had the power of_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3371",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:26",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek rose and stood upon their feet and asked the Lord to give them strength according to the faith which is in Christ for deliverance.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3372",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma14:26",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek broke the cords with which they were bound; and when the people saw this, they began to flee, for the fear of_____ had come upon them.",
    "answer": "Destruction",
    "options": ["Destruction", "Death", "Stupidity"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3373",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that so great was their fear that the people fell first to the earth then stood up and ran out of the prison.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3374",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:27",
    "question": "The earth shook mightily, and the walls of the prison fell on the people and they were slain by the fall thereof.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3375",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma14:28",
    "question": "Alma2 and_____ came forth out of the prison and were not hurt because the Lord had granted unto them power, according to their faith which was in Christ.",
    "answer": "Amulek",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3376",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma14:29",
    "question": "Many multitudes of people came to see what had happened because of the great noise the walls of the prison had made; and when they saw Alma2 and Amulek come out of prison unharmed, they fled.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3377",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 and Amulek were not commanded to leave the city of Ammonihah.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3378",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma15:1",
    "question": "When Alma2 and Amulek departed the city of Ammonihah they went to the land of Sidom and found all the people that had been cast out and stoned, because they believed in the words of_____.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3379",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma15:3",
    "question": "Who lay sick in the land of Sidom with a burning fever, which was caused by the great tribulations of his mind on account of his wickedness?",
    "answer": "Zeezrom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3380",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:3",
    "question": "Zeezrom supposed that Alma2 and Amulek were dead because of his iniquity.  And because this great sin and his other sins, did harrow up his mind until it became exceedingly sore.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3381",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:3",
    "question": "Zeezrom’s mind did not to began to be scorched with a burning heat because of the sins he had committed.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3382",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:9-10",
    "question": "Alma2 healed Zeezrom because he believed in all his words and had faith which was in Christ.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3383",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:11",
    "question": "When Alma2 healed Zeezrom he leaped upon his feet and began to walk; and this was done to the great astonishment of all the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3385",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:13",
    "question": "Alma2 did not establish a church in the land of Sidom.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3386",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma15:15",
    "question": "The people that were in the land of Ammonihah rema1ned a stiffnecked people and did not repent of their_____.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["Sins", "Wrong Doings", "Bad Mouthing"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3387",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma15:15",
    "question": "The people that were in Ammonihah credited the power of Alma2 and Amulek to the_____; for they were of the profession of Nehor, and did not believe in the repentance of their sins.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3389",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma15:16",
    "question": "Amulek was rejected by his own_____ and his relatives and also those that were once his friends; for believing in the word of God.",
    "answer": "Father",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3390",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma15:18",
    "question": "Alma2 took Amulek to his own house and administered unto him in his tribulations, and strengthened him in the Lord.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3391",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:2",
    "question": "The_____ came upon the borders of Zarahemla and the city of Ammonihah and began to slay the people and destroy the city.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Ishmaelites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3392",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that before the_____ could raise a sufficient army the Lamanites destroyed the people of the city of Ammonihah and also took some people captive into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3393",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:5",
    "question": "Who was the chief captain of the Nephite army during the time that Alma2 and Amulek were among the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Zoram",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3394",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:5",
    "question": "Zoram had two sons and their names were Lehi and Aha.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3395",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:5",
    "question": "Zoram knew that_____ had the spirit of",
    "answer": "prophecy. ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3396",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:5",
    "question": "Zoram went unto Alma and desired of him to tell them where they should go in the wilderness to search for the Nephites that had been taken captive by the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3397",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:6",
    "question": "Alma did not inquire of the Lord to let him know where the Lamanites had taken their brethren captive.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3398",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites and Zoram and his sons were able to free their brethren from the Lamanites; and not a soul was lost and they returned to posses their own land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3399",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma16:9",
    "question": "The people of the city of Ammonihah said that God could not destroy their city because of its_____.",
    "answer": "Greatness",
    "options": ["Majesty", "Size", "Greatness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3400",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma16:10",
    "question": "The city of Ammonihah was left desolate in one day; and the carcasses of the dead were mangled by_____ and wild beasts of the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Dogs",
    "options": ["Dogs", "Coyotes", "Lions"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3401",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:11",
    "question": "Because of the scent of the dead bodies that were in the city of_____; the people did not go in the land of Ammonihah for many years.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3402",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:11",
    "question": "Another name for the land of Ammonihah is the Desolation of Nehors.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3403",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:11",
    "question": "The land of Ammonihah was called the Desolation of Nehors because the people were of the profession of_____.",
    "answer": "Nehor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3404",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma16:12",
    "question": "After destruction of Ammonihah there was peace was again among the Nephites and Lamanites for the space of_____ years.",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3405",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:13",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek went forth preaching repentance to the people in their temples, and their sanctuaries, and in their_____.",
    "answer": "Synagogues",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3406",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:13",
    "question": "The Nephites worshipped the Lord in all their places that were built after the manner of what tribe of people?",
    "answer": "Jews",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3407",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:14",
    "question": "Alma2 and Amulek preached the word of God without any respect of persons continually.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3408",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:16",
    "question": "There was no inequality among the people; the Lord did pour out his_____ on all the face of the land to prepare the minds of the children of men.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3409",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma16:19",
    "question": "The priests taught the coming about the coming of Son of God, his sufferings and death, and also the_____ of the dead.",
    "answer": "Resurrection",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3410",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:20",
    "question": "Many people inquired concerning the place where the Son of God should come; and they were taught that he would appear unto them after his resurrection.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3411",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma16:21",
    "question": "Because the people were taught that the Son of God would visit them after his resurrection they did not receive the teachings with joy and gladness",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3413",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:1",
    "question": "When Alma2 was journeying from the land of Gideon towards the land of Manti he met the sons’ of_____ journeying towards the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Mosiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3414",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:2",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah were with Alma2 at the time the_____ first appeared unto him.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3415",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:2",
    "question": "Alma2 did rejoice exceedingly when he saw his brethren and was even more joyous when he learned that they were still his brethren in the Lord; and had waxed strong in the knowledge of the truth.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3416",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:2",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah were men of sound_____ and they had searched the scriptures diligently, that they might know the word of God.",
    "answer": "Understanding",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3417",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:3",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah had given themselves to much prayer, and fasting; therefore they had the spirit of prophecy and the spirit of_____.",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3418",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:3",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah taught with great power and_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Authority",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3419",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:4",
    "question": "For how many years had the sons of Mosiah been teaching the Lamanites the word of God?",
    "answer": "14",
    "options": ["14", "15", "16"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3420",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:5",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah had many afflictions and suffered much, both in body and in mind, such as_____, thirst and fatigue, and also much labor in the spirit.",
    "answer": "Hungar",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3421",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:6",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah had refused the kingdom of their father called King_____, in the first year of the reign of judges.",
    "answer": "Mosiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3422",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:7",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah departed out of the land of Zarahemla, and took their_____., spears, bows, arrows, and slings for the purpose of providing food for themselves in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Swords",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3423",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:8",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah did not take anyone else but themselves to preach to word of God unto the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3424",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:9",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah fasted and prayed much that the Lord would grant unto them a_____ of his Spirit.",
    "answer": "Portion",
    "options": ["Large Amount", "Small Amount", "Portion"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3425",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:9",
    "question": "The sons of Mosiah were desirous to be_____ in the hands of God in bringing the Lamanites to the knowledge of the truth and baseness of the traditions of their fathers which was not correct.",
    "answer": "Instuments",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3426",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:11",
    "question": "The Lord said unto the sons of Mosiah to establish his word and be patient in long-suffering and afflictions.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3427",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:11",
    "question": "The reason the Lord wanted the sons of Mosiah to be patient and long-suffering was so they could be_____ examples unto him and be an instrument in his hands in bringing many souls unto the salvation.",
    "answer": "Good",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3428",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____ of the sons of Mosiah, and also those that were with them received courage to go forth unto the Lamanites to declare the word of God.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Hearts", "Bodies", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3429",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:13",
    "question": "When the sons of Mosiah arrived at the borders of the land of the Lamanites they separated themselves from one another.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3430",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:14",
    "question": "The hearts of the Lamanites were set upon riches, or upon gold and silver, and precious stones; but they did not want to labor for these things with their own_____.",
    "answer": "Hands",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3431",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:15",
    "question": "The Lamanites were a very indolent people, and many of them worshipped_____, however the promises of the Lord were extended unto them on the condition of repentance.",
    "answer": "Idols",
    "options": ["Statues", "Idols", "Horses"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3432",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:18",
    "question": "Which of the sons of Mosiah was the chief among them? Administering unto them and departed from them to teach the Lamanites on his own.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3433",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:19",
    "question": "Ammon went to the land of Ishmael, which was called after the sons’ of_____; who also became Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Ishmael",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3434",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:20",
    "question": "When Ammon entered the land of Ishmael, the Lamanites took him and bound him which was their custom to bind all Nephites that fell into their hands.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3435",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:21",
    "question": "The Lamanites took Ammon and carried him before the king who was over the land of Ismael; and his name was_____; and he was a descendant of Ishmael.",
    "answer": "Lamoni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3436",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:22-23",
    "question": "King Lamoni asked Ammon if he desired to live in the land among the Lamanites and Ammon said no.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3437",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:24",
    "question": "King Lamoni caused that the bands on Ammon to be loosed wanted Ammon to marry one of his_____.",
    "answer": "Daughters",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3438",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:25",
    "question": "Ammon became a_____ to King Lamoni and was sent to watch over his flocks.",
    "answer": "Servant",
    "options": ["Servant", "Shepherd", "Slave"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3440",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:26",
    "question": "What was the name of the place of water where all the Lamanites took their flocks for water?",
    "answer": "Sebus",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3441",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:28-29",
    "question": "The servants of King Lamoni began to murmur and cry because they said that he would kill them for allowing other Lamanites to scatter his flock.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3442",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:29",
    "question": "Ammon wanted to show forth his power to his fellow servants in restoring the king’s flock so that he might lead them to believe in his_____.",
    "answer": "Words",
    "options": ["Babblings", "Speeches", "Words"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3443",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon led the search with the servants to find the flocks of King Lamoni and did gather them together again to the place of Sebus for water.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3444",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:34",
    "question": "The same men that had scattered the_____ of King Lamoni came a second time to scatter them again, and Ammon went to contend with them.",
    "answer": "Flocks",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3445",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:35",
    "question": "The men did not fear Ammon because they thought that one of them could slay him according to their pleasure.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3446",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:35",
    "question": "The men that had scattered King Lamoni’s flock did not know that the Lord had promised King_____ that he would deliver his sons out of their hands.",
    "answer": "Mosiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3447",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:35",
    "question": "The men that contended with Ammon did not know anything concerning the Lord.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3448",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:35",
    "question": "The men that contended with Ammon delighted in the destruction of their brethren; and this was the cause or purpose for scattering the flocks of King Lamoni.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3449",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma17:36",
    "question": "What was the choice of weapon that Ammon used the first time to slay the men who had scattered the kings’ flocks?",
    "answer": "stones",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3450",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:36",
    "question": "The men were angry with Ammon because he had slain their brethren so they came after him with their_____ to slay him because they could not hit him with their stones.",
    "answer": "Clubs",
    "options": ["Bats", "Clubs", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3451",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma17:37",
    "question": "Ammon did not cut the arms of every man that tried to kill him with the edge of his sword.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3452",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:38",
    "question": "How many men did Ammon kill with his sling and stones?",
    "answer": "6",
    "options": ["6", "7", "8"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3453",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma17:39",
    "question": "Ammon returned the flocks of Kings Lamoni to his pasture and then went unto the king carrying the_____ which he had smitten off by the sword as a testimony of the things which they had done.",
    "answer": "Arms",
    "options": ["Legs", "Heads", "Arms"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3454",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:1",
    "question": "King Lamoni caused that his servants should stand before him and to testify of the things which they had seen at the waters of Sebus.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3455",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:2",
    "question": "King Lamoni thought Ammon was the_____Spirit.",
    "answer": "Great",
    "options": ["Good", "Bad", "Great"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3456",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:3",
    "question": "The servants of King Lamoni did not know if Ammon was a man or the Great Spirit; but they did know that he could not be slain.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3457",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:4",
    "question": "Because of the things which he had done; King Lamoni thought the Ammon was the Great_____.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3458",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:4",
    "question": "King Lamoni thought that the Great Spirit had come down to spare the lives of his servants and it was the Great Spirit that had been spoken by their_____.",
    "answer": "Fathers",
    "options": ["Mothers", "Brothers", "Fathers"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3460",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:8",
    "question": "Ammon was preparing the king’s horse’s and_____ when King Lamoni asked his servants saying:  Where is this man that has such great power?",
    "answer": "Chariots",
    "options": ["Hair", "Supper", "Chariots"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3461",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:8",
    "question": "Ammon was preparing the king’s horses and chariots when King Lamoni asked his servants saying:  Where is this man that has such great power?",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3462",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:10",
    "question": "King Lamoni said that there had not been any servant among all his servants that has been so_____ as Ammon; because he remembered to execute all his commandments.",
    "answer": "Faithful",
    "options": ["Nice", "Faithful", "Honest"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3463",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Ammon had finished preparing the horse’s and_____ of King Lamoni; he returned to the king and saw that his countenance had change.",
    "answer": "Chariots",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3464",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:13",
    "question": "What was the other name that one of the servants of King Lamoni called Ammon by?",
    "answer": "Rabbanah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3465",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:13",
    "question": "The word Rabbanah interpreted means powerful or great king.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3466",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:13",
    "question": "The word Rabbanah only appears written in the Book of Alma.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3467",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:14",
    "question": "When Ammon turned himself to King Lamoni and asked what he desired of him and the king did not answer him for one hour.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3468",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:16",
    "question": "Because Ammon was filled with the Spirit of God; he could perceived the thoughts of King_____.",
    "answer": "Lamoni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3469",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:17",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that he was just a man and his servant; and told him that he would do anything which the king desired as long as it was right.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3470",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:18",
    "question": "King Lamoni marveled because_____ could discern his thoughts and asked:  Who art you? Are you the Great Spirit who knows all things?",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3471",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:19",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that he was the Great Spirit.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3472",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:20",
    "question": "King Lamoni told Ammon that he could speak boldly, and tell him by what power had he slew the_____of his brethren that had scattered his flocks.",
    "answer": "Arms",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3473",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:21",
    "question": "King Lamoni told Ammon if he told him concerning these things that he would give him anything which he desired and that he knew that he was more powerful than his_____.",
    "answer": "Armies",
    "options": ["Battalions", "Navy Seals", "Armies"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3474",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma18:22",
    "question": "Because Ammon was wise and_____, he asked King Lamoni if he would hearken unto his words and tell him by what power he had done the things that he did.",
    "answer": "Harmless",
    "options": ["Large", "Harmless", "Charismatic"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3475",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:23",
    "question": "King Lamoni told Ammon that he would not believe in his words.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3477",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:24-25",
    "question": "King Lamoni did not know what Ammon meant when he asked him if he believed that there was a God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3478",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:26-29",
    "question": "King Lamoni believed that Great Spirit or God had created all things which were in the_____; but did not know concerning the heavens.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3479",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:30",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that the heavens’ was the place where God dwelled with all his holy_____.",
    "answer": "Angels",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3480",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:31-32",
    "question": "King Lamoni asked Ammon if heaven was above the earth; and Ammon told him yes and that God looks down upon all the children of men.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3481",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:32",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that God knows all the thoughts and intents of the heart; because his_____ had created all the children of men from the beginning.",
    "answer": "Hand",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3482",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:33",
    "question": "King Lamoni asked Ammon if he was sent from God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3483",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:34",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that God was just a man; and he had created all men in his own_____.",
    "answer": "Image",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3484",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:34",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that he was called by the Lord’s Holy Spirit to teach God’s things unto his people, that they may be brought to the knowledge of that which is_____and true.",
    "answer": "Just",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3485",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:35",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamoni that a portion of the Spirit of God dwelled in him and give him knowledge, and also power according to his_____ and desires which are in God.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3486",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:36",
    "question": "After Ammon had finished with his words he began to tell King Lamoni of the creation of the world, and also the creation of father_____.",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3487",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:36",
    "question": "Ammon also told the king about the fall of man, and rehearsed and laid before him the records and the holy_____ of the people which had been spoken by the prophets.",
    "answer": "Scriptures",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3488",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:36",
    "question": "Ammon however, did not tell King Lamoni from the time that Lehi their father had left Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3489",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:37",
    "question": "Alma also rehearsed unto the king and his servants all the journeyings of their fathers in the wilderness, and all the suffering with hunger and thirst, and their travel, etc.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3490",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:38",
    "question": "Ammon also rehearsed unto the kings and his servants concerning the rebellions of_____ and Lemuel and the sons of Ishmael.",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3491",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:38",
    "question": "Ammon expounded to King Lamoni and his servants all the records and scriptures from the time Lehi left_____ down to the present time.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3492",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:39",
    "question": "Ammon also expounded unto them the plan of redemption, which was prepared from the foundation of the world; and also concerning the coming of _____, and all the works of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3493",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:40",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Ammon had finished with his words King Lamoni did not believe his words.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3494",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18:41",
    "question": "King Lamoni began to cry unto the Lord, to have mercy on him and his people liked he had upon the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3495",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:42",
    "question": "When King Lamoni had finished crying to the Lord for mercy he fell to the earth and if he were_____.",
    "answer": "Dead",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3496",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:43",
    "question": "And it came to pass that his servants carried King Lamoni unto his wife, and laid him upon a bed; and he laid there as if he were dead for the space of two days and two_____.",
    "answer": "Nights",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3497",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma18:43",
    "question": "King Lamoni’s wife and his sons, and his daughters mourned over him, after the manner of the_____, greatly lamenting his loss.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3498",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:2",
    "question": "King Lamoni’s wife heard of the fame of_____ and sent for him.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3499",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:5",
    "question": "The queen desired of Ammon to go to see her husband because some people had said that King Lamoni was dead and that he stunk but she said that her husband did not stink.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3500",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:6",
    "question": "Ammon knew that King Lamoni was under the power of God; he knew that the dark_____ of unbelief was being cast away from his mind.",
    "answer": "Veil",
    "options": ["Cloud", "Dream", "Veil"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3501",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:6",
    "question": "Ammon also knew that King Lamoni was experiencing a light which did light up his mind, which was the light of the Glory of God, which was a marvelous light of goodness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3502",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:6",
    "question": "Ammon knew that King Lamoni had the of everlasting life lighted up his soul and that he had overcome his_____ frame, and he was carried away in God.",
    "answer": "Natural",
    "options": ["Weakened", "Natural", "Spiritual"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3503",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:7",
    "question": "Ammon did not know that King Lamoni had passed away.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3504",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:8",
    "question": "Ammon told the queen that King Lamoni was not dead; but slept in_____, and that tomorrow he would rise again; therefore not to bury him.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3506",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon was wrong about his prediction, and King Lamoni did not arise when Ammon said he would.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3507",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:13",
    "question": "King Lamoni told his wife that he had seen his_____; and that he shall come forth, and be born of a woman, and he would redeem all mankind who believe in his name.",
    "answer": "Redeemer",
    "options": ["Forefathers", "Father", "Redeemer"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3508",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:14",
    "question": "King Lamoni’s heart was swollen with joy and he snaked to the ground and so did the queen because they had been overpowered by the Spirit.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3509",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:15",
    "question": "The servants of King Lamoni who testified to him about the great power of Ammon began to cry unto God because the fear of the Lord had come upon them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3510",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:16",
    "question": "All the servants of King Lamoni called on the name of the Lord until they all had fallen to the ground.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3511",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:16",
    "question": "What was the name of the servant of King Lamoni that had been converted unto the Lord for many years, on account of a remarkable vision of her father?",
    "answer": "Abish",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3512",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:16",
    "question": "Of what tribe was Abish?",
    "answer": "Lamanite",
    "options": ["Nephite", "Lamanite", "Ishmaelite"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3513",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:17",
    "question": "Abish let everyone of the servants of King Lamoni know that she had been converted to the Lord.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3514",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:17",
    "question": "Abish wanted to tell the people of what happened among them so she ran from house to_____, making it known unto the people.",
    "answer": "House",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3515",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:18",
    "question": "The multitude began to assemble themselves together and beheld the king, and the queen, and Ammon, and their servants lay_____ upon the earth.",
    "answer": "Prostrate",
    "options": ["Still", "Quietly", "Prostrate"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3516",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:19",
    "question": "The people began to murmur among themselves; some saying that it was a great evil that had come upon the king and his house because he had let a_____ remain in the land.",
    "answer": "Nephite",
    "options": ["Lamanite", "Nephite", "Zoramite"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3517",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:20",
    "question": "Some of the people rebuked the king saying that he had brought this evil upon his house, because he had slew his servants who had had their flocks scattered at the waters of_____.",
    "answer": "Sebus",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3518",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:22",
    "question": "One who was among the people was exceedingly angry with_____ because he had killed his brother and he went forth to slay Ammon; and as he lifted his sword to kill Ammon, he fell dead.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3519",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the multitude did not dare to touch Ammon, and began to marvel again among themselves what could be the cause of the great power that Ammon had and what all these things could mean.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3520",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there were many among the people who said Ammon was the Great_____, and others said he was sent by the Great Spirit.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3521",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:26",
    "question": "Some of the people said that Ammon was a_____, who had been sent from the Nephites to torment them.",
    "answer": "Monster",
    "options": ["Monster", "Devil", "Neither A Or B"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3522",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:27",
    "question": "And there were some who said that Ammon was sent by the Great Spirit to afflict them because of their iniquities.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3524",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:30",
    "question": "The queen did not clasp her hands, being filled with joy, speaking many words which were not understood.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3526",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:31",
    "question": "When King Lamoni saw the contention among his people he went forth and began to rebuke them, and to teach them the words which he had heard from_____.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3527",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma19:31-32",
    "question": "Many of the people were converted by the words of King Lamoni but there were many among them who would not hear his words; therefore they went on their way.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3528",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:33",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon stood up and began to administer unto the people, and also did all the servants of King Lamoni; they declared that their hearts had been changed; and they had no more desire to do_____.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3529",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma19:34",
    "question": "Many of the people of Lord began to declare to the people that they had seen_____ and had conversed with them; and they had told them the things of God, and his righteousness.",
    "answer": "Angels",
    "options": ["Devils", "Angels", "Dragons"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3530",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma19:36",
    "question": "And the work of the Lord did commence among the_____ and he began to pour his Spirit upon them; and we see that his arm is extended to all people who will repent and believe in his name.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3531",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:1",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 desired that Ammon would go with him to the land of Nephi, that he might show him unto his_____.",
    "answer": "Father",
    "options": ["Brother", "Mother", "Father"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3532",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:2",
    "question": "Who told Ammon not to go to the land of Nephi?",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3533",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:2",
    "question": "The Lord told Ammon not to go to the land of Nephi because who would seek his life?",
    "answer": "King",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3534",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:2",
    "question": "Ammon’s was told by the Lord that his brother’s Aaron, Muloki, and Ammah were in prison in the land of_____; and that he should go there.",
    "answer": "Middoni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3535",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:4",
    "question": "Who told Ammon that the king of the land of Middoni was his friend, and that he would go with him to flatter him and he would cast his brethren from prison?",
    "answer": "Lamoni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3536",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:6",
    "question": "When King Lamoni2 heard the words of Ammon he caused that his servants prepare his horses and his_____ for the trip.",
    "answer": "Chariots",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3537",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:8",
    "question": "When Ammon and King Lamoni2 where on their journey they came across King Lamoni1 who was king over all the land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3538",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:10",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 asked his son King Lamon2 why and where was he going with Ammon who was a_____?",
    "answer": "Nephite",
    "options": ["Bad Person", "Lamanite", "Nephite"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3539",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma-20:9,12",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told King Lamoni1 that he was tarrying in his own kingdom; and that was the reason he did not go to the feast his father had prepared for his sons.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3540",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:13",
    "question": "King Lamon2 was not astonished because King Lamon1 was angry with him.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3541",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:13",
    "question": "King Lamon1 told his son that Ammon was the son of liar, and had robbed their fathers by their cunning and their lyings; and had deceived them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3542",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:14",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 told his son to slay among with his_____ and not to go to the land of Middoni but to go to the land or Ishmael.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3543",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told King Lamoni1 that he would slay Ammon and go to the land of Ishmael.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3544",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 knew that Ammon and his brethren were just men and holy_____ of the true God.",
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3545",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:16",
    "question": "Because of the words that King Lamoni1 had told him, his father was angry with him and drew his sword to slay him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3546",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:17",
    "question": "Ammon stood before King Lamoni1 and told him that he should not slay his son because he was an innocent man and had _____of his sins.",
    "answer": "Repented",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3547",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:20",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 stretched forth his hand to slay Ammon.  But Ammon withstood his blows, and cut the_____ of the king.",
    "answer": "Arm",
    "options": ["Leg", "Arm", "Head"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3548",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:21",
    "question": "King Lamon1 saw that he could not slay Ammon and began to plead with Ammon to spare his life.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3549",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:22",
    "question": "Ammon told King Lamon1 that he would_____ him if he did not release his brethren from prison.",
    "answer": "Slay",
    "options": ["Slay", "Spare", "Free"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3550",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:23",
    "question": "King Lamon1 told Ammon that he would grant him anything that he would ask of him even half of his_____.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3551",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:26",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 saw that Ammon had know desire to slay him and a great_____ for his son, and he was astonished.",
    "answer": "Love",
    "options": ["Likeness", "Fondness", "Love"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3552",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:26",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 said that he would not grant unto his son his kingdom again and that he would continue to govern him.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3553",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:28",
    "question": "Because of his hardened heart King Lamoni1 did not release Ammon’s brethren from prison.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3554",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma20:29",
    "question": "When Ammon and King Lamoni2 were journeying toward the land of Middoni they met his brethren and they were exceedingly_____ because they saw that they were naked.",
    "answer": "Sorrowful",
    "options": ["Joyous", "Sorrowful", "Mad"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3555",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma20:29",
    "question": "Ammon’s brothers had suffered hunger, thirst, and all kinds of afflictions; nevertheless they were_____ in all their sufferings.",
    "answer": "Patient",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3556",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma20:30",
    "question": "It was their lot that Ammon’s brothers had fallen into the hands of a more hardened and a more stiffnecked Lamanites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3557",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:1",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren separated themselves again and Aaron took his journey towards the land that was called Jerusalem by the_____; calling it after the land of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3558",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:2",
    "question": "The Lamanites and Amalekites and the people of Amulon had built a great city which was called_____.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3559",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Aaron came upon the city of Jerusalem and first began to preach to the Amulonites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3560",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma21:4",
    "question": "Many of the Amalekites and Amulonites built_____ after the order of the Nehors.",
    "answer": "Synagogues",
    "options": ["Houses", "Barns", "Synagogues"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3561",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:5",
    "question": "When Aaron entered into a synagogue and began to preach unto them; there arose an Amalekite and began to contend with him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3562",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:8",
    "question": "The _____ that contended with Aaron did not believe that Aaron knew of things to come and knew of the things he had spoken of.",
    "answer": "Amalekite",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3563",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:9",
    "question": "Aaron began to open the_____ unto the people concerning the coming of Christ and also concerning the resurrection of the dead.",
    "answer": "Scriptures",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3564",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma21:9",
    "question": "Aaron told the people that there could be no redemption for mankind save it was through the death and sufferings of Christ, and the atonement of his_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Heart", "Blood", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3565",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:10",
    "question": "The people began to be angry with Aaron and started to mock him; and they would not hear his words so he left their synagogue.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3566",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:11",
    "question": "Aaron came upon the land which was called Ani-Anti and came upon his brother Muloki and also Ammah and his brethren contending with the people about the word of_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3567",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:13",
    "question": "Aaron and a certain number of his brethren were taken and cast into prison and the remainder of them fled to the land of Middoni and the regions surrounding it.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3569",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:17",
    "question": "Because of Aaron and his brethren many of the people were brought to the convincing of their sins, and of the traditions of their fathers, which were not correct.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3570",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma21:18",
    "question": "Ammon and King Lamoni2 returned from the land of Middoni to the land of Ishmael, which was the land of their_____.",
    "answer": "Inheritance",
    "options": ["Joy", "Hardship", "Inheritance"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3571",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:19",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 wanted Ammon to serve him and be his servant.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3572",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma21:21",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 caused that there should be synagogues built in the land of Ismael and declared unto those that were under his reign that they were a_____ people.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["Righteous", "Free", "Unrighteous"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3573",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:22",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 also declared unto the people that they had to liberty of worshiping the Lord their _____ according to their desires.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3574",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma21:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon did preach unto the people of King Lamoni2 all things pertaining to righteousness; and they were zealous in keeping the commandments of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3575",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:1",
    "question": "During the time when Ammon was teaching the people of King Lamoni2; Aaron and his brethren departed from the land of Middoni and were led by the_____ to the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3576",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:2",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren went unto the king’s_____ and bowed himself before the king.",
    "answer": "Palace",
    "options": ["Throne", "House", "Palace"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3577",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:3",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren desired that King Lamon1 would spare their lives and they would become his servants.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3578",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:3",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 was pleased with Aaron and his brethren and desired them to become his servants.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3579",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:3",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 insisted that Aaron administer unto him because he was troubled of the generosity and the_____ of the words of Ammon.",
    "answer": "Greatness",
    "options": ["Kindness", "Greatness", "Truthfulness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3580",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:3",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 did not want to know why Ammon had not come to the land of Middoni with_____ and his brethren.",
    "answer": "Aaron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3581",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:4",
    "question": "Who told King Lamoni1 that Ammon had been called by the Spirit of the Lord to go to the land of Ishmael to teach the people?",
    "answer": "Aaron",
    "options": ["Muloki", "Ammah", "Aaron"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3582",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:5",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 was troubled because Aaron had told him concerning the Spirit of the Lord.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3583",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:7",
    "question": "Aaron was not pleased with King Lamoni1 because he did not believe in God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3584",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:10",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 asked Aaron if God was the Great Spirit who had created all things both in heaven and in_____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3585",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:11",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 believed that the Great Spirit created all things and desired to know more concerning all the things that Aaron had said.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3586",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:13",
    "question": "Aaron did not start to teach King Lamoni1 about the creation of Adam and reading the scriptures unto the king.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3587",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:12",
    "question": "Aaron told the king how God created man after his own_____, and that God gave him commandments, and that because of transgression, man had fallen.",
    "answer": "Image",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3588",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:14",
    "question": "Aaron told King Lamoni1 since man had fallen he could not merit anything of himself; but the sufferings and death of_____ atoned for their sins, though faith and repentance, etc.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3589",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 asked Aaron what was required of him to have_____ life.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3590",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 also asked Aaron what he should do to be born of God, having his wicked spirit rooted out of his_____, and receive the Spirit, that he may be filled with joy.",
    "answer": "Breast",
    "options": ["Breast", "Body", "Chest"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3591",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 did not want to be cast off at the last day and said that he would forsake his_____, that he may receive great joy.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["Wife", "Children", "Kingdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3592",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:16",
    "question": "Aaron told King Lamoni1 that he needed to bow himself before God and repent of all of his sins and call on his name in faith, believing that he would receive the_____ which he desired.",
    "answer": "Hope",
    "options": ["Hope", "Answer", "Revelation"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3593",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Aaron had said these words, King Lamoni1 did not bow down before the Lord, upon hid knees; and lay prostrate himself upon the earth.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3594",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:18",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 told God that he would give away all his_____ to know him, and that he may be raised from the dead, and be saved at the last day.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["Fortune", "Sins", "Kingdoms"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3595",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:19",
    "question": "The servants of King Lamoni1 ran and told the_____ all that had happened unto the king.",
    "answer": "Queen",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3596",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:19",
    "question": "The queen was angry with Aaron and his brethren because she thought that they had been the cause of his fall, and commanded that her servants take and slay them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3597",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:21",
    "question": "The queen saw that the servants were afraid to lay their hands upon Aaron and his brethren and she began to fear exceedingly, lest there should some_____ come upon her.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["Curse", "Evil", "Omen"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3598",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:22",
    "question": "Because Aaron saw that there should be a great contention and disturbance among the people; he put forth his hand and raised King _____ from the earth.",
    "answer": "Lamoni1",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3599",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:23",
    "question": "When the queen and many of the servants saw what_____ had done they marveled and began to fear.  And King Lamoni1 stood forth, and began to minister unto them.",
    "answer": "Aaron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3600",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:23",
    "question": "Because of the ministering of King Lamoni1,all of his household was converted unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3601",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:25",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 administered unto his people and they were pacified towards Aaron and those who were with him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3602",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:27",
    "question": "The land of Zarahemla was divided by a_____ strip of wilderness, which ran from the sea east, and to the sea west.",
    "answer": "Narrow",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3603",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:27",
    "question": "The narrow strip of wilderness divided the_____ and the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3604",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:28",
    "question": "The Lamanites that were more idled lived in the wilderness and lived west of the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3605",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:28",
    "question": "The more _____of the Lamanites lived in the wilderness, and dwelt in tents; and they were spread through the wilderness on the west of the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Idle",
    "options": ["Idle", "Stiffnecked", "Ferocious"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3606",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:29",
    "question": "The Nephites were nearly surrounded by the_____; nevertheless they had taken possession of all the northern parts of the land bordering on the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3607",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:30",
    "question": "The land the Nephites called Bountiful bordered upon the land which they called_____; which was so far northward that it came into the land which been peopled, and been destroyed.",
    "answer": "Desolation",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3608",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:31",
    "question": "The land northward was called Desolation and the land southward was called_____.",
    "answer": "Bountiful",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3609",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:31",
    "question": "The land that was called Bountiful was filled with all manner of wild animals of every kind, and part of them had come from the land northward for_____.",
    "answer": "Food",
    "options": ["Water", "Refuge", "Food"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3610",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma22:32",
    "question": "How long did it take a Nephite to cross from the l1ne Bountiful to the land of Desolation?",
    "answer": "One Day And A Half",
    "options": [
      "One Day And A Half",
      "Two Days And A Half",
      "Three Days And A Half"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "3611",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma22:32",
    "question": "The land of Nephi and the land of Zarahemla were nearly surrounded by_____; and there was a small neck of land between the land northward and the land southward.",
    "answer": "Water",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3612",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma22:34",
    "question": "At the end of chapter 22 Mormon returns us again to the account of Ammon and Aaron, Omner and Himni, and their brethren.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3613",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the king of the Lamanites sent a proclamation among all his people, that they should not lay their hands upon Ammon and his",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3614",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:1",
    "question": "The proclamation the king of the Lamanites sent out among his people said that Ammon and his brethren would not go forth preaching the word of God",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3615",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:2",
    "question": "The king sent a decree among his people that they should let Ammon and his brethren into their houses, and also in their temples, and their_____.",
    "answer": "Sanctuaries",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3616",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:3",
    "question": "Because King Lamoni1 and his household had been converted; he sent his proclamation throughout the land unto his people, that the word of_____ might have no obstruction.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3617",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:3",
    "question": "King Lamoni1 wanted to convince all his people that they were all brethren, and that they ought not to murder, plunder, steal, nor commit adultery, nor to commit any manner of_____.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3618",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma23:5",
    "question": "Because of the preaching of Aaron and his brethren; _____ were brought to the knowledge of the Lord, and taught to believe in the traditions of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Thousands",
    "options": ["Hundreds", "Thousands", "Millions"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3619",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:5",
    "question": "Thousands of_____ were taught the records and prophecies which were handed down even to the present time.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3620",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:6",
    "question": "Many Lamanites were brought to the knowledge of the truth, through the preaching of Ammon and his brethren, according to the spirit of revelation, and the power of God working miracles in them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3621",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:6",
    "question": "And as sure as the Lord lives, many of the Lamanites that were taught the word of God by Ammon and his brethren fell away from the church.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3622",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:7",
    "question": "Many of the Lamanites became a righteous people and put down their weapons of rebellion and did not fight against God anymore, neither against any of their brethren.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3623",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma23:14",
    "question": "Only_____ of the Amalekites were converted unto the church of God by Ammon and his brethren.",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3624",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:14",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren were able to convert many of the Amulonites unto the church of God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3625",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma23:16",
    "question": "Because the king desired to have a name to distinguish themselves from their brethren; they consulted with Aaron and many of his priests concerning the name they should take upon themselves.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3626",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:17",
    "question": "The name that the people took upon themselves was Anti-_____; and they were no longer called Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3627",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma23:17 & Alma27:26",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehies were also known by what other name?",
    "answer": "Ammonites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3628",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma23:18",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehies became a very_____ people; and they were friendly with the Nephites and the curse of God did no more follow them.",
    "answer": "Industrious",
    "options": ["Idolatrous", "Industrious", "Lazy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3629",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people who were not converted to the church and had not take upon the name of Anti-Nephi-Lehies were stirred up by the Amulonites and_____ to anger against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Amalekites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3630",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:2",
    "question": "The people began to rebel against their king and took up arms against the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3631",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:3",
    "question": "The king conferred the_____ upon his son, and he was called Anti-Lehi-Nephi.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3632",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:5",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren wanted to have a council meeting with King Lamoni2 and his brother Anti-Nephi-_____.",
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3633",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:6",
    "question": "There was not one soul among all the people that had been converted unto the Lord that would take up arms against their brethren; and they would also not make preparations of war.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3634",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:8",
    "question": "King_____ thank his great God that he had given him and his people a portion of his Spirit to soften their hearts, that they were able to have opened a correspondence with their brethren the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamoni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3635",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:10",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told the people and thanked his great_____, for forgiving them of their many sins and murders which they had committed, and had taken away the guilt from their hearts, through the Merits of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3636",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma24:12",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 said to the people since God had taken away their stains, their_____ had become bright, and not to stain them no more with the blood of their brethren.",
    "answer": "Swords",
    "options": ["Hearts", "Sins", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3637",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:14",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 said that God loved their souls as well as their children; therefore, in his mercy he had visited them by his angels that the plan of_____ might be made known unto them as well as future generations.",
    "answer": "Salvation",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3638",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma24:15",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told the people to hide their swords that they may remain bright as a_____ to their God at the last day, that they would not stain them again with the blood of their brethren.",
    "answer": "Testimony",
    "options": ["Witness", "Testimony", "Pledge"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3639",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:16",
    "question": "King Lamoni2 told the people to hide their swords and_____ them deep in the earth, that they may be kept bright; and if their brethren did destroy them, they would go to their God and be saved.",
    "answer": "Bury",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3640",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:17",
    "question": "The people took their swords and all the weapons of war which were used for the shedding of man’s_____, and did bury them up deep in the earth.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3641",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:18",
    "question": "By burying their weapons of war the people were vouching and covenanting with God that they would give up their own lives.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3642",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:18",
    "question": "The people that were converted unto the Lord said that they would spend their days in idleness and would not labor abundantly with their hands.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3643",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites came up to the land of Nephi with the purpose of destroying the king, and to place another in his stead, and to destroy the people of Anti-Nephi-_____ out of the land.",
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3644",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:21",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's prostrated themselves before the Lamanites upon the earth; and they were in this attitude and position when the Lamanites fell upon them and began to slay them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3645",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:24",
    "question": "The_____ slew a thousand and five of the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's before they quit slaying them because their hearts were swollen; and repented to the Lord for the things which they had done.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3646",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:27",
    "question": "Of all the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's that were slain, there was not a wicked man among them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3647",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:27",
    "question": "More than a thousand of the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were brought to the knowledge of the truth; and thus we see that the____ works in many ways to the salvation of his people.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3648",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:28",
    "question": "The greatest number of those of the Lamanites who slew so many of their brethren were_____ and Amulonites, and they were of the order of the Nehors.",
    "answer": "Amalekites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3649",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:29",
    "question": "Many of the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were actual descendants of_____ and Lemuel.",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3650",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma24:30",
    "question": "Mormon reminds us that once a people have been enlightened by the Spirit of God, and have had a great knowledge of things pertaining to righteousness, and fall away and transgress, they become more hardened.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3651",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma24:30",
    "question": "Mormon writes that people who have been enlightened by the Spirit of_____ and have a great knowledge of things pertaining to righteousness, and have fallen away and transgress; their state becomes worse than though they have never known the things of God.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3652",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:1",
    "question": "The Lamanites were angry with themselves because they had slain their brethren the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's and swore vengeance upon the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3653",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:2",
    "question": "The Lamanites took their armies and went over to the land of Zarahemla, and fell upon the people who were in the land of_____, and destroyed them.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3654",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:4",
    "question": "And among the Lamanites who were slain were almost all the seed of_____ and his brethren who was the leader of the priests of King Noah.",
    "answer": "Amulon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3655",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:7",
    "question": "The rest of the priest of King Noah fled into the east wilderness and having usurped the power and authority of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3656",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma25:5",
    "question": "The priest of King Noah caused that many of the Lamanites should perish by_____ because of their belief in the Lord.",
    "answer": "Fire",
    "options": ["Hanging", "Firing Squad", "Fire"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3657",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:7",
    "question": "The rulers who were the remnant of the children of Amulon caused that they should be put to death; all those that believed in the things of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3658",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:8",
    "question": "The_____ began to hunt the seed of Amulon and his brethren and began to slay them; and they fled into the east wilderness.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3659",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:9",
    "question": "The words of_____ were brought to pass, which he said concerning the seed of the priests who caused that he should suffer death by fire.",
    "answer": "Abinadi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3660",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:10",
    "question": "Abinadi had said to the priests of King Noah:  What you shall do unto me shall be a_____ of things to come.",
    "answer": "Type",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3661",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:11",
    "question": "Abinadi was the first that suffered death by fire because of his belief in God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3662",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:11",
    "question": "Abinadi is considered to be the first martyr in the Book of Mormon by many Book of Mormon scholars.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3663",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:12",
    "question": "The words of_____ were verified what he told the priests of King Noah because their seed had been driven and hunted and smitten by the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Abinadi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3664",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that many of the Lamanites came over to dwell in the land of Ishmael and Nephi, and did join themselves to the people of God, who were the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3665",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:14",
    "question": "Some of the Lamanites did bury their weapons of war and began to be a righteous people, and they did walk in the ways of the_____, and did observe to keep his commandments and his statutes.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3666",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma25:15",
    "question": "The Lamanites did keep the Law of_____; because it had not yet been fulfilled.",
    "answer": "Mosess",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3667",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:15",
    "question": "Some of the Lamanites did not look forward to the coming of Christ, considering that the Law of Moses was a type of his coming.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3668",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma25:16",
    "question": "The Lamanites did not suppose that_____ came by the Law of Moses; but the law of Moses did serve to strengthen their faith in Christ; and thus they did retain a hope through faith.",
    "answer": "Salvation",
    "options": ["Riches", "Salvation", "Favoritism"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3669",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma25:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammon, Aaron, Omner, and Himni, and their brethren did not rejoice exceedingly, for the success they had had among the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3670",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:2",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that they had had great success because of the_____ the Lord had bestowed upon them.",
    "answer": "Blessings",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3671",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:3",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that the Lamanites were in darkness, yea, even in the darkest_____, but now many of them were brought to behold the marvelous light of God!",
    "answer": "Abyss",
    "options": ["Abyss", "Canyon", "Hole"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3672",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:3",
    "question": "Ammon also told his brethren that they had become_____ in the hands of God to bring about this great work among the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Instruments",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3673",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:5",
    "question": "Ammon said the field was ripe and they thrust what farm tool into the field and did reap with their might, and day long in laboring?",
    "answer": "Sickle",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3674",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:6",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that the storm cannot penetrate them; neither shall they be driven with fierce winds whithersoever the enemy desires to carry them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3675",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:10",
    "question": "Which one of Ammon’s brothers rebuked him and accused him of boasting?",
    "answer": "Aaron",
    "options": ["Himni", "Aaron", "Omner"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3676",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:11",
    "question": "Ammon told his brother Aaron that he did not boast in his own strength, neither in his own wisdom; but that his heart was full of joy and would rejoice in his_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3677",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:12",
    "question": "Ammon told his brother that he knew he was nothing; therefore he would not boast of himself, but that he would boast of his God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3678",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:12",
    "question": "Ammon told Aaron that in the strength of whom could he do all things?",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3679",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:14",
    "question": "Ammon said they had reason to praise God forever, because the Lord was the Most High God, and loosed our brethren from the chains of_____.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["Death", "Misery", "Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3680",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:15",
    "question": "Ammon said to Aaron the Lord had encircled them with the matchless bounty of his_____; and they had been instruments in his hands of doing his great and marvelous work.",
    "answer": "Love",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3681",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:16",
    "question": "Ammon wanted his brethren to glory in the Lord; and said that who could glory in the Lord too much.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3682",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:16",
    "question": "Ammon said he could not say the_____ part of which he felt about God.",
    "answer": "Smallest",
    "options": ["Biggest", "Smallest", "Largest"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3683",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:20",
    "question": "Ammon said that the Lord did not exercise his justice upon him and his brethren when they went about trying to destroy his_____.",
    "answer": "Church",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3684",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:20",
    "question": "Ammon said that the Lord did not exercise his justice upon him and his brethren when they went about trying to destroy his church.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3685",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:20",
    "question": "Ammon said the Lord in his great mercy had brought them over the everlasting gulf of death and misery, even to the salvation of their souls.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3686",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:21",
    "question": "Ammon said that there is no_____ man that can know the things of God save it be those that have a feeling of expressing humbleness or regretful pain or sorrow for his sins.",
    "answer": "Natural",
    "options": ["Natural", "Strong", "Rich"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3687",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:22",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that those who repent and exercise faith and bring forth good works and prays continually without ceasing—unto such is given to know the_____of God.",
    "answer": "Mysteries",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3688",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:22",
    "question": "Ammon said that those who is given the mysteries of God; also can be given to reveal things which never have been revealed.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3689",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:26",
    "question": "Ammon reminded his beloved brethren, that they came into the wilderness not with the intent to destroy their brethren, but with the intent that perhaps they might save some of their souls.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3690",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:27",
    "question": "Ammon said when their hearts were depressed, and were about to turn back, the Lord had comforted them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3691",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:27",
    "question": "The Lord told Ammon and his brethren to go among the Lamanites, and bear with patience your afflictions; and I will give you_____.",
    "answer": "Success",
    "options": ["Money", "Success", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3692",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:28",
    "question": "Ammon said that they had gone from house to house, relying upon the mercies of the world—not upon the mercies of the world alone but upon the____ of God.",
    "answer": "Mercies",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3693",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:29",
    "question": "Ammon told his brethren that they had been delivered through the power and_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "options": ["Goodness", "Wisdom", "Skill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3694",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:30",
    "question": "Ammon said that they had suffered all manner of afflictions, that perhaps they might be the means of saving some few_____.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3695",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma26:31",
    "question": "Ammon said they could witness of the sincerity of the brethren they had saved because of their love towards their brethren and towards them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3696",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:33",
    "question": "Ammon and his brethren knew that the Lamanites that had been slain had gone to their God because of their love and of their hatred towards_____.",
    "answer": "Sin",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3697",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma26:35",
    "question": "Ammon said that there have never been men born that had so great reason to rejoice as him and his_____ since the world began.",
    "answer": "Brethren",
    "options": ["Wives", "Sons", "Brethren"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3698",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:35",
    "question": "Ammon said that God has all power, all wisdom, and all understanding; he comprehends all things, and he is a merciful Being, even unto salvation, to those who will_____ and believe in his name.",
    "answer": "Repent",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3699",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:36",
    "question": "Ammon boasted in the name of his God, who had been mindful of the Lamanites, who are a branch of the tree of_____, and had been lost from its body in a strange land.",
    "answer": "Israel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3700",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma26:37",
    "question": "Ammon reminded his brethren that God is mindful of every people, whatsoever land they may be; and numbers his people, and his_____ of mercy are over all the earth.",
    "answer": "Bowels",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3701",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:2",
    "question": "The_____ were angry because of their losses in war and they saw that they could not seek revenge from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Amalekites",
    "options": ["Amalekites", "Amulonites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3702",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:2",
    "question": "The Amalekites began to stir up the people in anger against their brethren, the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3703",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:3",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's again refused to take up their arms, and they suffered themselves to be slain according to the desires of their enemies.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3704",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:4",
    "question": "Ammon and his_____ saw this great work of destruction and they were moved with compassion.",
    "answer": "Brethren",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3705",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:5",
    "question": "Ammon wanted to gather the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's and go down to the land of Zarahemla of their brethren; the_____, and flee out of the hands of their enemies, that they may not be destroyed.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3706",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:7",
    "question": "Who did Ammon inquired of to see if he would say to him to go down to Zarahemla among the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3707",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:9",
    "question": "Who established the laws in Zarahemla that said there should be no slaves among the land?",
    "answer": "King Mosiah2",
    "options": ["King Noah", "King Mosiah2", "King Benjamin"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3708",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:12",
    "question": "When Ammon inquired of the Lord he told him not to go to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3709",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:12",
    "question": "Who did the Lord say to Ammon had a great hold on the hearts of the Amalekites, who do stir up the Lamanites to anger against their brethren?",
    "answer": "Satan",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3710",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:13",
    "question": "When Ammon finished inquiring of the Lord he did not go and tell the kings all the words which the Lord had said unto him.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3711",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as Ammon was going forth into the land of Zarahemla, he and his brethren met_____, and it was a joyful meeting.",
    "answer": "Younger",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3712",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:17",
    "question": "Ammon was so joyous when he met Alma the Younger that he fell to the ground.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3713",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:18",
    "question": "Mormon writes that Ammon’s joy can none receive save it be the truly penitent and humble seeker of happiness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3714",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:19",
    "question": "Ammon was accompanied by his brethren which were Aaron, Omner, and _____.",
    "answer": "Himni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3715",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:20",
    "question": "Alma the Younger took Ammon and his brethren to his own_____; and they went and told the chief judge all the things that had happened unto them in the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "House",
    "options": ["Inn", "House", "Farm House"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3716",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:21",
    "question": "Alma the Younger sent a proclamation throughout all the land, desiring the_____ of the people concerning the admitting their brethren, who were the people of Anti-Nephi-Lehis.",
    "answer": "Voice",
    "options": ["Vote", "Hearts", "Voice"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3717",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass the voice of the people came saying:”We will give up the land of_____ unto our brethren for an inheritance”.",
    "answer": "Jershon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3718",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:24",
    "question": "The Nephites said that they would set of their armies between the land of Jershon and the land of Nephi to protect the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3719",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:25,26",
    "question": "Ammon and Alma the Younger related to the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's the conditions of the Nephites and they were not joyous and did not agree to the terms.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3720",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:26 & Alma57:6",
    "question": "What is the name that the Nephites gave to the people of Ammon who were known for their zeal towards God?",
    "answer": "Ammonites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3721",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:27",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's became among the people of Nephi, and also numbered among the people who were of the church of God",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3722",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:27",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were distinguished for their_____ towards God.",
    "answer": "Zeal",
    "options": ["Love", "Zeal", "Red Mark On Their Foreheads"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3723",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:27",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were perfectly honest and upright in all things; and they were firm in the faith of_____, even unto the end.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3724",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma27:28",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's looked upon shedding the_____of their brethren with the greatest abhorrence.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3725",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma27:28",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi's never did look upon death with any degree of terror, for their hope and views of Christ and the resurrection; therefore, death was swallowed up to them by the victory of Christ over it.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3726",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma27:30",
    "question": "Because of their beliefs the Anti-Nephi-Lehi's were a zealous and beloved people, and a highly_____ people of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Favored",
    "options": ["Looked Upon", "Motivated", "Favored"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3727",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma28:1",
    "question": "It came to pass that the Ammonites were established in the land of Jershon and also established a_____.",
    "answer": "Church",
    "options": ["Fraternity", "Club", "Church"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3729",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma28:2-3",
    "question": "During this time in Nephites history the most tremendous battle between the Nephites and Lamanites occurred in which tens of thousands of Lamanites were slaughtered and also of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3730",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:4",
    "question": "Because of the tremendous battle between the Lamanites and Nephites; there was a great mourning and lamentation heard throughout all the land, among all the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3731",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:10",
    "question": "From the first year to the fifteenth years of the reign of the_____ it had brought to pass the destruction of many thousands of lives, and also has brought to pass an awful scene of bloodshed.",
    "answer": "Judges",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3732",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:11",
    "question": "The bodies of many thousands were moldering in heaps upon the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3733",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:12",
    "question": "The Nephites had hope and rejoiced and even know according to the promises of the Lord, that those that died are raised to dwell at the_____ hand of God, in a state of never-ending happiness.",
    "answer": "Right",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3734",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:13",
    "question": "Mormon writes to us that the inequality of man comes about because of sin and transgression, and the power of the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3735",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma28:13",
    "question": "The inequality of man comes about because of sin and transgression and the power of the devil; which comes by the cunning plans which he devises to ensnare the hearts of men.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3737",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma28:14",
    "question": "Mormon writes that there is a great reason of sorrow, and also rejoicing-sorrow because of death and destruction among men, and joy because of the light of_____ unto life.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3738",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:1",
    "question": "Alma2 wished that he was an_____, and could go forth and speak with the trump of God, with a voice to shake the earth, and cry repentance unto every people!",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3739",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he would declare unto every soul, as with the voice of_____, repentance and the plan of redemption; that they should repent and come unto God.",
    "answer": "Thunder",
    "options": ["Thunder", "Clarity", "Electricity"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3740",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:2",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted to declare to the people with the voice of thunder to come unto repentance that there might not be more sorrow upon all the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3741",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he should not be content with the things which the Lord had allotted unto him.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3742",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:4",
    "question": "Alma2 testified that he knew that the Lord grants unto men according to their_____, whether it should be unto death or unto life.",
    "answer": "Desire",
    "options": ["Wishes", "Desire", "Likes"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3743",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:4",
    "question": "Alma2 also knew that the Lord allots unto men according to their_____, whether they should be unto salvation or unto destruction.",
    "answer": "Wills",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3744",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:5",
    "question": "Alma2 testified that he knew the choice of good and_____ has come before all men, and he that knows not good from evil is blameless.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3745",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:5",
    "question": "Alma2 testified that he knew the choice of good and evil has come before all men, and he that knows not good from evil is blameless.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3746",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:5",
    "question": "Alma2 knew to him it is given according to his desires, whether he desires good or evil, life or death, joy or remorse of conscience.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3747",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:6,7",
    "question": "Because of all the things he knew; Alma2 wondered why he desired to be an angel, and desired more than to perform the work to which he had been called.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3748",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord does grant unto all nations, of their own nation and_____, to teach his word, and in his wisdom he sees to it that they should have all they need.",
    "answer": "Tongue",
    "options": ["Tongue", "Tribe", "Company"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3749",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord does counsel in wisdom, according to that which is_____ and true.",
    "answer": "Just",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3750",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:9",
    "question": "Alma2 knew what the Lord had commanded of him and gloried in it.  He did not_____ of himself, but did glory in that which the Lord had commanded of him.",
    "answer": "Gloried",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3751",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:9",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted to be an_____ in the hands of God and to bring some soul to repentance; and this was his joy.",
    "answer": "Instrument",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3752",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said that when he saw many of his brethren truly penitent; and coming to the Lord their God, then his soul was filled with_____.",
    "answer": "Joy",
    "options": ["Gladness", "Mercy", "Joy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3753",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said when he saw many of his brethren coming to the Lord their God; then he does remember what the Lord has done for him, even that he has heard his_____.",
    "answer": "Prayers",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3754",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said he could not recall when the Lord his God stretched his merciful arm which he extended towards him.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3755",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:11",
    "question": "Alma2 remembered the captivity of his_____; and he surely did know that the Lord did deliver them out of bondage, and by this he established his church.",
    "answer": "Fathers",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3756",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:11",
    "question": "Alma2 also knew that the Lord God, the God of_____, the God of Isaac, and the God of Jacob, did deliver them out of bondage.",
    "answer": "Abraham",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3757",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma29:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he had always remembered the captivity of his fathers; and that the same God who delivered them out of the hands of the_____ did deliver them out of bondage.",
    "answer": "Egyptians",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3758",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma2913",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the same God did establish his church among them and that the same God had called him by a_____ calling.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["Precious", "Holy", "Sacred"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3759",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God had called him to a holy calling to preach the word unto this people, and had given him much success, in which his joy was full.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3760",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said his joy had been more full because of the success of his brethren, who have been up to the land of Nephi preaching the word of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3761",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that his brethren have labored exceedingly preaching the word of God, and have brought much_____; and how great shall be their reward!",
    "answer": "Fruit",
    "options": ["Success", "Fruit", "Vegetables"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3762",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma29:17",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted God to grant unto his brethren, that they may sit down in the_____ of God; and also al those who are the fruit of their labors that they may go no more out, but that they may praise him forever.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["Kingdom", "Throne", "Seat"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3763",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma29:17",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted God that he would grant unto him that it may be done according to his words, even as he had spoken it. Amen",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3764",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after the tremendous battle; the dead of the Lamanites and Nephites were not numbered because of the greatness of their numbers.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3765",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:2",
    "question": "But it came to pass that after they had buried their dead, and also after the days of fasting, and mourning, and_____, there began to be continual peace throughout all the land.",
    "answer": "Prayer",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3766",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:3",
    "question": "The Nephites did observe to keep the commandments of the Lord; and they were not strict in observing the ordinances of God; according to the Law of Moses.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3767",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:3",
    "question": "The Nephites were taught to keep the Law of_____ until it should be fulfilled.",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3768",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:6",
    "question": "In the latter end of the seventeenth year of the reign of the judges; there came a man into the land of_____, and he was an Anti-Christ.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3769",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:6",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book; do we find the words “Anti-Christ” first mentioned?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3770",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:6",
    "question": "The man who was an Anti-Christ began to preach unto the people against the prophecies which had been spoken by the prophets, concerning the coming of_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3771",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:7",
    "question": "There was no law among the Nephites against a man’s belief; for it was strictly contrary to the commands of God that there should be a law which should bring men on to unequal grounds.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3772",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:8",
    "question": "For thus says the scriptures: “Choose ye this day, whom ye will_____”.",
    "answer": "Serve",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3773",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:9",
    "question": "If a man desired to serve God, it was his_____; or rather, if he believed in God it was his privilege to serve him; but if he did not believe in God there was no law to punish him.",
    "answer": "Privilege",
    "options": ["Right", "Liberty", "Privilege"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3774",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:10",
    "question": "According to Nephite law if a man murdered another man he was punished and put to_____.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3775",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:10",
    "question": "People were not punished for robbing, stealing, and committing adultery and for all this wickedness and they were not punished but a fine was imposed on them.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3776",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:11",
    "question": "The Nephites had a law that a man would be punished for his beliefs.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3777",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:11",
    "question": "For the Nephites there was a law that men should be judged according to their_____.  And there was no law against a man’s belief, but a man was punished only for the crimes which he had done.",
    "answer": "Crimes",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3778",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:12",
    "question": "What was the name of the Anti-Christ that came into the land of Zarahemla preaching that there should be no Christ?_____",
    "answer": "Korihor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3779",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:13",
    "question": "Korihor told the people of_____ that they were bound down under a foolish and vain hope and yoked themselves with such foolish things, and that no man could know of anything which is to come.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3780",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:13",
    "question": "Korihor told the Nephites that only a just and holy prophet of the Lord could know of anything which is to come.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3781",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:14",
    "question": "Korihor said the things the people called prophecies, which they said are handed down by the holy prophets, were foolish_____ of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Traditions",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3782",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:15",
    "question": "Korihor told the Nephites that they could not know of things which they could not see; therefore they cannot know that there shall be a_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3783",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:16",
    "question": "Korihor told the people that when they looked forward and said they saw a remission of their sins; it was the effect of a frenzied_____.",
    "answer": "Mind",
    "options": ["Thought", "Mind", "Head"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3784",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:16",
    "question": "Korihor told the Nephites that the derangement of their minds came because of the traditions of their fathers, which led them away into a belief of things which were not so.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3785",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:17",
    "question": "Korihor said many more false things unto the people, telling them that there could be no_____ made for the sins of men, but every man fared in this life according to the management of the creature.",
    "answer": "Atonement",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3786",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:17",
    "question": "Korihor told the Nephites that every man prospered according to his_____, and that every man conquered according to his strength; and whatsoever a man did was no crime.",
    "answer": "Genius",
    "options": ["Know How", "Brain", "Genius"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3787",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:18",
    "question": "Because of his preaching Korihor led the hearts of many Nephites away, causing them to lift up their heads in their wickedness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3788",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:18",
    "question": "Korihor led many women, and also men, to commit_____telling them that when a man was dead, that was the end thereof.",
    "answer": "Whoredoms",
    "options": ["Robberies", "Whoredoms", "Murders"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3789",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:19 & 27:26",
    "question": "Korihor also went to the land of Jershon to preach false things among the_____ who were the people of Ammon, who were once the people of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Ammonites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3790",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:20",
    "question": "The people of Ammon were more wise than many of the Nephites; and they took_____ and bound him and carried him before Ammon, who was a high priest over the people.",
    "answer": "Korihor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3791",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:19,21",
    "question": "Who caused that Korihor should be carried out of the land of Jershon?",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3792",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:21",
    "question": "Korihor than went to the land of Gideon, and began to preach to them also; and here he did have much success.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3793",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:21,23",
    "question": "The people in the land of Gideon took Korihor and bound and carried him before the high priest whose name was_____.",
    "answer": "Giddonah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3794",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:21 & 23:16",
    "question": "And Korihor was also taken before the chief judge over the land whose was name_____.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3795",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:22",
    "question": "Giddonah asked_____ why he went about perverting the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Korihor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3796",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:22",
    "question": "Giddonah the high priest did not ask Korihor why he went about the land of Gideon perverting the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3797",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:22",
    "question": "Giddonah asked Korihor why he taught the people that there should be no_____, and interrupting their rejoicings; and why he spoke against all the prophecies of the holy prophets.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3798",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:23",
    "question": "Korihor told Giddonah and Alma2 that he taught the things he did because he did not teach the foolish_____of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Traditions",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3799",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:23",
    "question": "Korihor told Giddonah and Alma2 that he did not teach the people to bind themselves down under the foolish ordinances and performances which are laid down by ancient priests.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3800",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:23",
    "question": "Korihor also told Giddonah and Alma2 that the ancient_____ taught what they did to the people to usurp power and authority over them.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Prophets", "Priests", "Elders"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3801",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:23",
    "question": "Korihor told Giddonah and Alma2 that the ancient_____ taught things to keep the people in ignorance, that they may not lift there heads, but be brought down according to their words.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Prophets", "Priests", "Elders"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3802",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:24",
    "question": "Korihor said to Giddonah and Alma2 that the people were not a_____ people, but a people that were in bondage.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3803",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:24",
    "question": "Giddonah and Alma2 taught the people that the ancient prophecies were true but Korihor said that they were not_____.",
    "answer": "True",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3804",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:25",
    "question": "Korihor accused Giddonah and Alma2 of saying the Nephites were a guilty and a fallen people because of the transgressions of their parents. But he said that a child is not guilty because of his parents.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3805",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:27",
    "question": "Korihor said that Giddonah and Alma2 taught according to their own desires; and to keep the people down, even as if they were in bondage, that they may_____ themselves with the labors of their hands.",
    "answer": "Glut",
    "options": ["Glut", "Fill", "Stuff"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3806",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:27",
    "question": "Korihor told Giddonah and Alma2 that the people did not dare to look up with boldness, and that they did not_____ to enjoy their rights and privileges.",
    "answer": "Dare",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3807",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:28",
    "question": "Korihor said that the people did not dare to make use of that which is their own because they might offend their_____.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Gods", "Elders", "Priests"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3808",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:28",
    "question": "Korihor said that if the people did not do what Giddonah and Alma2 said according to their words, they might offend some unknown being, who they said is_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3809",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:28",
    "question": "Korihor said that God is a being who never has been_____ or known, who never was or will never ever be.",
    "answer": "Seen",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3810",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:29",
    "question": "Giddonah and Alma2 saw the hardness of the heart of_____, and that he would revile even against God, they would not make any reply to his words.",
    "answer": "Korihor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3811",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:29",
    "question": "Giddonah and the high_____ caused that Korihor should be bound; and they delivered him up to the hands of the officers, and sent him to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Priest",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3812",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:29",
    "question": "Giddonah and the high priest caused that Korihor be brought before_____, and the chief judge who was governor over all the land.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3813",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:30",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Korihor was brought before Alma2 the chief judge, and he did go on in the same manner as he had done in the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Gideon",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Jershon", "Gideon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3814",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:30",
    "question": "Because of the words that_____ had said, he was a blasphemous person.",
    "answer": "Korihor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3815",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:31",
    "question": "Korihor did rise up in great swelling words before Alma2, and did revile against the priests and teachers, accusing them of leading away the people after the silly_____ of their fathers.",
    "answer": "Traditions",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3816",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:32",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he knew that they did not glut themselves upon the labors of the people.  And that he had labored from the commencement of the reign of judges, with his own_____.",
    "answer": "Hands",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3817",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma11:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he had never received so much as even one_____; which was a monetary unit used by the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Seon",
    "options": ["Seon", "Senine", "Limnah"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3818",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:33",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he had never received so much as even one senine but that his brethren were the only ones to receive compensation.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3819",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:34",
    "question": "Alma2 said to Korihor that the only thing he and his brethren received for their labors in the church was to declare the truth, and have rejoicings in the joy of their people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3820",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:35",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that it was not possible that he and his brethren had deceived the people because their teachings had caused great joy in their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Hearts", "Heads", "Bodies"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3821",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:38",
    "question": "At the time that Alma2 first asked Korihor if he believed there was a God he said yes.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3822",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:39",
    "question": "Alma2 testified to Korihor that he knew there was a God and that_____ shall come.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3823",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:40",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that the only evidence he had that there is no God and that Christ will not come was only his_____.",
    "answer": "Word",
    "options": ["Bible", "Beliefs", "Word"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3824",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:42",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Korihor knew there was a God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3825",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:42",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Korihor was possessed with a_____ spirit, and that he had put of the Spirit of God and that it had no place in him.",
    "answer": "Lying",
    "options": ["Good", "Bad", "Lying"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3826",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:42",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say had power over Korihor?_____",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3827",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:42",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the devil had power over Korihor and carried him about; working devices that he may destroy the_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3828",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:43",
    "question": "Korihor wanted Alma2 to show him a_____, that he may be convinced that there was a God; and show unto him that he has power, and then he would be convinced of the truth in Alma2’s words.",
    "answer": "Sign",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3829",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he already has signs that there was a God and not to_____ God.",
    "answer": "Tempt",
    "options": ["Question", "Tempt", "Deny"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3830",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 said that these things proved there was a God:  His personal testimony and also the testimonies of his brethren",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3831",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "The testimony of all the holy prophets.  The scriptures and even the earth, and all things that are upon the face of it; prove that there is a God",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3832",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that also these things denoted that there is a God:  The motion of the earth and also all the planets which move in their regular form do witness that there is a Supreme_____.",
    "answer": "Creator",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3833",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that there is a Supreme Creator.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3834",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:44",
    "question": "Alma2 testified to Korihor about the motion of planets.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3835",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:45",
    "question": "Even after all the things Alma2 showed to Korihor that proved there was a God, he said he would still deny there was a God unless showed him a_____.",
    "answer": "Sign",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3836",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:46",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 was grieved because of the_____ of the heart of Korihor, and that he still resisted the spirit of the truth, that his soul may be destroyed.",
    "answer": "Hardness",
    "options": ["Stupidity", "Hatred", "Hardness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3837",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:47",
    "question": "Alma2 said that it was better that the soul of Korihor should be lost than he may and should have the means of bringing many_____ down to destruction.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3838",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:47",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Korihor used lying words and flattering words to make the people believe that there was no God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3839",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:47",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that if he denied again that there was no God, that God would smite him and that he would become_____.",
    "answer": "Dumb",
    "options": ["Crazy", "Sick", "Dumb"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3840",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:47",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he would become dumb and would never open his mouth again and deceive the Nephites anymore.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3842",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:48",
    "question": "Korihor said that he did not deny the existence of a_____, but that he did not believe that there was a God.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3843",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:48",
    "question": "Korihor told Almsa2 that he did not know that there is a God; and except he showed him a sign, he would not believe.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3844",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:49",
    "question": "Alma2 told Korihor that he would give him a sign, that he would be struck dumb, according to his words; and he said that in the name of God he would be struck dumb and no more have utterance.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3845",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:50",
    "question": "When Alma2 said the words which he said, Korihor was struck_____, that he could not have utterance, according to the words of Alma2.",
    "answer": "Dumb",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3846",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:51",
    "question": "What person put forth his hand and wrote unto Korihor these words: Art thou convinced of the power of God?",
    "answer": "The Chief Judge",
    "options": ["Alma2", "Ammon", "The Chief Judge"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3847",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:52",
    "question": "Korihor did not write back to the chief judge and did not confess that he knew that he was dumb and could not speak.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3848",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:52",
    "question": "Korihor wrote that he knew that it was the power of_____ that brought upon him the inability to speak.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3849",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:52",
    "question": "Korihor wrote that he knew that there was a God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3850",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Who did Korihor say had deceived him?_____",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3851",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Korihor wrote that the devil had appeared unto him in the form of an_____.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["Dove", "Angel", "Serpent"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3852",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "The devil told Korihor to go and reclaim the people, because they had gone astray after an unknown_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3853",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "The devil did not tell Korihor that there was no God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3854",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Who taught Korihor all the words which he should say unto the people?",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3855",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Korihor taught the words that he did and had much success with them because they were_____ unto the carnal mind.",
    "answer": "Pleasing",
    "options": ["Intelligent", "Challenging", "Pleasing"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3856",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Korihor said that because the words were pleasing unto the carnal mind he started to believe that they were actually true.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3857",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:53",
    "question": "Korihor confessed that he did not know why such a curse was put on him.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3858",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:54",
    "question": "Who did Korihor wished that would pray to God on his behalf to take away the curse from him?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3859",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:55",
    "question": "Alma2 said that it was up to_____ to take away the curse from Korihor.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3860",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:56",
    "question": "After Alma2 prayed unto the Lord; the curse was taken away from Korihor.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3861",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:56",
    "question": "Korihor was cast out and went about from house to house_____ for his food.",
    "answer": "Begging",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3862",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:57",
    "question": "The knowledge of what had happened to Korihor was published throughout all the land in a_____.",
    "answer": "Proclamation",
    "options": ["Text Message", "Proclamation", "Newspaper"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3863",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:57",
    "question": "What person sent the proclamation throughout all the land of what had happened to Korihor?",
    "answer": "Chief Judge",
    "options": ["Alma2", "Chief Judge", "King Lamoni2"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3864",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:57",
    "question": "The chief judge declared unto those that had believed in the words of_____ that they must speedily repent, or the same judgments would come upon them.",
    "answer": "Korihor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3865",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:58",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people were all convinced of the_____ of Korihor.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["Wickedness", "Deceiving", "Evilness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3866",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma30:59",
    "question": "What was the name of the people that Korihor went about begging for food and was run upon and trodden down?",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3867",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma30:59",
    "question": "Korihor was able to live a long and normal life because he repented of his sins.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3868",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma30:60",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that we can see for ourselves that the devil will not support his_____ at the last day, but does speedily drag them down to hell.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3869",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:1",
    "question": "Who was leading the Zoramites to bow down to dumb idols?_____",
    "answer": "Zoram",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3870",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:2",
    "question": "Because of the iniquity of the Zoramites it caused great sorrow to Alma2.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3871",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:2",
    "question": "The Zoramites had not separated themselves from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3872",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:2",
    "question": "The_____ had separated themselves from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Zoramites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3873",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:3",
    "question": "The land where the Zoramites had gathered together was called_____.",
    "answer": "Antionum",
    "options": ["Jershon", "Manti", "Antionum"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3874",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:4",
    "question": "The Nephites were concerned greatly because they thought that the Zoramites would enter a correspondence with the_____ which would cause a great loss to them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3875",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:15",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that the word of God has more power on the effect of the mind of the people than the sword.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3876",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:5",
    "question": "According to Mormon; which has more power on the effect of the mind of the people-the sword or the word of God?",
    "answer": "word",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3877",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:7",
    "question": "Alma2 had three sons; but only took two of them to preach the word of God to the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3878",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:7",
    "question": "What is the name of the eldest son of Alma2 the Younger?",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3879",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:8",
    "question": "Because the_____ were dissenters from the Nephites; therefore they had had the word of God preached unto them.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3880",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:9",
    "question": "The Zoramites would not observe to keep the commandments of God, and his statutes, according to the Law of_____.",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3881",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:10",
    "question": "The Zoramites would not observe the performances of the church; to continue to pray daily in order that they might not enter into temptation.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3882",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:11",
    "question": "Mormon writes that one of the best ways to ward off the temptations of the devil is to pray and be in supplication to God daily.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3883",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:11",
    "question": "By doing the things which they were doing; the Zoramites were perverting the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3884",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:11",
    "question": "By not doing what they were supposed to do according to the church; the_____ were perverting the ways of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3885",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:12",
    "question": "To the astonishment of Alma2 and his brethren, the Zoramites had built_____, and they would gather themselves together on one day of the week; which they called the day of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Synagogues",
    "options": ["Synagogues", "Houses", "Chapels"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3886",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:12",
    "question": "The manner in which the Zoramites worshipped the Lord was not new to Alma2 and his brethren.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3887",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:13",
    "question": "The Zoramites had a place built up in the center of their synagogue, a place for standing, which was high above the head and it would only allow one person at a time to worship.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3888",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:15",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that God was a holy God and a spirit and that God would be a spirit forever.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3889",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:16",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that the Nephites believed in traditions which were handed down by the childishness of their fathers.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3890",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:16",
    "question": "What tribe of people believed that they were elected to be the chosen children of God?",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Nephites", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3891",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:16",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that they were elected to be the_____ children of God.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["Chosen", "Holy", "Preferred"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3892",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:16",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that God had made it known unto them that there would be no_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["Death", "Christ", "Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3893",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:17",
    "question": "The Zoramites believed that God was the same yesterday, today and_____; and had elected them to be saved.",
    "answer": "Forever",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3894",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:19",
    "question": "When Alma2 and his brethren and his sons had heard the prayers of the Zoramites; they were astonished beyond measure.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3895",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:20",
    "question": "Every Zoramites that went up to pray on the stand did not offer the same prayer.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3896",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:21",
    "question": "Another name for the holy stand in which the Zoramites offered their prayers is called_____.",
    "answer": "Rameumptom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3897",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:21",
    "question": "The word “Rameumptom” only appears how many times in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3898",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:21",
    "question": "The word “Rameumpton” only appears once in the Book of Mormon.  Name the book in which it appears.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3899",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:23",
    "question": "After the Zoramites finished offering the self-same prayer unto God, they returned to their homes, never speaking of their God again until they had assembled themselves together again.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3900",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:23",
    "question": "After the Zoramites finished offerings their prayers unto God; they would return home and talked to each other about speaking of God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3901",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:24",
    "question": "When Alma2 saw how the_____ offered their prayers he was sadden because he saw that they were a wicked and a perverse people.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3902",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:24",
    "question": "Alma2 also saw that the Zoramites hearts were set upon_____, and upon silver, and upon all manner of f1ne goods.",
    "answer": "Gold",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3903",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:25",
    "question": "Alma2 also saw the Zoramites_____ were lifted up unto great boasting of their pride.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Heads", "Hearts", "Voices"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3904",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:26",
    "question": "Alma2 wondered how long the Lord would suffer that he and his servants would dwell below in the flesh, to behold such gross wickedness among the children of men.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3905",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:28",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Zoramites were puffed up with their costly apparel, and their ringlets, and their bracelets, and their ornaments of_____.",
    "answer": "Gold",
    "options": ["Silver", "Platinum", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3906",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:29",
    "question": "The Zoramites said that God had made it known to them that there shall be no_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["Sabbath Day", "Christ", "Evil"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3907",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:30",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the Lord to give him_____ that he may be able to bear his infirmities because of the wickedness of the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "Strength",
    "options": ["Patience", "Longsuffering", "Strength"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3908",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:31",
    "question": "Alma2’s heart was exceedingly sorrowful because of the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3909",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:31",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted strength from the Lord so that he could suffer with patience the afflictions which would come upon him because of the iniquity of the_____.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3910",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:32",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Lord to comfort his_____ and give him success; and also those of his fellow laborers who were with him.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3911",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:34",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the Lord to grant unto them that they might have success in bringing the Zoramites again unto_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3912",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:35",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell the Lord that the souls of the Zoramites were precious and that they were also their brethren.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3913",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 finished with his prayer and clapped his_____ upon all of them who were with him. And behold, they were filled with the Holy Spirit.",
    "answer": "Hands",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3914",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma31:37",
    "question": "After Alma2 finished with his prayer and clapped his hands; he and his brethren separated themselves one from another, taking no thought for themselves’ what they should eat, drink, or put on.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3915",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:38",
    "question": "Who provided for Alma2 and his brethren that they would not get hungry or thirst?",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3916",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:38",
    "question": "The Lord also gave Alma2 and his brethren strength that they should suffer no manner of_____.",
    "answer": "Afflictions",
    "options": ["Afflictions", "Sickness", "Death"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3917",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma31:38",
    "question": "The Lord granted unto Alma2 all that he had asked for because he had prayed in_____.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Private", "Faith", "Church"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3918",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:1",
    "question": "Alma2 and his brethren preached to the Zoramites in their synagogues, and in their houses, and in their streets.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3919",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:2",
    "question": "When Alma2 and his brother went among the Zoramites to preach the word of God; they had success in what class of people?",
    "answer": "Poor",
    "options": ["Rich", "Middle Income", "Poor"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3920",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:2",
    "question": "The poor class of people; were cast out of the synagogues because of the_____ of their apparel.",
    "answer": "Coarseness",
    "options": ["Costl1ness", "Ugl1ness", "Coarseness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3921",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:3",
    "question": "The poor class of people; were permitted to enter into the synagogues to worship God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3922",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:3",
    "question": "The poor class of people; were esteemed as filthy and dross and they were poor as to the things of the_____.",
    "answer": "World",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3923",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:3",
    "question": "The poor class of people; were also poor in heart.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3924",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:4",
    "question": "What is the name of the hill where Alma2 was teaching and speaking to the poor class of people of the Zoramites?",
    "answer": "Onidah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3925",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:5",
    "question": "The poor class of the Zoramites; were despised of all men but more especially by the_____.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["Teachers", "Priests", "Elders"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3926",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:5",
    "question": "The poor class of the people of the Zoramites had labored abundantly to build the_____ with their own hands.",
    "answer": "Synagogues",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3927",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:5",
    "question": "One of the Zoramites who was foremost among the crowd of people asked Alma2 where they should go to worship the word of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3928",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:6",
    "question": "Alma2 beheld with great_____ because he knew that the people were truly humbled because of their afflictions.",
    "answer": "Joy",
    "options": ["Joy", "Sorrow", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3929",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:6,7",
    "question": "Alma2 stretched forth his hand and blessed those who were truly penitent among the crowd.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3930",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:9",
    "question": "The poor class of the Zoramites said that they could not worship God because they had been cast out of their_____.",
    "answer": "Synagogues",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3931",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:10",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the Zoramites if they thought that they could only worship God in their synagogues.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3932",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:12",
    "question": "Alma2 thought that it was well that the poor class of people had been cast out of their synagogues because it made them_____.",
    "answer": "Humble",
    "options": ["Nicer", "Humble", "Poorer"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3933",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said that it was necessary for the poor class of people to learn wisdom; and that they are brought to a lowl1ness of heart because it made them humble.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3934",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:12",
    "question": "The poor class of the Zoramites; were despised because of their exceeding_____.",
    "answer": "Poverty",
    "options": ["Poverty", "Number", "Dirt1ness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3935",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told the poor class of the Zoramites that they were blessed because they were compelled to be_____.",
    "answer": "Humble",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3936",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said that those who truly humble themselves and repent of their sins, and_____ to the end, the same shall be blessed.",
    "answer": "Endure",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3937",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:16",
    "question": "Blessed are they who_____ themselves without being compelled to be humble.",
    "answer": "Humble",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3938",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:16",
    "question": "Blessed is he who believes in the word of God, and is_____ without stubbornness of heart.",
    "answer": "Baptized",
    "options": ["Truly", "Baptized", "Willingly"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3939",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:17",
    "question": "Alma2 says that there are many who say:  If you will show unto us a sign from heaven, then we shall know of a surety; then we shall believe.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3940",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:18",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if we need to be shown a sign in order to believe, we have true faith.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3941",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said that_____ is not to have a perfect knowledge of things.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3942",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:21",
    "question": "If we have faith we hope for things which are not seen, which are_____.",
    "answer": "True",
    "options": ["True", "False", "Unreal"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3943",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:22",
    "question": "Alma2 said that we should remember that_____ is merciful unto all who believe on his name; therefore he desires in the first place, that we should believe even on his word.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3944",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:23",
    "question": "By whom does the Lord impart his words to give unto men and women also?",
    "answer": "Angels",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3945",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:23",
    "question": "Alma2 says that_____ children do have words given unto them many times which confound the wise and learned.",
    "answer": "Little",
    "options": ["Many", "Big", "Little"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3946",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:24",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that he did not mean to judge them only according to that which is_____.",
    "answer": "True",
    "options": ["Right", "True", "Righteous"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3947",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:25",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that he truly believed that there were some among them who were really humbled and not compelled to be made to be so.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3948",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites to awake and arouse their faculties, even to an experiment upon his_____.",
    "answer": "Words",
    "options": ["Teachings", "Words", "Neither A Or B"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3949",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Zoramites to compare his word unto a_____.",
    "answer": "Seed",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3950",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted the Zoramites to plant a true or good seed unto their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3951",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "If the seed that we plant unto our hearts is a good seed and we do not resist the Spirit of the Lord, it will begin to swell within our breasts.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3952",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "If the seed that we have planted in our hearts is a good seed; we must say that it is a good seed because it is beginning to enlarge our souls.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3953",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:28",
    "question": "A good seed will begin to enlighten our understanding, and will be delicious unto us.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3954",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:31",
    "question": "Alma2 said that every good seed will bring forth unto its own_____.",
    "answer": "Likeness",
    "options": ["Tree", "Fruit", "Likeness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3955",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:32",
    "question": "Alma2 said if a seed grows it is good, but if it does not grow, behold it is not good, therefore it is_____ away.",
    "answer": "Cast",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3956",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:33",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if we try his experiment and plant the seed, and it swells and sprouts and begins to grow, we must know that the seed is good.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3957",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:34",
    "question": "Alma2 tells us that our knowledge is perfect of the seed only but that our_____ is dormant.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3958",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:35",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that whatsoever is light is_____, because it is discernible, therefore we must know that it is good.",
    "answer": "Good",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3959",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:37",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that in order for the seed to get roots and grow up into a tree and bring forth fruit we must nourish it with great care that it may grow up and bring forth fruit unto us.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3960",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:38",
    "question": "Alma2 said if we neglect the tree and take no thought for its nourishment it will not get any root and when the heat of the_____ comes and scorches it; it will wither away and we will pluck it up and cast it out.",
    "answer": "Sun",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3961",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:39",
    "question": "Alma2 tells us that if the seed that we plant does not grow up and bear fruit; it is not because the seed was no good but it was because are ground was barren, therefore we cannot have the fruit thereof.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3962",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:40",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that if we do not nourish the word, looking forward with an eye of faith to the fruit thereof, we can never pluck of the fruit of the tree of_____.",
    "answer": "Life",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3963",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:41",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that if we nourish the word, nourish the tree as it begins to grow by our faith with great diligence and patience, looking forward to the fruit thereof, it shall take root; springing up unto everlasting life.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3964",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma32:42",
    "question": "Alma2 tells us that because of our diligence and our faith and our patience with the word in nourishing it, we shall pluck the fruit thereof.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3965",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma32:42",
    "question": "The fruit of the Tree of Life is most precious, which is sweet above all that is_____.",
    "answer": "Sweet",
    "options": ["Good", "Sweet", "Rich"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3966",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:42",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the fruit of the tree of everlasting life is white above all that is_____ and pure above all that is pure.  And we shall feast upon this fruit even until we are filled.",
    "answer": "White",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3967",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:42",
    "question": "Alma2 writes that we shall never_____ neither shall we never thirst if we partake of the tree of everlasting life.",
    "answer": "Hunger",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3968",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma32:43",
    "question": "Alma2 said that after we nourish the word/tree we shall reap the rewards of our faith, and our_____, and patience, and long-suffering, waiting for the tree to bring forth fruit unto us.",
    "answer": "Diligence",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3969",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:1",
    "question": "After Alma2 finished speaking to the Zoramites they desired to know whether they should believe in one_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["God", "Person", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3970",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:1",
    "question": "The Zoramites desired and asked Alma2 how they might obtain this fruit of which he had spoken, or how they should plant the seed, or the word of which he had spoken.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3971",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that the seed or word of which he had spoken of must be planted in their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Heads", "Chest", "Hearts"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3972",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:1",
    "question": "The Zoramites did not desire to know in what manner they should begin to exercise their faith.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3973",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:2",
    "question": "The Zoramites told Alma2 that they could not worship their God because they had been cast out of their_____.",
    "answer": "Synagogues",
    "options": ["Synagogues", "Houses", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3974",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that they should search the_____ to find out where and how they could worship their God.",
    "answer": "Scriptures",
    "options": ["Book Of Mormon", "Scriptures", "Pearl Of Great Price"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3975",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that if they had searched the scriptures concerning where and how they could worship their God they did not understand them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3976",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:3",
    "question": "What prophet of old times did Alma2 refer to and told the Zoramites had spoken concerning prayer or worship?",
    "answer": "Zenos",
    "options": ["Moses", "Nephi", "Zenos"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3977",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:4",
    "question": "What prophet of old times did Alma2 say had prayed in the wilderness and the Lord had heard his prayer.",
    "answer": "Zenos",
    "options": ["Zenos", "Zenock", "Zeus"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3978",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:5",
    "question": "Alma2 said the prophet_____ of old times had cried unto the Lord in his field and the Lord had heard his prayer?",
    "answer": "Zenos",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3979",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:6",
    "question": "When Zenos the prophet of old times had cried unto the Lord in his_____ the Lord did hear his prayer.",
    "answer": "House",
    "options": ["Barn", "Shed", "House"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3980",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:7",
    "question": "What particular place in his house did the prophet Zenos pray unto the Lord and he did hear his prayer?",
    "answer": "Closet",
    "options": ["Bathroom", "Closet", "Living Room"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3981",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:8",
    "question": "The Lord is merciful unto us when we cry unto him to be heard of him and not of men, and he will hear our prayers.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3982",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord had not been merciful unto him when he had prayed unto him in the midst of his congregations.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3983",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord had also heard his prayers when he had been cast out and despised by his_____.",
    "answer": "Enemies",
    "options": ["People", "Enemies", "Friends"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3984",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:10",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord was angry with his enemies and did visit them in his anger with speedy destruction.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3985",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord had heard his prayers because of his afflictions and sincerity.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3986",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:11",
    "question": "Alma2 prayed unto the Lord in all his afflictions because in the Lord was his joy; and he had turned his judgments away from him, because of_____.",
    "answer": "Jesus Christ",
    "options": ["Sincerity Of His Prayers", "Constant Praying", "Jesus Christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3987",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:12",
    "question": "Alma2 asked the Zoramites if they believed in the scriptures which had been written by the prophets of old times.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3988",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:13",
    "question": "What prophet of old times did Alma2 tell the Zoramites had written and said that the Lord had turned away his judgments because of his beloved son Jesus Christ?_____",
    "answer": "Zenos",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3989",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told the_____ if they had read the scriptures, how was it possible that could they disbelieve in the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3990",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that the prophet Zenos and also the prophet_____ of old times had spoken of the things concerning the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Zenock",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Moses", "Zenock"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3991",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that the Lord was _____ with them because they could not understand his mercies which he had bestowed upon them because of his son Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Angry",
    "options": ["Upset", "Angry", "Mad"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3993",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:18",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that Zenos and Zenock were the only prophets that had spoken and testified of the things concerning the Son of God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3994",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:19",
    "question": "What prophet did Alma2 say raised a type of Jesus Christ in the wilderness, that whosoever would look upon it might live?",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3995",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:19",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Moses raised a type of Jesus Christ in the wilderness and many of them did look and lived",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3996",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 said that a lot of the people understood the meaning of the type of Jesus Christ that Moses had raised up in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3997",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that many of the Israelites did not understand the type of Jesus Christ that_____ had raised up because the hardness of their hearts.",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3998",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 said that many of the Israelites would not look upon the type of Jesus Christ Moses had raised up because they were_____.",
    "answer": "Harden",
    "options": ["Stuck Up", "Harden", "Sick"]
  },
  {
    "id": "3999",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told the_____that they were many who were so hardened that they would not look, therefore they perished.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4000",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites the reason they would not look was because they did not believe that it would_____ them.",
    "answer": "Heal",
    "options": ["Heal", "Save", "Cleanse"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4001",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:21",
    "question": "Alma2 desired that the Zoramites could be healed by merely casting about their eyes unto the_____ that they might be healed.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4002",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people to behold quickly their eyes unto the Son of God and not hardened their hearts and be slothful.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4003",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people that wo would come upon them in they would not cast their eyes unto the Son of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4004",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites the Son of God would come to redeem his people, and that he shall suffer and die and_____ for their sins.",
    "answer": "Atone",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4005",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the people the Son of God would also rise again from the dead, which shall bring to pass the_____, and that all men shall stand before him.",
    "answer": "Resurrection",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4006",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites the Lord would bring to pass the resurrection; that all men shall stand before him, to be judged at the last and judgment_____, according to their works.",
    "answer": "Day",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4007",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma33:23",
    "question": "Alma2 desired that the Zoramites would plant the word in their hearts, and as it begins to swell that they would nourish if by their_____.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Belief", "Faith", "Sincerity"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4008",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told the Zoramites that he desired that God would grant unto them that their burdens might be heavy and awful.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4009",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma33:23",
    "question": "Alma2 desired that the Zoramites burdens may be light through the joy of the Son of_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4010",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma33:23",
    "question": "Alma2 desired the Zoramites would believe in the word of God and could do anything if they were willing.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4011",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:1",
    "question": "After Alma2 finished speaking to the Zoramites; he sat down on the ground and who arose and began to speak to them?",
    "answer": "Amulek",
    "options": ["King Noah", "King Limhi2", "Amulek"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4012",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:1",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that it was impossible that they should be ignorant of the things which have been spoken by Alma2 concerning the coming of Christ.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4013",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:2",
    "question": "Who did Amulek say was the taught by Alma2 and himself that would be the father of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4014",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:2",
    "question": "Amulek told the_____ that he knew the things concerning Christ were taught unto them bountifully before their dissension from among them.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4015",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:3",
    "question": "The Zoramites desired of_____, the beloved brother of Amulek; that he should make known unto them what they should do because of their afflictions.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4016",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:3",
    "question": "Amulek told the people that Alma2 had exhorted them to have faith and patience in their afflictions.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4017",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:4",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that they should have so much_____ as even to plant the word in their hearts, that they may try the experiment of its goodness.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Desire", "Faith", "Knowledge"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4018",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:5",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites he knew that the great question in their minds was whether the word be in the Son of God, or whether there shall be no_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4019",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:6",
    "question": "Amulek said who had proved unto the Zoramites in many instances, that the word is in Christ unto salvation?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4020",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:7",
    "question": "What three prophets of old times did Amulek say Alma2 had appealed unto; to prove to the Zoramites that the things concerning Christ were true?  Zenos, and Zenock, and_____.",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4021",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:8",
    "question": "Amulek did not testify to the Zoramites that the things he said concerning Jesus Christ were true.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4022",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:8",
    "question": "Amulek testified unto the Zoramites that he knew Jesus Christ would come among the children of men, to take upon him the transgressions of his people, and shall atone for the sins of the world.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4023",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:8",
    "question": "Amulek testified to the Zoramites that the Lord God himself had spoken of the things concerning Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4024",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:9",
    "question": "Amulek said it was expedient that an_____ should be made; for according to the great plan of the Eternal God.",
    "answer": "Atonement",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4025",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:9",
    "question": "Amulek said that mankind would unavoidably_____ if there was no atonement made by Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Perish",
    "options": ["Get Burned", "Be Sent To Hell", "Perish"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4026",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:10",
    "question": "Amulek said that there should be a great and_____ sacrifice; not a sacrifice of man, neither of beast, neither of any manner of fowl.",
    "answer": "Last",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4027",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:10",
    "question": "Amulek testified that there should be a great and last sacrifice; not a sacrifice of man, neither of beast, neither of any manner of fowl.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4028",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:10",
    "question": "Amulek said that it was expedient that the sacrifice of Jesus Christ must be an infinite and_____ sacrifice.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4029",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:11",
    "question": "Amulek said that a man could sacrifice his own blood which shall atone for the sins of another.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4030",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:13",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that there should be a stop to the shedding of blood; then shall the Law of_____ be fulfilled.",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4031",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:13",
    "question": "After the great and last sacrifice; Amulek said that every jot and _____, and none shall have passed away.",
    "answer": "Tittle",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4032",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:14",
    "question": "Amulek said that the meaning of the law was to point to the great and last sacrifice.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4033",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:14",
    "question": "Amulek said that the great and last sacrifice will be the Son of_____, infinite and eternal.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4034",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:15",
    "question": "The intent of this last sacrifice is to bring about the bowels of mercy which overpowers justice, and brings about means unto men that they may have faith unto repentance.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4035",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:16",
    "question": "And_____ can satisfy the demands of justice, and encircles them in the arms of safety.",
    "answer": "Mercy",
    "options": ["Mercy", "Repentance", "Money"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4036",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:16",
    "question": "Amulek said that those who exercise no faith unto repentance are exposed to the whole law of the demands of justice.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4037",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:16",
    "question": "The great and eternal plan of redemption is brought about unto those that have no faith unto repentance.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4038",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:17",
    "question": "Amulek wished that his brethren would begin to exercise their faith unto_____.",
    "answer": "Repentance",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4039",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:17",
    "question": "Amulek wanted his brethren to begin to call upon Jesus Christ, that he would have_____ upon them.",
    "answer": "Mercy",
    "options": ["Pity", "Mercy", "Compassion"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4042",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:21",
    "question": "Amulek told his brethren to cry unto the Lord how many times during the day.",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4043",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:22",
    "question": "Amulek said that his brethren should not cry unto the Lord against the power of their enemies.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4044",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:23",
    "question": "Who did Amulek say is “an enemy to all righteousness”?",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4045",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:24",
    "question": "Amulek did not tell his brethren to cry unto the Lord over the crops of their fields, that they may prosper in them.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4046",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:26",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites to pour out their souls in their_____, their secret places, and in their wilderness.",
    "answer": "Closets",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4047",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:27",
    "question": "We should let our hearts be full, and drawn out in prayer unto the Lord continually for our welfare, and also for the welfare of those who are_____ us.",
    "answer": "Around",
    "options": ["Behind", "Around", "Beneath"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4048",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:28",
    "question": "After we have prayed continually for the welfare of others it is okay to turn away the needy and the naked.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4049",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:28",
    "question": "Amulek said that we should visit the sick and_____, and impart of our substance, if we have, to those who stand in need of it.",
    "answer": "Afflicted",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4050",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:28",
    "question": "Amulek said that if we do not do any of these things (visit the sick/help the needy/impart of our substance) our prayers are in vain, and avails us nothing, and we are hypocrites who deny the faith.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4051",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:28",
    "question": "Amulek said if we do not cry unto the Lord and do other good things; our_____ are in vain, and avails us nothing, and we are hypocrites who deny the faith.",
    "answer": "Prayers",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4052",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:29",
    "question": "If we are not charitable, Amulek said we are dross, which_____ do cast out, (it being of no worth) and is trodden under foot of men.",
    "answer": "Ref1ners",
    "options": ["Woodsmiths", "Metallurgist", "Ref1ners"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4053",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:30",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that they had received many witnesses, seeing that the holy_____ testify of these things.",
    "answer": "Scriptures",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4054",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:30",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that after they had received so many witnesses, they should come forth and bring fruit unto_____.",
    "answer": "Repentance",
    "options": ["Repentance", "Him", "Jesus Christ"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4055",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:31",
    "question": "Amulek wished that the_____ would come forth and harden not their hearts any longer.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4056",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:13",
    "question": "Amulek did not wish that the Zoramites would come forth and not harden their hearts any longer.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4057",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:31",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that tomorrow would be the time which would become the day of their salvation.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4058",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:31",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that if they harden not their_____, immediately shall the great plan or redemption would be brought about unto them.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4059",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:31",
    "question": "For behold, this_____ is the time for men to prepare to meet God.",
    "answer": "Life",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4060",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:32",
    "question": "Behold the day of this life is the day for men to perform their_____.",
    "answer": "Labors",
    "options": ["Jobs", "Acts Of Charity", "Labors"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4061",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:33",
    "question": "Amulek beseeched the Zoramites that they would not_____ the day of their repentance until the end.",
    "answer": "Procastinate",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4062",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:33",
    "question": "Amulek said that this day of life is given to us to prepare for_____.",
    "answer": "Life",
    "options": ["Charitable Work", "Life", "The Olympics"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4063",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:33",
    "question": "For behold, if we do not improve our time while in this_____, then comes the night of darkness.",
    "answer": "Life",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4064",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:33",
    "question": "According to Amulek, we can perform our labors in the night of darkness.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4065",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:34",
    "question": "Amulek said that at the end of this life we cannot say, that I will repent, that I will return to my_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4066",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:34",
    "question": "The same_____ which does possess our bodies at the time that we go out of this life, that same spirit will have power to possess our bodies in the eternal world.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4067",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:34",
    "question": "Amulek said the same spirit which possesses our bodies at the time that we go out of this life, that same spirit will have the power to possess our bodies in the eternal world.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4068",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:35",
    "question": "Amulek said if we have procrastinated the day of our repentance even until death, behold, we have become subjected unto the spirit of the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4069",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:35",
    "question": "If the Spirit of the Lord has withdrawn from us, and has no place in us, the devil has all power over us.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4070",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:35",
    "question": "The final state of the wicked is when the devil has all power over them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4071",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:36",
    "question": "Amulek testified that the things he knew were true because the Lord has said that he cannot dwell in_____ temples.",
    "answer": "Unholy",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4072",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:36",
    "question": "Amulek said that the Spirit of the Lord can only dwell in_____ of the righteous.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Bodies", "Hearts", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4073",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:36",
    "question": "The Lord has said that the righteous shall sit down in his_____, to go out no more.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4074",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:36",
    "question": "Our garments are made_____ through the blood of the Lamb.",
    "answer": "White",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4075",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:37",
    "question": "Amulek said that we should remember his testimony, and that we should work on our salvation with fear before God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4076",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:37",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that it was all right if they denied the coming of Christ, as long as they had repented and gain a testimony of him.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4077",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:38",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that they should not contend any more against the_____ Ghost.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4078",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:38",
    "question": "Amulek told the Zoramites that they should receive the Holy Ghost, and take upon them the name of_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4079",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:38",
    "question": "Amulek testified that we should humble ourselves even to the dust, and worship_____, in whatsoever place that we may be in, in spirit and in truth.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4080",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:38",
    "question": "Amulek said that we should live in thanksgiving daily, for the many mercies and blessings which the Lord does bestow upon us.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4081",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma34:39",
    "question": "Amulek exhorts us that we should be watchful unto prayer continually, that we may not be led away by the temptation of the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4082",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:39",
    "question": "Amulek exhorts us pray continually, that the devil may not overpower us and that we may not become his_____ at the last day.",
    "answer": "Subjects",
    "options": ["People", "Subjects", "Beings"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4083",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:39",
    "question": "Amulek testified that if we become the subjects of the Devil, he will reward us with good things at the last day.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4084",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma34:40",
    "question": "Amulek exhorted his brethren to have patience and should bear all manner of their afflictions; that they would not revile against those who had cast them out of their sanctuaries.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4085",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:40",
    "question": "The people that Amulek testified to were cast out of their sanctuaries because of their exceeding_____.",
    "answer": "Poverty",
    "options": ["Smell", "Riches", "Poverty"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4086",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma34:41",
    "question": "Amulek testified to the Zoramites to have patience and bear their afflictions with a firm_____ that they shall one day rest from all of their afflictions.",
    "answer": "Hope",
    "options": ["Testimony", "Hope", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4087",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma35:1",
    "question": "After Amulek had finished testifying to the Zoramites, they withdrew themselves from the multitude and came over into the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Jershon",
    "options": ["Waters Of Mormon", "Zarahemla", "Jershon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4088",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:2",
    "question": "The more part of the Zoramites consulted together concerning the words which had preached unto them, and were angry.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4089",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:3",
    "question": "The Zoramites were angry with the words that had been preached unto them because it did destroy their craft, and they would not hearken unto the words.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4090",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:6",
    "question": "The Zoramites consulted one with another and found out the minds of all the people, and those that were in favor of the words which had been spoken by_____ and his brethren were cast out.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4091",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 and his brethren did minister to those that were cast out.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4092",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:8",
    "question": "The people of the Zoramites did not get angry with the people of Ammon who were in Jershon, because of their beliefs.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4093",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:8",
    "question": "During the time that Alma2 and Amulek and their brethren testified of the word or God, the chief ruler of the Zoramites was a very wicked man.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4094",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:9",
    "question": "The people of Ammon were afraid of the chief ruler of the _____ because he breathed out many threatenings against them.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4095",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:9",
    "question": "The poor people of the Zoramite’s who had been cast out, were nourished and clothed and given lands unto their inheritance by what people?",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4096",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:9",
    "question": "The people of Ammon did not administer to the wants of the people of the Zoramites who had been cast out.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4097",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:10",
    "question": "The Zoramites became angry with the people of Ammon because of the things they were doing for the poor and began to stir up what people to also be angry with them?",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4098",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:11",
    "question": "And the Zoramites and the Lamanites began to make preparations for war against the people of_____, and also against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4099",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma35:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Ammon departed out of the land of Jershon, and came over into the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Melek",
    "options": ["Melek", "Mormon", "Zarahemla"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4100",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma35:14",
    "question": "And Alma2, and Ammon, and their brethren, and also the two sons of Alma returned to the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["Melek", "Mormon", "Zarahemla"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4101",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:14",
    "question": "Alma2, Ammon, and his brethren; became_____ in the hands of God of bringing many of the Zoramites unto repentance.",
    "answer": "Instruments",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4102",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:15",
    "question": "Alma2 was not sadden or grieved because of the iniquity of his people.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4103",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:15",
    "question": "Alma2 and his brethren declared the word of God unto all the people in every city.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4104",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:15",
    "question": "Alma2 began to see that the hearts of the people began to wax hard, and that they began to be offended because of the strictness of the_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Word",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4105",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma35:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____ caused his sons should be gathered together, that he might give unto them every one his charge, separately.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4106",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:16",
    "question": "Alma2 gave charge to each of his sons concerning the things pertaining unto righteousness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4107",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma35:16",
    "question": "The charge that Alma2 gave to each of his sons pertaining to righteousness, have been recorded; and we have a copy of them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4108",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:1,37:1,38:1,39:1-42:31",
    "question": "The charge that Alma2 gave to each of his sons pertaining to righteousness; have been recorded in the Book of Jacob.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4109",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma31:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to give ear to his words; that inasmuch as he shall keep the commandments of_____ he shall prosper in the land.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4110",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:2",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted Helaman to remember the captivity of their fathers.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4111",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that no one else but God could deliver their fathers from captivity and _____.",
    "answer": "Bondage",
    "options": ["Prison", "Bondage", "Jails"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4112",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:3",
    "question": "Helaman was in his mid 30’s when Alma2 gave his commandments to him.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4113",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:3",
    "question": "Alma2 testified to Helaman that he knew that whosoever shall put their trust in God shall be supported in their_____.",
    "answer": "Trials",
    "options": ["Trials", "Life", "Homes"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4114",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:3",
    "question": "If we put are trust in God; we will be supported by him in our trials, troubles, and in our afflictions.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4115",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:3",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto _____ that if we must put our trust in God we shall be lifted up at the last day.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4116",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:4",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto Helaman that he knew the things he knew because of his spiritual mind, not of the carnal mind but, of_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4117",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he knew the things of God because a holy_____ had made these things known to him.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["Man", "Ghost", "Angel"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4118",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:5",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto Helaman that he was unworthy to receive the things of God told to him by an angel.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4119",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:6",
    "question": "Seeking to destroy the church of God; Alma2 went with the_____ of Mosiah.",
    "answer": "Sons",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4120",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:6",
    "question": "Who or what stopped Alma2 and the sons of Mosiah from destroying the church of God?",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4121",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:7",
    "question": "The holy angel spoke to Alma2 and the sons of Mosiah with a voice of_____, and the whole earth did tremble beneath their feet.",
    "answer": "Thunder",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4122",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:7",
    "question": "Alma2 and the sons of Mosiah fell to the earth because the fear of the Lord came upon them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4123",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:8",
    "question": "Who did the angel of the Lord tell to arise and stand up first, Alma2 or the sons of Mosiah?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4124",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:8",
    "question": "Alma2 did not arise and stand up as he was commanded by the angel of the Lord.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4125",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:9",
    "question": "The angel of the Lord told Alma2 that he would be destroyed if he continued to destroy the church of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4126",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 fell to the earth for how many days and how many nights?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4127",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:10",
    "question": "When_____ fell to the earth he could not open his mouth and could not use his limbs.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4128",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:10",
    "question": "When Alma2 fell to the earth he could not open his mouth and could not use his limbs.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4129",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:11",
    "question": "Alma2 heard all the words of the Lord which were spoken to him by his holy angel.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4130",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:11",
    "question": "Immediately upon hearing the words of the holy angel; Alma2 was struck with such great fear and amazement, that he fell to the_____ and did not hear anymore of his words.",
    "options": ["Ground", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4131",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:12",
    "question": "Alma2’s was racked with eternal_____, for his soul was harrowed up to the greatest degree and racked with all his sins.",
    "answer": "Torment",
    "options": ["Torment", "Punishment", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4132",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he could not remember all his sins and iniquities.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4133",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that not only could he remember all his sins and iniquities for which he was tormented with the pains of_____.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4134",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:13",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto Helaman that he could not understand why he was being punished because he had not rebelled against God and had kept his holy commandments.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4135",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:14",
    "question": "Alma2 testified unto Helaman that he had led many of the Lord’s_____ away unto destruction.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4136",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that so great had been his iniquities, that the very thought of coming into the presence of God did rack his soul with 1nexpressible_____.",
    "answer": "Horror",
    "options": ["Fear", "Horror", "Gladness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4137",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:15",
    "question": "Alma2 thought that he could be banished and become extinct both_____ and body for the things he had done to by leading the children of the Lord away from him.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4138",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:15",
    "question": "Alma2 wished that he would not be brought to stand in the presence of God, to be judged of his deeds.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4139",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:16",
    "question": "For how many days and nights was Alma2’s soul racked with the pains of a damned soul?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4140",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 was racked with torment, while he was harrowed up by the memory of his many_____.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["Deeds", "Sins", "Thoughts"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4141",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:17",
    "question": "Alma2 remembered that his father had prophesied to the people concerning the coming of Jesus Christ, a_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Son",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4142",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:17",
    "question": "Alma2 remembered that his father had prophesied that Jesus Christ would come; to_____ for the sins of the world.",
    "answer": "Atone",
    "options": ["Atone", "Be Punished", "Bleed"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4143",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:18",
    "question": "Alma2 cried within his heart: O Jesus, the Son of God, have mercy on me.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4144",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:18",
    "question": "Alma2 was caught in his mind in the gall of bitterness and was encircled about by the everlasting chains of_____.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4146",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:20",
    "question": "Alma2 was filled with joy and with a marvelous light that his joy was the same as filled with the joy as exceeding as was his pain.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4147",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:20",
    "question": "Alma2 told _____ that there could be nothing so exquisite and so bitter as were his pains.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4148",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that on the other hand, there could be nothing so exquisite and sweet as was his joy.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4149",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:22",
    "question": "Alma2 thought that he saw God sitting upon his throne as did Lehi in his vision.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4150",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:22",
    "question": "Alma2 saw God sitting upon his throne, surrounded with numberless concourses of_____, in singing and praising their God.",
    "answer": "Angels",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4151",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:22",
    "question": "Alma2’s soul did not want to be where God and his angels were.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4152",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:23",
    "question": "Alma2’s limbs did receive their strength again, and he stood on his feet, and did manifest unto the people that he had been born of_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4153",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:24",
    "question": "From the time that Alma2 was born again of God; he had not labored without ceasing, that he might brings souls unto repentance",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4154",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:24",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted his people to taste of the exceeding_____ of which he tasted; that they might also be filled with the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Joy",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4155",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:25",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the Lord does give him exceeding great joy in the fruit of his_____.",
    "answer": "Labors",
    "options": ["Loins", "Fields", "Labors"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4156",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said that many people had also been born of God and have tasted the same as he has tasted.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4157",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that many people have been born of God and have seen eye to_____ as he had seen.",
    "answer": "Eye",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4158",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:26",
    "question": "The knowledge that Alma2 had of God was of_____; and not of man.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4159",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:27",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God had not supported him when he was under trials and troubles of every kind.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4160",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that God had delivered him from_____, and from bonds, and from death.",
    "answer": "Prison",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4162",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he knew that God would raise him up at the_____ day, to dwell in his glory.",
    "answer": "Last",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4163",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he would not always praise God for delivering him from his trials and troubles.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4164",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he knew that God had brought their fathers out of_____, and that he had swallowed up the Egyptians in the Red Sea.",
    "answer": "Egypt",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4165",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "What is the name of the body of water that the Lord swallowed up the Egyptians in?",
    "answer": "Red",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4166",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma36:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he knew the Lord had delivered their fathers from bondage and_____ from time to time.",
    "answer": "Captivity",
    "options": ["Prison", "Captivity", "Jail"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4167",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:29",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God had brought their fathers out of the land of_____; by his everlasting power.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4168",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to retain in his memory and remembrance the captivity of their fathers even as he has done.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4169",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:30",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted Helaman to know that inasmuch as he would keep the commandments of God; he would prosper in the land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4170",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma36:30",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted Helaman to know that inasmuch as he would not keep the_____ of God; he would be cut off from his presence.",
    "answer": "Commandments",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4171",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma36:30",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that all things come to pass according to the word of God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4172",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:1",
    "question": "What son did Alma2 entrust with the records of the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4173",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:2",
    "question": "Alma2 did not command Helaman to keep a record of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4174",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to keep a record of the Nephites on the Plates of_____, and keep all those things sacred, as he had done.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4175",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the Nephite records are kept for a_____ purpose.",
    "answer": "Wise",
    "options": ["Wise", "Not So Wise", "Important"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4176",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the plates of what metal contain all the engravings which have the records of the Holy Scriptures upon them?",
    "answer": "Brass",
    "options": ["Copper", "Brass", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4177",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the plates of brass contain the genealogy of their forefathers, even from the beginning",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4178",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that it had been prophesied by their fathers that a record should be kept and handed down from one_____ to another.",
    "answer": "Generation",
    "options": ["People", "Generation", "Tribe"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4179",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say would preserve the records of the Nephites?",
    "answer": ["lord", "god"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4180",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that their records would go forth to every nation, kindred, _____, and people.",
    "answer": "Tongue",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4181",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the records would go forth to the world and that every people would know the mysteries conta1ned upon them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4182",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:5",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Plates of Nephi would retain their_____; and also all the plates which contain Holy Scripture.",
    "answer": "Brightness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4183",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that by_____ and simple things are great things brought to pass.",
    "answer": "Small",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4184",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that by small and simple things are great things brought to pass; and small means in many instances_____ the wise.",
    "answer": "Confoud",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4185",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:7",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord God does work by small means to bring about his great and_____ purposes.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["Small", "Eternal", "Unimportant"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4186",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that by very small means the Lord does confound the wise and brings about the salvation of many_____.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["Bodies", "Souls", "People"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4187",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is wisdom in God that many things should be preserved.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4188",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the records have enlarged the memory of the people and convinced them of the error of their ways, and brought them to the knowledge of____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4189",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the records have brought many people of the error of their ways and to the knowledge of God; unto the salvation of many souls.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4190",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if it was not for the things in the records, _____ he and his brethren could not convince so many thousands of the Lamanites of the error of their traditions.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4191",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the records and their words brought many_____ unto repentance and brought them to the knowledge of the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4192",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the records and their words had not brought the Lamanites to rejoice in Jesus Christ their redeemer.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4193",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that many of their brethren, the Nephites, were beginning to harden their hearts in sin and iniquities.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4194",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the records were preserved for a_____ purpose, which purpose is known unto God.",
    "answer": "Wise",
    "options": ["Good", "Wise", "Unknown"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4195",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord does counsel in wisdom over all his works, and his paths are unknown.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4196",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lords paths are straight and his course is one_____ round.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4197",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:12",
    "question": "What prophet of the Lord is the first person to say that the Lord’s course is “one eternal round”?_____-Alma2/Alma the",
    "answer": "Younger",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4198",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:13",
    "question": "Alma2 reminded Helaman to remember how strict the commandments of God are.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4199",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:14",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted_____ to remember that God had entrusted him with the sacred records, which he has kept sacred, and also which he will keep and preserve them for a wise purpose.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4200",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said one of the purposes of the sacred records was so that God could show forth his power unto future generations.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4201",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman by the_____ prophecy, that if he transgressed the commandments of God, the things which are sacred would be taken away from him by the power of God.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Spirit", "Gift", "Tongue"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4202",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman by the spirit of prophecy, that if he transgressed the commandments of God, he would be delivered up unto Satan.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4203",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he must not appeal unto the Lord for all things whatsoever he must do with the sacred records.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4204",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said to Helaman that if he kept the commandments of God concerning the sacred records, no power on earth or_____ could take them away from him.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4205",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said that God is powerful to the fulfilling of all his words.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4206",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:17",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that God would fulfil all his_____ which he shall make unto him.",
    "answer": "Promises",
    "options": ["Deeds", "Promises", "Tasks"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4207",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:17",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that God had fulfilled all his promises which he had made unto their fathers.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4208",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:19",
    "question": "Alma2 said one of the purposes of the sacred records had been fulfilled, even to the restoration of many thousands of the_____ to the knowledge of the truth of the word of God.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4209",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:19",
    "question": "Alma2 said God would show forth his power to future generations of the Lamanites; therefore the sacred records will be preserved.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4210",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:20",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded_____ to be diligent in fulfilling all his words, and to be diligent in keeping the commandments of God as they are written.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4211",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "Alma2 did not speak unto Helaman concerning the twenty-four plates that were in his possession.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4212",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "The twenty-four plates contain mysteries and works of darkness, or the_____ works of those people who had been destroyed.",
    "answer": "Secret",
    "options": ["Good", "Bad", "Secret"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4213",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said the twenty-four plates mysteries would be manifested unto his people, the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4214",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "The twenty-four plates contain the murders, and robbings, and the plunderings, and all the wickedness and abominations, of the people the Lord had destroyed.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4215",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:21,Mos8:8,Ether1:1",
    "question": "The twenty-four plates contain the record of the Jaredites which the Lord had destroyed because of their wickedness and abominations.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4216",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:21",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded_____ to preserve the interpreters.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4217",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:22",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Lord saw that his people began to work in_____, and work secret murders and abominations.",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "options": ["Daylight", "Darkness", "Sundays"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4218",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the Lord had said the people needed to repent are they would be destroyed from the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["Moon", "Americas", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4219",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the Lord would prepare unto his servant Gazelem, a stone, which shall sh1ne forth in darkness unto light.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4221",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said the stone would show those that serve the Lord the secret works of their brethren; their works of_____, and their wickedness and abominations.",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4222",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:24",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the interpreters were prepared that the word of God might be fulfilled.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4224",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:25",
    "question": "The Lord said the interpreters would bring to light all the secrets and abominations, unto every nation that shall hereafter possess the land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4226",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said the secret abominations of the Jaredites had been brought out of_____ and made known unto them.",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "options": ["Their Closets", "Obscurity", "Darkness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4227",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:27",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded Helaman to retain all the oaths, covenants, and agreements and all the signs and the wonders of the Jaredites from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4228",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that if the Nephites were to get a hold of the secret oaths and covenants of the Jaredites they would fall into darkness also and be_____.",
    "answer": "Destroyed",
    "options": ["Destroyed", "Rewarded", "Resurrected"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4229",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:28",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that there was not a curse upon the land; that destruction would not come upon all those workers of darkness.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4230",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:28",
    "question": "Alma2 said when the workers of darkness were fully_____, they would be destroyed by the power of God.",
    "answer": "Ripe",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4231",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:28",
    "question": "Alma2 desired that the Nephites would not be destroyed by the power of the Lord.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4232",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to keep the secrets plans of their oaths and their covenants of the Jaredites from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4233",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to only let the Nephites know of the wickedness and murders and the_____ of the Jaredites.",
    "answer": "Abominations",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4234",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to teach the Nephites to abhor such wickedness and murders and abominations of the Jaredites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4235",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:29",
    "question": "Helaman was to teach the_____ that the Jaredites were destroyed on account of their wickedness and abominations and their murders.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4236",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:30",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Jaredites had murdered all the_____ of the Lord who came among them to declare unto them concerning their iniquities.",
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4237",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:30",
    "question": "Alma2 never mentions that the blood of the prophets who had been murdered by the Jaredites; did not cry unto the Lord their God for vengeance.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4238",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:30",
    "question": "Alma2 said the judgments of_____ did come upon those workers of darkness and secret combinations.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4239",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:31",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the land was cursed forever and ever unto those workers of darkness and secret_____, even unto destruction, except they repent before they are fully ripe.",
    "answer": "Combinations",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4240",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:31,21-23,29",
    "question": "Alma2 never uses the word Jaredites to Helaman to refer to the people who have been destroyed because of their works of darkness and secret combinations to.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4241",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:32",
    "question": "Alma2 wanted Helaman to remember the words which he had spoken unto him; and not trust the secret plans unto the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4242",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:32",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to teach the Nephites an everlasting hatred against sin and_____.",
    "answer": "Iniquity",
    "options": ["Cleanl1ness", "Murders", "Iniquity"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4243",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:33",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to preach unto the Nephites repentance, and faith on the Lord Jesus_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4244",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:33",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to teach the Nephites to_____ themselves and to be meek and lowly in heart.",
    "answer": "Humble",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4245",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:33",
    "question": "Helaman was to teach the Nephites to withstand every temptation of the_____, with their faith on the Lord Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4246",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:34",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ to teach the Nephites to never be weary of good works, but to be meek and lowly in heart; for such shall find rest in their souls.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4247",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:35",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to remember to learn_____ in his youth and to learn to keep the commandments of God in his youth.",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "options": ["Knowledge", "Wisdom", "Everything"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4248",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:36",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to cry unto_____ for all of his support; and to let all his doings be unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4249",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:36",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to let his thoughts be directed unto the Lord; and to let his_____ of his heart be placed upon the Lord forever.",
    "answer": "Afflictions",
    "options": ["Afflictions", "Sorrows", "Pains"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4250",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to_____ with the Lord in all his doings and he would direct him in all things which are good.",
    "answer": "Counsel",
    "options": ["Wrestle", "Counsel", "Pray"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4251",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to counsel with the Lord when he lies down in the_____ to lie down unto the Lord; that he may watch over him in his sleep.",
    "answer": "Night",
    "options": ["Couch", "Day", "Night"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4252",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to let his_____ be full of thanks unto God every time he wakes up in the morning.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Belly", "Chest", "Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4253",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that if he always gave thanks unto the Lord and did the right things he would not be lifted at the last day.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4254",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that their fathers called a ball or director a_____, which is, being interpreted, a compass.",
    "answer": "Liahona",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4255",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "How many times does the word “Liahona” appear in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4256",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "The word “Liahona” only appears in what book of the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4257",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:38",
    "question": "According to Alma2, who did he say made or prepared the compass?",
    "answer": ["lord", "god"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4258",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:39",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that know man can work and make such a thing as the Liahona of so curious_____.",
    "answer": "Workmanship",
    "options": ["Engravings", "Workmanship", "Metal"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4259",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:39",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the Liahona was prepared to show unto their fathers the course which they should travel in the_____.",
    "answer": "Wilderness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4260",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:40",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Liahona worked for their fathers according to their_____ in God.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4261",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:40",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the faith their fathers had in God would caused the_____ to point the way they should travel in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Spindles",
    "options": ["Spindles", "Arrows", "Missiles"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4262",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:40",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman their fathers had the miracle of the Liahona and many other_____ wrought by the power of God, day by day.",
    "answer": "Miracles",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4263",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:41",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman because the miracles were worked by_____ means it did show unto their fathers marvelous works.",
    "answer": "Small",
    "options": ["Large", "Small", "Huge"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4264",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:41",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman their fathers were slothful, and forgot to exercise their_____ and diligence and then those marvelous works ceased.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4265",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:41",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman because of the slothfulness of their fathers, and because they did not exercise their faith in the Lord; their fathers did not progress in their_____.",
    "answer": "Journey",
    "options": ["Journey", "Way", "Direction"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4266",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:42",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that their fathers tarried in the wilderness, or did not travel a direct course.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4267",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:42",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman their fathers were afflicted with hunger and thirst, because of their_____.",
    "answer": "Transgressions",
    "options": ["Wrong Doings", "Transgressions", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4268",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:43",
    "question": "Alma2 said that his fathers were slothful to give heed to the_____ and that is why they did not prosper and was an example of things which were temporal.",
    "answer": "Compass",
    "options": ["Lord", "Gospel", "Compass"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4269",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:43",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman their fathers did not prosper in temporal and_____ things because they did not give heed to the compass which was prepare by the Lord.",
    "answer": "Spiritual",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4270",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:44",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is easy to give heed to the word of Christ, which will point to you a straight course to eternal bliss.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4271",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:44",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is not easy to give heed to the word of Jesus Christ because the Liahona will not always point to a straight course to eternal bliss.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4272",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:45",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the director/Liahona is a type of thing or an example of following Jesus_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4273",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:45",
    "question": "Alma2 said if we follow Jesus Christ he will carry us beyond the vale of sorrow into a far better land or course of promise.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4274",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:46",
    "question": "Alma2 cautioned Helaman to not be slothful because of the eas1ness of the way like it was for their fathers; that if they would look they might live.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4275",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma37:46",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ the way is prepared by the Lord, even so it is with us; and if we will look we may live forever.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4276",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma37:47",
    "question": "And told Helaman to take care of the sacred things he had been entrusted with and to see that he looks to God and live.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4277",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:47",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman to go and declare the word of the Lord unto his people and to be_____.",
    "answer": "Sober",
    "options": ["Gentle", "Thoughtful", "Sober"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4278",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma37:47",
    "question": "Which one of his three sons did Alma2 command to go and declare the word of the Lord unto the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4279",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:15",
    "question": "Which one of his three sons did Alma2 command to go and teach the word of the Lord unto the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Shiblon",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4280",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Which one of his three sons did Alma2 command to go and preach the word of the Lord unto the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4282",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "What is the name of Alma2 the Youngers’ youngest son?",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4283",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that inasmuch as he would keep the commandments of God he would prosper in the land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4284",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon if he would not keep the commandments of God he would be cast off from his presence.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4285",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:2",
    "question": "Alma2 had great joy in_____ because of the stead1ness and faithfulness he had in God.",
    "answer": "Shiblon",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4286",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said_____ had commenced in his youth to look to the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "Shiblon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4287",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:2",
    "question": "Alma2 hope Shiblon would continue in keeping the commandments of the Lord; and said blessed is he that endureth to the_____.",
    "answer": "End",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4288",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:3",
    "question": "Alma2 had great joy in Shiblon because of his faithfulness, diligence, patience, and long-_____ among the people of the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "Suffering",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4289",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said he knew Shiblon had been bonded by the_____.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Zoramites", "Amulekites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4290",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:4",
    "question": "Which one of Alma2’s son was stoned by the Zoramites because he preached the word of the Lord to them?",
    "answer": "Sbilon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4291",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said Shiblon was able to bear all his sufferings with patience because the_____ was with him.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4292",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said he and Shiblon knew that the Lord had delivered him from the Zoramites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4293",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to remember to keep his_____ in the Lord and he would deliver him out of his trials.",
    "answer": "Trust",
    "options": ["Prayers", "Trust", "Faith"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4294",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to trust in the Lord and he would deliver him from his trials, troubles, and his_____.",
    "answer": "Afflictions",
    "options": ["Unworth1ness", "Cleanl1ness", "Afflictions"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4295",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:5",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say would be lifted up in the last day if he would keep his trust in the Lord?",
    "answer": "Shiblon",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4296",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Spirit of God was the one that made all things known unto him and not his own wisdom.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4297",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon if he had not been born of_____ he would had not been able to know the things of God.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4298",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:7",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say had been sent by God to declare unto him to stop the work of destruction among his people?",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4299",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:7",
    "question": "Alma2 said he had seen an angel face to_____ and had spoken to him.",
    "answer": "Face",
    "options": ["Head", "Face", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4300",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that the voice of the angel that had spoken to him was like_____, and it shook the whole earth.",
    "answer": "Thunder",
    "options": ["Fire", "Thunder", "A Ghetto Blaster"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4301",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:37",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that the angel that had spoken to him face to face was a female.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4302",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that he did not receive a remission of his_____ until he cried out unto the Lord Jesus Christ for mercy.",
    "answer": "Sins",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4303",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:8",
    "question": "Alma2 cried unto the Lord for a remission of his sins and did find peace unto his_____.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Soul", "Mind", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4304",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon of his experience with the angel so that he would learn wisdom.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4305",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that there is no other way or_____ whereby man can be saved, only in and through Christ.",
    "answer": "Means",
    "options": ["Direction", "Means", "Path"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4306",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Jesus Christ is the_____ and the light of the world.",
    "answer": "Life",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4307",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:9",
    "question": "Alma2 said that Jesus Christ is the word of truth and righteousness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4308",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ even as he had begun to teach the word of the Lord; that he should continue to do so.",
    "answer": "Shiblon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4309",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to be_____ and temperate in all things.",
    "answer": "Diligent",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4310",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon not to be lifted up unto pride and to not_____ in his own wisdom, nor of his own strength.",
    "answer": "Boast",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4311",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to use_____, but not overbearance; and to also bridle all his passions and be filled with love.",
    "answer": "Boldness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4312",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:12",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell Shiblon to see that he refrain from idleness.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4313",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon not to pray like what group of people that wanted to be seen and heard of men?",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4314",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:13",
    "question": "The Zoramites prayed to be heard of men and to be praised for their_____.",
    "answer": "Wisdom",
    "options": ["Looks", "Apparel", "Wisdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4315",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that the Zoramites would pray and say:  O God, I thank thee that we are_____ than our brethren.",
    "answer": "Better",
    "options": ["Taller", "Better", "Worst"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4316",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma38:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to pray and ask for his forgiveness in his _____, and to remember his brethren in mercy.",
    "answer": "Unworth1ness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4317",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that he did not have to acknowledge his unworth1ness before God at all times.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4318",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma38:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon that may the Lord bless his_____, and receive him at the last day into his kingdom, to sit in peace.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Body", "Soul", "Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4319",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma38:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Shiblon to go and teach the word of the Lord unto the Nephites and to be sober.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4320",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:10",
    "question": "Corianton was around his mid twenties when Alma2 gave him his charge.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4321",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ that he had more to say to him that he did to Shiblon.",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4322",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "Alma2 gave more counsel to Coriantion than any other of his sons.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4323",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "Alma2 said Corianton did not observe the stead1ness, faithfulness and diligence in keeping the commandments of God like his brother Shiblon.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4324",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that Shiblon did not set a good example for him; in keeping the commandments of the Lord.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4325",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said Corianton did not give so much heed unto his_____ as did his brother Shiblon, among the Zoramites.",
    "options": ["Apparel", "Looks"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4326",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:2",
    "question": "Who did Alma2 say went about boasting in his own strength and wisdom?",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4327",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it was grievous to him because he forsaken the ministry of the Lord.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4328",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:3",
    "question": "What was the name of the harlot that Corianton went after among the borders of the Lamanites?",
    "answer": "Isabel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4329",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:3",
    "question": "The harlot Isabel was from the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Siron",
    "options": ["Waters Of Mormon", "Many Waters", "Siron"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4330",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ that Isabel had stolen away the hearts of many men; but that it was not an excuse for him to go after her.",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4331",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he should have tended to the ministry wherewith he was entrusted to.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4332",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:5, 9,11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the things or the lust of his eyes was an abomination in the sight of the Lord.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4333",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:5",
    "question": "According to Alma2; the lust of our eyes, is above all sins except of the shedding of innocent blood and denying the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4334",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said if we deny the_____ Ghost once it has had a place in us, and we know that we deny it, it is a sin which is unpardonable.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4335",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:6",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that whosoever murders against the light and_____ of God, it is not easy for him to obtain forgiveness.",
    "answer": "Knowledge",
    "options": ["Knowledge", "Wisdom", "Truth"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4336",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:7",
    "question": "Alma2 did not tell Corianton that he wished that he would not be guilty of such a crime as denying the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4337",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____ that he did not wish to dwell upon his crimes, to harrow up his soul, if it were not for his own good.",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4338",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he could hide his crimes from God if he was very cleaver and sneaky.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4339",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that if we do not repent, our sins will stand against us as a_____ against us at the last day.",
    "answer": "Testimony",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4340",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to repent and forsake his sins, and not to go anymore after the_____ of his eyes.",
    "answer": "Lusts",
    "options": ["Pleasure", "Eye Candy", "Lusts"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4341",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to cross himself in all things; and if he did not, he could not inherit the_____ of God.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4342",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:10",
    "question": "Alma2 did not command Corianton to take it upon himself to counsel with his older brothers in his undertakings.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4343",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:10",
    "question": "Because he was in his youth; Alma2 told Corianton that he stood in need of nourishing from his elder brothers.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4344",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he did not have to always give heed to the counsel of his older brothers.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4345",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:11",
    "question": "Alma2 counseled Corianton against being led away by any vain and _____ things.",
    "answer": "Foolish",
    "options": ["Precious", "Foolish", "Pretty"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4346",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to not let his heart be led away by the_____ again after those wicked harlots.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4347",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said Corianton had brought great iniquity among the_____ because when they saw his conduct they would not believe in his words.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Lamanites", "Amulekites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4348",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the Spirit of the Lord had commanded him to tell his children to do good because they could lead away the hearts of many people unto destruction.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4349",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:12",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded Corianton in the fear of the Lord that he should not refrain from his iniquities.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4350",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he should turn to the Lord with all his mind, might, and _____.",
    "answer": "Strength",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4351",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to turn to the Lord and use his mind, might, and strength; and not lead away the hearts of anymore of the people unto iniquity.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4352",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to acknowledge his_____ and the wrong which he had done unto the people.",
    "answer": "Faults",
    "options": ["Strength", "Wisdom And", "Faults"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4353",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:12",
    "question": "Alma2 commanded Corianton not to seek after riches and the_____ things of the world.",
    "answer": "Vain",
    "options": ["Pretty", "Vain", "Better"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4354",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the riches and vain things of this world could not be carried away with him when he died.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4355",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:15",
    "question": "Alma2 spoke to Corianton about the coming of Christ; and that he would surely come to declare_____ tidings of salvation unto his people.",
    "answer": "Glad",
    "options": ["Glad", "Sad", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4356",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he was called to the ministry to declare glad tidings among his people and to prepare their minds for salvation.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4357",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:16",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton he was called to the ministry to prepare the minds of the people to prepare their children to hear the gospel at the time of Jesus Christ’s coming.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4358",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:17",
    "question": "According to Alma2; Corianton felt comfortable or at ease about the things pertaining to the coming of Christ.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4359",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:17",
    "question": "Corianton wondered why the things pertaining to the coming of Jesus _____were being known unto him so long before his actual coming.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4360",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma39:17",
    "question": "Corianton did not wonder why the things pertaining to the coming of Jesus Christ were being made known unto him so long before his actual coming.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4361",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:18",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton a_____ at this time is as precious unto God as a soul will be at the time of his coming.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Person", "Body", "Soul"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4362",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma39:18",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it was necessary that the plan of_____ should be made known unto this people as well as unto their children.",
    "answer": "Redemption",
    "options": ["God", "Redemption", "The Resurrection"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4363",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma39:19",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it was just as easy for the Lord to send his_____ to declare glad tidings now as is was for him or after the time of his coming.",
    "answer": "Angel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4364",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:1",
    "question": "Alma2 did not know that Corianton was worried concerning the resurrection of the dead.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4365",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:1",
    "question": "Alma2 perceived that Corianton was worried concerning the resurrection of the_____.",
    "answer": "Dead",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4366",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the mortal body does not put on immortality until after the coming of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4367",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the mortal body does not put on corruption and_____ until the coming of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Incorruption",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4368",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said Jesus Christ brings to pass the_____ of the dead.",
    "answer": "Resurrection",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4369",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said there are many mysteries which are kept from man and that no one knows them except God and his holy prophets.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4370",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he had inquired diligently of the Lord that he may know concerning the resurrection of the dead.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4371",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said there is a time appointed that all shall come_____ from the dead.",
    "answer": "Forth",
    "options": ["Before", "Forth", "Among"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4372",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the time which is appointed that all shall come forth from the dead is known only to God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4373",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton it does not matter that all shall come forth at one time, or a second time or a_____ time from the dead.",
    "answer": "Third",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4374",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:5",
    "question": "Alma2 said he knew that there is a time appointed that all shall rise from the_____.",
    "answer": "Dead",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4375",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said there must be a space between the time of _____and the time of the resurrection.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4376",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he had inquired of the Lord concerning what became of the_____ of men from the time of death until the time appointed for the resurrection.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4377",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said it does not matter if there was more than one time appointed for men to rise from the dead; because all men to not die at once.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4378",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that all is one day with God, and _____ is only measured unto men.",
    "answer": "Time",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4379",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the he knew the time will come when all shall rise from the dead, and then shall they know that God knows all the times that are appointed unto man",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4380",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said an angel of the Lord had told him concerning the state of the_____of man between death and the resurrection.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4381",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the spirits of all_____, as soon as they departed from this mortal body, are taken home to that God who gave them life.",
    "answer": "Men",
    "options": ["Persons", "Men", "Individuals"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4382",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said that only the spirits of the good are taken home to that God that gave them life.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4383",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it shall come to pass, that the spirits of those who are_____ are received into a state of happiness.",
    "answer": "Righteous",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4384",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the state of happiness is called paradise.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4385",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:12",
    "question": "According to Alma2 paradise is a state of_____, a state of peace, where the righteous shall rest from all their troubles and from all care, and sorrow.",
    "answer": "Rest",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4386",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:12",
    "question": "According to Alma2 paradise is a state of rest, a state of_____, where the righteous can rest from all their troubles and from all care, and sorrow.",
    "answer": "Peace",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4387",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that the spirits of the wicked or the evil shall be cast into outer_____.",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4388",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "The spirits of the wicked and evil chose to have no part or portion of the Spirit of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4389",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "The spirits of the wicked and evil chose evil works rather than good; therefore the spirit of the_____ did enter them, and take possession of their house.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4390",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the spirits in outer darkness shall be weeping, and wailing, and_____of their teeth, because of their own iniquity.",
    "answer": "Gnashing",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4391",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said the spirits of the wicked and evil will be led captive by the will of the Grim Reaper.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4392",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the state of the wicked in outer darkness is awful; and are looking fearful for the fiery indignation of the wrath of God upon them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4393",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said the spirits of the wicked and evil remain in outer darkness and as well as the righteous in paradise, until the time of their resurrection.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4394",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said there are some people that have understood that the state of happiness and the state of misery of the soul; was a first resurrection.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4395",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:15",
    "question": "Alma2 did not admit to Corianton that the raising of the spirit of the soul and their consignation to happiness or misery; may be termed a resurrection.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4396",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:16",
    "question": "According to Alma2 the resurrection of all those who have been, or who are, or who shall be, down to the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead is called the first resurrection.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4397",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said that only those souls who have been born and have died before the coming of Jesus Christ are entitled to the first resurrection.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4398",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:17",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton not to suppose the first resurrection does not mean that the consignation to happiness or misery does not mean what he had spoken of.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4399",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:18",
    "question": "According to Alma2 the first resurrection means the reuniting of the soul with the body, of those from the days of_____ down to the resurrection of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Adam",
    "options": ["Abraham", "Adam", "Noah"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4400",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:19",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton whether the souls and the bodies of those of whom he had spoken shall all be reunited at once, the wicked as well as the righteous, he did not say.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4401",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:29",
    "question": "Alma2 said all will come forth; and it was enough for him to know that the resurrection comes to pass before the resurrection of those who die after the resurrection of Jesus Christ",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4402",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:20",
    "question": "Alma2 said it was his_____, that the souls and the bodies are reunited, of the righteous, at the resurrection of Jesus Christ, and his ascension into heaven.",
    "answer": "Opinion",
    "options": ["Opinion", "Understanding", "Thoughts"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4403",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:21",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton there is a space between death and the resurrection of the body, and a state of the soul in happiness or in_____.",
    "answer": "Misery",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4404",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said there is a time appointed by God that the dead shall come forth, and be reunited, both_____ and body, and be brought to stand before God, and be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4405",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma40:21",
    "question": "Alma2 said only the unrighteous dead that died during the time before Jesus Christ ascension into heaven; will be brought to stand before God and be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4406",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:22",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the resurrection of Jesus Christ brings about the restoration of those things of which has been spoken by the mouths of the_____.",
    "answer": "Prophets",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4407",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:23",
    "question": "According to Alma2 every soul shall be restored to the body, and the body to the soul; and every limb and_____.",
    "answer": "Joint",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4408",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton every soul shall be restored to the body; and that not even a _____ of the head shall not be lost; but all things shall be restored to their proper and perfect frame.",
    "answer": "Hair",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4409",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:24,25",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton after the restoration the_____will sh1ne forth in the kingdom of God; according to the things which has been spoken by the prophets of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Righteous",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4410",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said an awful death will come upon the wicked; for they die as to things pertaining to things of_____.",
    "answer": "Righteousness",
    "options": ["The Good", "Righteousness", "Cleanl1ness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4411",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that no_____ thing can inherit the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Unclean",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4412",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma40:26",
    "question": "Alma2 said unclean things and the wicked are cast out of the kingdom of God, and consigned to partake of the fruits of their_____or their works.",
    "answer": "Labors",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4413",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma40:26",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the wicked are cast out of the kingdom of God and they drink the dregs of a_____cup.",
    "answer": "Bitter",
    "options": ["Bad", "Large", "Bitter"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4414",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:1",
    "question": "Alma2 said he had more to say about the restoration because some people had wrested (twisted) the scriptures, and have gone astray because of this thing.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4415",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:1",
    "question": "Alma2 knew_____was worried and concerned about the restoration of things which had been spoken by the mouths to the prophets of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4416",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the plan of the_____is requisite with the justice of God.",
    "answer": "Restoration",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4417",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is requisite that all things should be restored to their proper order and it was also requisite and just; according to the power and resurrection of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4418",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:2",
    "question": "According to the power and resurrection of Jesus Christ; the soul of man should be restored to its body, and that every part of the_____should be restored to itself.",
    "answer": "Body",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4419",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said it is requisite with the_____of God that men should be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "Justice",
    "options": ["Laws", "Justice", "Meaning"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4420",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said if your works were good in this life, and the desires of your hearts were good, then you should also, at the last day, be restored unto that which is good.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4421",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said if your works were evil in this life, then evil will be restored unto you.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4422",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:4",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton all things shall be restored to their proper order, every thing to its natural frame-mortality raised to immortality, corruption to_____.",
    "answer": "Incorruption",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4423",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:4",
    "question": "Alma2 said all of us will be raised to endless happiness to inherit the kingdom of God, or to_____misery to inherit the kingdom of the devil, the one on one hand, the other on the other.",
    "answer": "Endless",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4424",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that all of us will be raised to endless happiness to inherit the kingdom of God, or to endless misery to inherit the kingdom of the_____.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4425",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:5",
    "question": "Alma2 said if we desired to do evil all day long, even so shall we have evil rewarded unto us when the night comes.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4426",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:6",
    "question": "According to Alma2; if we have repented of our sins, and desired righteousness until the end of our days, even so shall we be rewarded unto_____.",
    "answer": "Righteousness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4427",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:7",
    "question": "If we are righteous until the end of our days; we are redeemed of the Lord and are taken out, and we are delivered out from the endless night of_____.",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "options": ["Darkness", "Misery", "Woes"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4428",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:7",
    "question": "Alma2 said we either stand or fall; for behold, we are our own judges, whether to do good or to do_____.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4429",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said that the decrees of God are alterable for our own good.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4430",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:8",
    "question": "Alma2 said the decrees of God are unalterable; therefore, the way is prepared that whosoever will; may_____therein and be saved.",
    "answer": "Walk",
    "options": ["Walk", "Run", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4431",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told_____not to risk more offenses against God upon the points of doctr1ne, which had caused him to commit sin.",
    "answer": "Coriantion",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4432",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:10",
    "question": "Alma told Corianton not to suppose he would be restored from sin to happiness because of the things which he had spoken to him concerning the restoration.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4433",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:10",
    "question": "What person did Alma2 say “wickedness never was happiness” to?",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Shiblon", "Corianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4434",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that all men are in a state of nature or carnal state, and are in the gall of bitterness and in the bonds of iniquity without God in the world.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4435",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:11",
    "question": "If we are of a carnal state and in the bonds of iniquity, we are without God in the world; therefore, we are in a state contrary to the nature of happiness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4436",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma41:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the meaning of the word restoration is to bring back again evil for_____, carnal for carnal, or devilish for devilish.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4437",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma41:13",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the meaning of the word restoration is to bring back good for that which is good; righteous for that which is unrighteous.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4438",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to see that he was merciful unto his brethren; to deal justly, judged righteously, and do good_____.",
    "answer": "Continually",
    "options": ["Always", "Once In Awhile", "Continually"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4439",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:15",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the things which he did send out shall return unto him again, and be_____.",
    "answer": "Restored",
    "options": ["Restored", "Given Back", "Taken Away"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4440",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma41:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said the word_____more fully condem’s the sinner, and justifies him not at all.",
    "answer": "Restoration",
    "options": ["Damnation", "Restoration", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4441",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:1",
    "question": "Alma2 knew Corianton was worried because of the things which he could not understand-which is concerning the justice of God in the punishment of the sinner.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4442",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:1",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton he knew he supposed that it is an injustice that the sinner should be consigned to a state of misery.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4443",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:2",
    "question": "Alma2 did not relate to Corianton the story of Adam and Eve our first parents.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4444",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:2",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the Lord God sent out our first parents forth from the garden of_____, to till the ground, from where they were taken.",
    "answer": "Eden",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4445",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said God drew out the man, and he placed at the west end of the Garden of Eden, and placed a thing which was called Cherubim.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4446",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:2",
    "question": "Alma2 said God drew out the man, and he placed at the east end of the Garden of Eden, _____, and a flaming sword which turned every way, to keep Adam away from the Tree of Life.",
    "answer": "Cherubim",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4447",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that the man had become as God, knowing good and_____; because he had partaken of the fruit.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4448",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said if the man had partaken of the_____of Life, he would have lived forever.",
    "answer": "Tree",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4449",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:2-3",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton the purpose God had placed Cherubim and a flaming sword in front of the Tree of Life was to keep Adam from partaking of it.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4450",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:3",
    "question": "Alma2 said if Adam would have partaken of the Tree of Life, he would have lived forever.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4451",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:4",
    "question": "There was a time granted unto man to repent, a______time, a time to repent and serve God.",
    "answer": "Probationary",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4452",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:5",
    "question": "If_____ would have put forth his hand immediately, and partaken of the tree of life, he would have lived forever, according to the word of God.",
    "answer": "Mike",
    "options": ["Mike", "John"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4453",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:5",
    "question": "If Adam would have partaken of the Tree of Life, he would have lived forever, having no space for repentance, and the word of God would have been void.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4454",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:5",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton if Adam would have partaken of the Tree of Life, the word of God would have been void, and the great plan of_____would have been frustrated.",
    "answer": "Salvation",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4455",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said there was appointed unto man to_____; therefore, as they were cut off from the Tree of Life they should be cut off from the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "Die",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4456",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:6",
    "question": "Alma2 said man became lost forever, and they became a_____man.",
    "answer": "Fallen",
    "options": ["Sinful", "Fallen", "Wicked"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4457",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:7",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that our first parents were cut off both temporally and_____from the presence of the Lord; and they became subjects to follow after their own will.",
    "answer": "Spiritually",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4458",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:8",
    "question": "It was not expedient that man should be reclaimed from this temporal death, for that would destroy the great plan of_____.",
    "answer": "Happiness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4459",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:9",
    "question": "The fall had brought upon all mankind a spiritual death as well as a_____death, and they were cut off from the presence of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Temporal",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4460",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that it was not necessary that mankind should not be reclaimed from this spiritual death that he had been speaking about.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4461",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:10",
    "question": "Because we have become carnal, sensual, by nature; Alma2 said this probationary state that we are in is for us to prepare; or it is our preparatory state.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4462",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:11",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to remember that if it was not for the plan of_____, as soon as we would die, our souls would be miserable, being cut off from the presence of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Redemption",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4463",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said if it were not for the plan of redemption; there was no means to reclaim men from this fallen state, which man brought upon himself because of his own disobedience.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4464",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:13",
    "question": "According to the justice of God, the plan of redemption could not be brought about, only on conditions of repentance of men in this_____state.",
    "answer": "Probationary",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4465",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:13",
    "question": "The words “probationary state” can also be used to describe this “preparatory state” that we are now living in.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4466",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:13",
    "question": "According to Alma2 if there was not a preparatory state the plan of redemption or the conditions thereof; mercy could not take effect except is should destroy the work of justice.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4467",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:13",
    "question": "The work of justice could not be destroyed; if so God would cease to be_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4468",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:14",
    "question": "Because all mankind were fallen, and they were in the grasp of justice; yea, the_____of God, it consigned mankind forever to be cut off from his presence.",
    "answer": "Justice",
    "options": ["Justice", "Conditions", "Hands"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4469",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:15",
    "question": "The plan of mercy could not be brought about except an_____should be made; therefore God himself has atoned for the sins of the world, to bring about the plan of mercy.",
    "answer": "Atonement",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4470",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:15",
    "question": "Alma2 said God himself has brought about the plan of mercy, to appease the demands of justice; that God might be a perfect, just_____, and a merciful God also.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4471",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:16",
    "question": "Repentance could not come unto men except there was a punishment, which also was eternal as the life of the soul should be.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4472",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:16",
    "question": "There is a punishment which also is eternal as the life of the soul should be, affixed opposite to the plan of_____, which was as eternal also as the life of the soul.",
    "answer": "Happiness",
    "options": ["Misery", "Happiness", "Hell"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4473",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:18",
    "question": "There is not a punishment affixed, and a just law given, which brought remorse of conscience unto man.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4474",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:20",
    "question": "If there was no law given against sin; men would not be afraid to_____.",
    "answer": "Sin",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4475",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:21",
    "question": "If there was no law given unto men, if men sinned what could justice do, or mercy either, for they would have no claim upon the creature.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4476",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:22",
    "question": "There is a_____given, and a punishment affixed, and a repentance granted; which repentance mercy claims; otherwise, justice claims the creature and executes the law, and the law inflicts the punishment.",
    "answer": "Law",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4477",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:22",
    "question": "If there was no law given or punishment for sin, the works of justice would be destroyed, and God would cease to be_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4478",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:23",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that God sometimes ceases to be God and is not fair and just.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4479",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:23",
    "question": "Mercy claims the penitent, and mercy comes because of the atonement; and the atonement brings to pass the resurrection of the_____.",
    "answer": "Dead",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4480",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said the resurrection of the dead brings men back into the presence of_____; and thus they are restored into his presence, to be judged according to their works.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4481",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:23",
    "question": "Alma2 said that men are judged according to their works, according to the law and not according to justice.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4482",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:24",
    "question": "Justice exercises all his demands, and also mercy claims all which is her own; and thus, none but the truly_____are saved.",
    "answer": "Penitent",
    "options": ["Penitent", "Sorry", "Forgiving"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4483",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:25",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton not to suppose mercy can rob justice, if that was the case, God would cease to be God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4484",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:26",
    "question": "God brings about his great and_____purposes, which were prepared from the foundation of the world.",
    "answer": "Eternal",
    "options": ["Beautiful", "Just", "Eternal"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4485",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:26",
    "question": "God brings about his great and eternal purposes, which were prepared from the_____of the world.",
    "answer": "Foundation",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4486",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:26",
    "question": "Because of God’s great and eternal purposes; there comes the salvation and the redemption of men, and also their destruction and_____.",
    "answer": "Misery",
    "options": ["Fall", "Misery", "Damnation"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4487",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that anyone can come and partake of the waters of life freely.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4488",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:27",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that anyone and everyone should come and partake of the waters of life freely because God has made it a commandment.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4489",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:27",
    "question": "Alma2 said no one is compelled to come and partake of the waters of life freely; but in the last day it shall be restored unto him according to his_____.",
    "answer": "Deeds",
    "options": ["Wealth", "Deeds", "Fortune"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4490",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:28",
    "question": "If we desire to do evil, and have not repented in our days, behold, _____shall be done unto us, according to the restoration of God.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4491",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:29,1",
    "question": "Alma2 desired Corianton to not be troubled by so many things in his mind, but to only let his sins trouble him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4492",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:29",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to only be troubled by his sins, which shall bring him down to repentance.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4493",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma42:30",
    "question": "Alma2 desired_____not to deny the justice of God no more, and not endeavor to excuse himself in the least point because of his sins, by denying the justice of God.",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4494",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:30",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to let the justice of God and his mercy and his long-suffering; have a full sway in his_____; and let it bring him down to the dust in humility.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Belly", "Heart", "Bosom"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4495",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton that he was called of God to_____the word unto the people.",
    "answer": "Preach",
    "options": ["Prophesy", "Preach", "Explain"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4496",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton to declare the word of God with truth and soberness, that he may bring souls unto repentance, that the great plan of mercy may have claim upon them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4497",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Alma2 told Corianton may God grant unto him even according to his_____.",
    "answer": "Words",
    "options": ["Wishes", "Words", "Deeds"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4498",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma42:31",
    "question": "Out of his three sons, Alma2 counseled Corianton the most.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4499",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma21:31",
    "question": "Because_____ was the most wayward son of Alma2; he counseled him the most.",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4500",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:1",
    "question": "Alma2 and his sons went forth among the people of Zarahemla to declare the word of God unto the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4501",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:2",
    "question": "Alma2 and his sons preached the word of God, and the truth, according to the spirit of prophecy and_____.",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4502",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:2",
    "question": "Alma2 and his sons preached the word of God after the_____order of God by which they were called.",
    "answer": "Holy",
    "options": ["Sacred", "Holy", "Chosen"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4503",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the days that Alma2 and his sons preached the word of God unto the Zoramites, the Zoramites became_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Amulekites", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4504",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:4",
    "question": "In the eighteenth year of the reign of the_____, the Lamanites gathered together their armies in the land of Jershon to make war with the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Judges",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4505",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:5",
    "question": "What was the name of the leader of the Lamanites who came into the land of the Zoramites to make war with the Nephites?",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah",
    "options": ["Moroni", "Zerahemnah", "Teancum"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4506",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:6",
    "question": "What tribe of people did Zerahemnah appoint as chief captains over the Lamanites because of their wicked and murderous disposition?",
    "answer": "Amalekites",
    "options": ["Amalekites", "Amulekites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4507",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:7",
    "question": "Zerahemnah appointed Amalekites as chief captains of the Lamanites in order to preserve their hatred towards the Nephites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4508",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:7",
    "question": "Zerahemnah did not appoint Amalekites as chief captains so that he might bring them into subjection to the accomplishment of his designs.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4509",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah purposes and designs were to stir up the_____to anger against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Amulekites", "Ammonites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4510",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah’s designs were to usurp great power over the Amulekites, and also that he might grain power over the_____by bringing them into bondage.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4511",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:9",
    "question": "The Nephites designs or purposes were to support their lands, houses, wives, and their_____.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["Barns", "Children", "Property"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4512",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:9",
    "question": "The Nephites wanted to preserve all the things they possessed from the hands of their_____.",
    "answer": "Enemies",
    "options": ["Enemies", "Opposing Forces", "Neighbors"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4513",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:9",
    "question": "The Nephites wanted to preserve their rights, privileges, and also their_____, that they might worship God according to their desires.",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4514",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:9",
    "question": "The Nephites did not want to preserve their rights, privileges, and also their liberty, that they might worship God according to their desires.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4515",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:10",
    "question": "The Nephites knew that if they should fall into the hands of the_____ and worship God in spirit and in truth, the Lamanites would destroy them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4516",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:11",
    "question": "The Nephites did not know the extreme hatred of the Lamanites towards their brethren, who were the Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4517",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:11",
    "question": "Another name for the people of_____; is the Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4518",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:11,56:6",
    "question": "The Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s had entered into a covenant with the Lord that they would not shed the blood of their brethren; and they would not break it.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4519",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:11",
    "question": "If the people of Ammon should fall into the hands of the_____ they would be destroyed.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4520",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:12",
    "question": "The Nephites would not allow the Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s to be destroyed; therefore they gave them_____for their inheritance.",
    "answer": "Lands",
    "options": ["Precious Things", "Gold", "Lands"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4521",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:13",
    "question": "The people of_____did give the Nephites a large portion of their substance to support the armies of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4522",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:13",
    "question": "Because the Anti-Nephi-Lehi’s would not take up arms against their brethren; the Nephites were compelled, alone, to withstand against the Lamanites by themselves.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4523",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:13",
    "question": "During the time of the eighteenth year of the reign of the judges, the Lamanites consisted of people who were descendants of Laman and Lemuel, and the sons of Ismael.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4524",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:13",
    "question": "The Lamanites also consisted from those who were dissented from the Nephites; who were Amalekites, Zoramites, and the descendants of the priests’ of_____.",
    "answer": "Noah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4525",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:14",
    "question": "The Lamanites and those descendants of people were as numerous, nearly, as were the Nephites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4526",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:14",
    "question": "The Nephites were not obligated to contend with their brethren, even unto bloodshed.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4527",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass the armies of the Lamanites gathered together in the land of Antionum, and the armies of the _____were prepared to go to battle and meet them in the land of Jershon.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4528",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:16",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book is Moroni; the chief captain of the Nephite armies first mentioned?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4529",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:16",
    "question": "The words “Captain Moroni” never appear in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4530",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:16",
    "question": "Moroni was the only chief captain of the Nephite armies.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4531",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:17",
    "question": "Moroni took command only of the Nephites armies and not of the government of their wars.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4532",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:17",
    "question": "Moroni was only_____years old when he took command of the armies of the Nephites and of their government of their wars.",
    "answer": "25",
    "options": ["25", "26", "27"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4533",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:17",
    "question": "Moroni was in his mid-thirties when he took command of the armies of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4534",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:18",
    "question": "Moroni and his people were armed with swords, and with cimeters, and all manner of_____of war.",
    "answer": "Weapons",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4535",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:19",
    "question": "Moroni had prepared his people with breastplates and arm-shields, and also shields to defend their hands, and they were also dressed with thick clothing.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4536",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:20",
    "question": "The army of_____ was not prepared with any such things as was the armies of Moroni; they had only their swords, cimeters, their bows and their arrows.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4537",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:20",
    "question": "The armies of Zerahemnah also had their stones and slings; and they were naked, save it were a skin which was girded about their loins.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4538",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:20",
    "question": "All the armies of Zerahemnah were naked except for the skins that were girded about their loins; but the Zoramites and the Amalekites were not.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4539",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:21",
    "question": "Because Zerahemnah’s armies were not armed with breastplates, neither with shields they were exceedingly afraid of the armies of the_____ because of their armor.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4540",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:21",
    "question": "Even though the armies of Zerahemnah were more numerous than the armies of the Nephites; they were exceedingly afraid because of how well Nephites were prepared for war.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4541",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:22",
    "question": "Zerahemnah and his armies came unto the land of Manti to try to take possession of it and supposed that_____and his armies would not know where they had gone.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4542",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni sent_____into the wilderness to watch the camp of the armies of Zerahemnah.",
    "answer": "Spies",
    "options": ["Women", "Spies", "Investigators"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4543",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:23",
    "question": "Because Moroni knew concerning the prophecies of_____; he sent certain men unto him to inquire of the Lord where they should go to defend themselves against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4544",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 informed the men of_____ where they should go to defend themselves and those messengers went and delivered the message unto him.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4545",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:2",
    "question": "Moroni caused that all the people in that quarter of the land of Manti should gather themselves together to do battle against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4546",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:26",
    "question": "Moroni and the Nephites were prepared to defend their lands, country, rights, and their liberties against the time of the coming of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4547",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni caused that his army should be secreted in the valley which was near the bank of the river_____.",
    "answer": "Sidon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4548",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:28",
    "question": "Moroni did not place spies about the land that he might know when the camp of the Lamanites should come upon them.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4549",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:29",
    "question": "Moroni was always oblivious to the intention of the Lamanites against his army and the Nephites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4550",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:29",
    "question": "The_____wanted to destroy the Nephites, or to subject them and bring them into bondage that they might establish a kingdom unto themselves over all the land.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4551",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:30",
    "question": "Moroni knew that it was only the desire of the Nephites to preserve their lands, their liberty, and their church.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4552",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:30",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book is the word “Stratagem” first used?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4553",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:30",
    "question": "Moroni though it was no sin that he should defend the_____by stratagem; therefore, he found out by his spies which course the Lamanites were taking.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4554",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:30&Refer to Origin of the Book of Mormon",
    "question": "Alma2 is not the only person to use the word “Stratagem” in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4555",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:30",
    "question": "The word “Stratagem” is only used in what Book of Mormon book?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4557",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:31",
    "question": "The name of the hill in which Moroni concealed a part of his army to do battle with the Lamanites was called what?",
    "answer": "Riplah",
    "options": ["Cumorah", "Riplah", "Ramah"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4558",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:35",
    "question": "The army of the Nephites which was concealed on the south of the hill Riplah was led by a man whose name was Lehi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4559",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:37",
    "question": "The work of death commenced on both sides of the armies, but it was more dreadful on the part of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4560",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:37",
    "question": "Because of the Lamanites nakedness they were exposed to the heavy blows of the Nephites with their swords and their cimeters, which brought death almost at every_____.",
    "answer": "&&&",
    "options": ["Blow", "Stroke", "Swing"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4561",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:38",
    "question": "Because of the way the Nephites were dressed they were shielded from the vital parts of their body from the strokes of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4562",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____became frightened, because of the great destruction among them; and they began to flee towards the river Sidon.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4563",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:43",
    "question": "Before their fight with the army of Moroni; the Lamanites had never been known to fight with such exceeding great strength and courage, not even from the beginning of their days.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4564",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:44",
    "question": "The armies of the Lamanites were inspired to fight with great strength and courage because their leaders and chief captains were_____and Amalekites.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4565",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:44",
    "question": "The armies of the Lamanites were also inspired to fight with great strength and courage because of_____who was their chief captain and commander.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4566",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:44",
    "question": "The Lamanites did fight like_____against the armies of Moroni.",
    "answer": "Dragons",
    "options": ["Animals", "Dogs", "Dragons"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4567",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:44",
    "question": "Many of the Nephites were slain by the hands of the Lamanites and their strokes did pierce many of their breastplates, and their arms.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4568",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:45",
    "question": "The Nephites were inspired by a better cause, for they were not fighting for a monarchy neither for power; but they were fighting for their homes and their liberties.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4569",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:45",
    "question": "The_____were also fighting for their wives and their children, and for their rites of worship and their church.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4570",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:46",
    "question": "The Nephites fought and were doing that which they felt was the duty which they owed to their_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["Countrymen", "Fathers", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4571",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:46",
    "question": "The Lord had said unto the_____, that; “Inasmuch as you are not guilty of the first offense, neither the second, you shall not suffer yourselves to be slain by the hands of your enemies”.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4572",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:47",
    "question": "The Lord did not say unto the Nephites to defend their families even unto bloodshed.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4573",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:47",
    "question": "The Nephites contended with the_____, to defend themselves, and their families, and their religion.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4574",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:48",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the men of_____saw the fierceness and the anger of the Lamanites, they were about to shrink and flee from them.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4575",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma43:48",
    "question": "Moroni perceived the thoughts of his men and sent forth and inspired them with these thoughts-the thoughts of their lands, their liberty, and their freedom from_____.",
    "answer": "Bondage",
    "options": ["Bondage", "Worship", "Work"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4576",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:49",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the men of Moroni turned upon the Lamanites, and they cried with several voices unto the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4577",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:49",
    "question": "The men of Captain Moroni cried with one voice unto the Lord their God for their liberty and their freedom from bondage.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4578",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:50",
    "question": "The men of Moroni began to stand against the Lamanites with power; and in that selfsame hour that they cried unto the Lord for their freedom, the_____ began to flee before them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4579",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma43:51",
    "question": "During this time in the history of the Nephites; the Lamanites were more numerous, by more than double the number of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4580",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:53",
    "question": "When Zerahemnah saw that his armies were encircled by the armies of_____; he and his armies were struck with terror.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4581",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma43:54",
    "question": "When Moroni saw that_____and his armies were struck with terror; he commanded his men that they should stop shedding their blood.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4582",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass Moroni said unto Zerahemnah that he and his armies did not desire to be men of_____, and you know that you are in our hands.",
    "answer": "&&&",
    "options": ["War", "Blood", "No Mercy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4583",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:2",
    "question": "Moroni and his armies did not come to battle against the Lamanites that they might shed their blood for power neither did he desire to bring anyone to the yoke of bondage.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4584",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:2",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah he knew they were angry with the Nephites because of their_____.",
    "answer": "Religion",
    "options": ["Riches", "Skin Color", "Religion"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4585",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:3",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah that the Lord was with them; and had delivered the_____into their hands.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Ammonites", "Lamanites", "Amulekites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4586",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:3",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah that the Lord had delivered them into their hands because of their religion and their faith in_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["Christ", "Holy Ghost", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4587",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:3",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah to recognize that he and his armies could not destroy their faith in Christ.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4588",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:4",
    "question": "Moroni said because they had true faith in God; God will support, and keep, and preserve them, so long as they are faithful unto him, and unto their faith, and their religion.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4589",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:4",
    "question": "Moroni said the Lord will never suffer that they shall be destroyed except they should fall in transgression and deny their_____.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["Idols", "Faith", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4591",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:5",
    "question": "Moroni commanded Zerahemnah in the name of that all-powerful God, who had strengthened their arms that they could have ga1ned power of him and his armies.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4592",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:5",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah that because they had mainta1ned the sacred word of God, they owed all of their_____; and all that was most near and dear unto them.",
    "answer": "Happiness",
    "options": ["Trust", "Happiness", "Misery"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4593",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:6",
    "question": "Moroni commanded_____by all of his desires which he had for life that he would deliver up his weapons of war unto him and his armies.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4594",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:6",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah if he would deliver up his arms unto him he would not seek his blood, but would spare his life and the life of his armies.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4595",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah told_____he and his armies would deliver up their weapons of war unto him but would not suffer themselves to take an oath of not warring with them again.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4596",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah told Moroni he and his armies would deliver up their weapons of war unto him but would not suffer themselves to take an oath of not warring with them again.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4597",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:8",
    "question": "The reason Zerahemnah told Moroni he and his armies would not take an oath of not coming to war with them again is because he knew he and his armies would break it.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4598",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:8",
    "question": "Zerahemnah told Moroni to take his and his armies weapons of war and to let them depart into the_____; otherwise they would retain their weapons and perish or conquer.",
    "answer": "Wilderness",
    "options": ["Forest", "Wilderness", "Waters Of Mormon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4599",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:9",
    "question": "Zerahemnah told Moroni that even though they were of his faith, they believed that God had not delivered them up unto the hands of Moroni and his armies.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4600",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:19",
    "question": "Zerahemnah believed that is was the cunning of_____that had preserved them from their swords and also their breastplates.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4601",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:10",
    "question": "After Zerahemnah had finished speaking; Moroni returned unto him his weapons of war, which he had received, and said: “Behold, we will end the_____”.",
    "answer": "Conflict",
    "options": ["Fight", "Conflict", "Battle"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4602",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:11",
    "question": "Moroni told Zerahemnah that he would not let him leave unless he took an oath or he would spill his_____, or shall submit to the conditions which he had proposed.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Guts", "Blood", "Neither A Or B"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4603",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:12",
    "question": "Zerahemnah reta1ned his sword and was angry with Moroni, and he rushed forward to try to kill Moroni; but as he raised his_____, one of Moroni’s soldiers smote it to the ground.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4604",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:12",
    "question": "One of Moroni’s soldiers broke Zerahemnah’s sword and took of his_____and it fell to the earth. And Zerahemnah withdrew from before them into the midst of his soldiers.",
    "answer": "Scalp",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4605",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the soldier who had smote off the scalp of Zerahemnah, took up the scalp from off the ground by the hair, and put it upon the point of his sword and raised it up",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4606",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:14",
    "question": "The soldier raised his sword and said even as this scalp has fallen to the earth, so shall you fall to the earth except you will deliver up your weapons of war and depart with a_____of peace.",
    "answer": "Covenant",
    "options": ["Compromise", "Covenant", "Treaty"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4607",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:15",
    "question": "There were many or Zerahemnah’s armies who heard the words of the soldier and were struck with fear and came forward and delivered up their weapons unto the feet of_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4608",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:15",
    "question": "Those that delivered up their weapons of war unto Moroni were not allowed to depart into the wilderness but were taken prisoners by Moroni and his armies.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4609",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____was exceedingly wroth, and he did stir up the remainder of his soldiers to anger, to contend more powerfully against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Zerahemnah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4610",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:17",
    "question": "Moroni was angry because of the stubbornness of Zerahemnah and the Lamanites; therefore he commanded his people that they should fall upon them and slay them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4611",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:18",
    "question": "Because of the_____naked skins and their bare heads were exposed to the sharp swords of the Nephites; they were pierced and smitten, and did fall exceedingly fast before the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4612",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:18",
    "question": "The prophecy the soldier of Moroni had prophesied concerning the fall and defeat of the armies of Zerahemnah did not come to pass.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4613",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:19",
    "question": "When Zerahemnah saw that they were all about to be destroyed, he cried mightily unto_____, promising that he would covenant unto him and his armies.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4614",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:19",
    "question": "Because of the covenant Zerahemnah had made with him, Moroni caused that the work of death should cease again among the people.  And he took the weapons of war from the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4615",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma44:20",
    "question": "Because of the covenant Zerahemnah had made with Moroni and his armies they were allowed to depart into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4616",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:21",
    "question": "Because the number of dead among the Lamanites and_____ was so great; their dead were not numbered.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4617",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma44:22",
    "question": "What is the name of the river that the dead among the Lamanites and Nephites were cast into, and they have gone forth and are buried in the depths of the sea.",
    "answer": "Sidon",
    "options": ["Snake", "Mississippi", "Sidon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4618",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma44:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the eighteenth year of the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi ended; and also the record of_____, which was written upon the plates of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4619",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45-62",
    "question": "Chapters 45-62 comprise the account of the people of Nephi, and their wars and dissentions, in the days of Helaman, according to the record of Helaman, which he kept in his days",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4620",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass the people of_____were exceedingly rejoiced, because the Lord had again delivered them out of the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4621",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:1",
    "question": "The Nephites did not give thanks to the Lord because he had delivered them from the hands of the Nephites but made human sacrifices unto him instead.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4622",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:1",
    "question": "The Nephites did fast much and pray much, and they did worship God with exceedingly great joy because he had delivered them out of the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4623",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Alma2 came into his eldest son_____; and asked him if he believed the words which he had spoken unto him concerning the records which had been kept.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4624",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:3",
    "question": "Helaman did not believe in the words which had been spoken unto him by Alma2; concerning that which had been spoken in the records which had been kept.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4627",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:8",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he was blessed and that the Lord shall prosper him in the promise land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4628",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:9",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that he had a_____to tell him; but was not allowed to tell the people until it has been fulfilled; and to write the words which he should say.",
    "answer": "Prophecy",
    "options": ["Secret", "Prophecy", "Story"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4629",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that because he had the spirit of_____he could prophecy unto him.",
    "answer": "Revelation",
    "options": ["God", "Holy Ghost", "Revelation"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4630",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:10",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that the Nephites were going to dwindle in the Lord 400 years from the time that Jesus Christ would manifest himself unto them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4631",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:10",
    "question": "How many years did Alma2 tell Helaman the Nephites would start to dwindle in unbelief after Jesus Christ would manifest himself unto them?",
    "answer": "4 Hundred",
    "options": ["2 Hundred", "3 Hundred", "4 Hundred"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4632",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:11",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Nephites would see wars and pestilences, fam1nes and bloodshed, even until the people of_____shall become extinct.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Moses", "Nephi", "Lehi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4633",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Nephites would suffer because they would dwindle in unbelief in the word of God and fall into works of_____.",
    "answer": "Darkness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4634",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:12",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman the Nephites would suffer because they would also do all manner of iniquities and lasciviousness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4635",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:12",
    "question": "Alma2 said the Nephites would sin against so great light and_____.",
    "answer": "Knowledge",
    "options": ["Truth", "Knowledge", "Smarts"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4636",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:12",
    "question": "How many generations did Alma2 tell Helaman shall not all pass away before the great iniquity of the Nephites would come?",
    "answer": "4",
    "options": ["3", "4", "5"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4637",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:13",
    "question": "Alma2 said when the great day would come of the suffering of the people; the seed of those who are now numbered among the people of Nephi would no longer be numbered.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4638",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:14",
    "question": "Alma2 told Helaman that those few who would survive the great and dreadful day would be numbered among what tribe of people?",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Israelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4639",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said that a few would survive the great and dreadful day and would be called the_____of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Disciples",
    "options": ["Children", "Chosen", "Disciples"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4640",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said the disciples of the Lord would be pursued and killed by the Lamanites until they would also become extinct.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4641",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:14",
    "question": "Alma2 said the disciples of the Lord would be killed because of the iniquity of the people and because his_____would be fulfilled.",
    "answer": "Prophecy",
    "options": ["Revelation", "Prophecy", "Storytelling"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4642",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after Alma2 had spoken to Helaman he blessed him and his other sons; and he also blessed the_____for the righteous sake.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["Earth", "Ground", "Heavens"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4643",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:16",
    "question": "The Lord cursed the land unto every nation, kindred, tongue, and every_____, when they are fully ripe and fall into wickedness.",
    "answer": "People",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4644",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:16",
    "question": "Alma2 said the cursing and the blessing of God upon the land, is because he cannot look upon sin with the least degree of_____.",
    "answer": "Allowance",
    "options": ["Allowance", "Tolerance", "Admittance"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4645",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:17",
    "question": "After Alma2 said these things unto Helaman, he blessed the church and all those who should stand fast in the faith from that time forward.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4646",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:18",
    "question": "What was the name of the land which Alma2 departed to after he blessed his sons and all of those who would stand fast in the faith of the church?",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["Manti", "Zarahemla", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4647",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:18",
    "question": "After Alma2 departed into the land of Zarahemla he was heard preaching unto the Nephites in the land of Melek.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4648",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:18",
    "question": "After Alma2 departed into the land of Zarahemla he was never heard of anymore.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4649",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:18",
    "question": "In the Book of Ether we are told by Mormon about the burial and the death of Alma2 theYounger.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4650",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:19",
    "question": "Mormon tells us that Alma2 the Younger was a_____man; and that if was said among the people of the church that he was taken up by the Spirit.",
    "answer": "Righteous",
    "options": ["Righteous", "Holy", "Unrighteous"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4651",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:19",
    "question": "Mormon tell us that Alma2 the Younger was a righteous man and taken up by the Spirit, or buried by the Lord, even as what other prophet old times?_____",
    "answer": "Moses",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4652",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:19",
    "question": "We suppose that the Lord took Alma2 the Younger unto himself and received him in the Spirit; therefore, for this cause we know nothing concerning his_____and burial.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["Death", "Body", "Life"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4653",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the beginning of the 19th year of the reign of the judges, Helaman went forth among the people to declare the word of the Lord.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4654",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:21",
    "question": "Because the_____ had many little dissensions and disturbances among themselves; it became expedient that the word of the God should be declared among them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4655",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman and his brethren appointed_____and teachers over the churches.",
    "answer": "Priests",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4656",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma45:23",
    "question": "Because there arose a dissension among the Lamanites, they would not give heed to the words of Helaman and his brethren.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4657",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma45:24",
    "question": "The people grew proud, being lifted up in the pride of their_____, because of their exceeding great riches.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Skins", "Eyes", "Hearts"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4658",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma45:24",
    "question": "The people grew proud and rich in there own eyes, and would not give heed to_____and his brothers’ words, and walk uprightly before God.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4659",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:1,2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that those that would not hearken unto Helaman and his brethren were gathered together to battle and they were exceedingly wroth with the Nephites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4660",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:3",
    "question": "The leader of the Lamanites was a large and strong man; and his name was_____.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["Teancum", "Helorum", "Amalickiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4661",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:25",
    "question": "Amalickiah was not a Nephite by birth; but was a descendant of Ismael.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4662",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:4",
    "question": "The Lamanite leader Amalickiah was desirous to be a_____over the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "King",
    "options": ["King", "Chief", "Commander"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4663",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:4",
    "question": "Amalickiah and those that desired that he should be their king were greater than the lower judges of the land, and they were seeking for_____.",
    "answer": "Power",
    "options": ["Riches", "Power", "Jewels"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4664",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:5",
    "question": "Amalickiah led the people by flattering them, and said if he were made king he would make them_____over the people.",
    "answer": "Rulers",
    "options": ["Kings", "Rulers", "Justices"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4665",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:6",
    "question": "Amalickiah led many of the Lord’s children away from the Lord by creating dissensions among the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4666",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:6",
    "question": "During the time of Amalickiah there were not many high priests among the land preaching the word of God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4667",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:7",
    "question": "there were many people who belonged to the church who believed in the flattering words of_____.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4668",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:7",
    "question": "Because the Lord had delivered them from the Lamanites the_____had great rejoicings.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4669",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:8",
    "question": "Mormon tells us that when we forget the Lord our God, we are quick to do iniquity, and we are left to be led by_____.",
    "answer": ["Satan", "devil", "Adversary", "evil"],
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4670",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:9",
    "question": "Mormon writes that we can see the great wickedness one very wicked man can cause to take place among the children of men.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4671",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:10",
    "question": "Amalickiah was a man of cunning devices and a man of many_____words; that he led away the hearts of many people to do wicked things.",
    "answer": "Flattering",
    "options": ["Smart", "Flattering", "Cunning"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4672",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:10",
    "question": "Amalickiah and his people seeked to destroy the church of God, and to destroy the foundation of_____which God had granted unto them.",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["Liberty", "Equal Rights", "Justice"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4673",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:10",
    "question": "The foundation of liberty was granted unto the people and was also blessing from God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4674",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass when_____who was the chief commander of the armies of the Nephites, had heard of the dissensions, he was angry with Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4675",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:12",
    "question": "On what type of clothing did Moroni write the words: In memory of our God?",
    "answer": "Coat",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4676",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote inspiring words on his coat and fastened it upon the end of a_____.",
    "answer": "Pole",
    "options": ["Stick", "2 X 4", "Pole"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4677",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni fastened on his head-plate, and his_____-plate, and his shields, and girded on his armor about his loins.",
    "answer": "Breast",
    "options": ["Arm", "Leg", "Breast"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4678",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni took the pole which he had fastened to his coat and bowed himself to the earth and called it what name?",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4679",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not pray mightily unto his God for the blessings of liberty to rest upon his brethren.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4680",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni prayed for liberty for his brethren as long as there should be a band of_____remain to posses the land.",
    "answer": "Christians",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Christians"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4681",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:14",
    "question": "The true believers of Christ were called what name by those who did not belong to the church?",
    "answer": "Christians",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4682",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:15",
    "question": "The true believers in Christ took upon them, gladly, the name of Christ, or Christians, because of their belief in Christ who should come.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4683",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni prayed that the cause of the_____; and that the freedom of the land might be favored.",
    "answer": "Christians",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4684",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass Captain Moroni poured out his soul to God, and named all the land which was south of the land Desolation; a chosen land, and the land of liberty.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4685",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:18",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said the Christians were_____; because they took upon themselves the name of Christ.",
    "answer": "Despised",
    "options": ["Disowned", "Despised", "Likeable"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4686",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:19",
    "question": "When Captain Moroni had finished with his words, he went forth among the people, waving the rent part of his garment in the air.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4687",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:20",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told those who would help maintain the title of Liberty upon the land; to come forth and enter into a_____with the Lord.",
    "answer": "Covenant",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4688",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:20",
    "question": "The people covenanted with the Lord that they would help maintain their_____, and their religion, that the Lord God may bless them.",
    "answer": "Rights",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4689",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:212",
    "question": "The people came running together with their armor girded about their loins, rending their garments in token or as a covenant.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4690",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:21",
    "question": "The people covenanted that they would not forsake their God; or, and if they should fall into transgression; the Lord would rend them even as they had rent their_____.",
    "answer": "Garments",
    "options": ["Swords", "Axes", "Garments"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4691",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:22",
    "question": "After the people had covenanted with the Lord; they cast their garments upon the_____of Moroni, that if they should fall into transgression, the Lord would cast them upon the feet of their enemies.",
    "answer": "Feet",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4692",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told his people they were a remnant of the seed of what people?",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "options": ["Jacob", "Laman", "Lemuel"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4693",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told his people they were a remnant of the seed of_____, whose coat was rent by his brethren into many pieces.",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4694",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the people to remember to keep the commandments of God, or their garments should be rent by their brethren, and cast into prison, sold, or be slain.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4695",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the Nephites to preserve their liberty as a remnant of_____; and remember his words before his death.",
    "answer": "Joseph",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4696",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said Joseph saw that a part of the remnant of his coat was preserved and had not decayed.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4697",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said Joseph said that even as a remnant of his coat was preserved by the hand of the Lord; so shall the remainder of his seed shall perish, even as the remnant of his garment.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4698",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:25",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that Jacob felt no sorrow that part of his seed would perish while part of his seed would be preserved.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4699",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:25",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that Jacob was joyful because of his part of his son’s seed would be taken up unto_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4700",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:27",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the Nephites who knew what part of Joseph seed would perish and which would be taken up unto the Lord, unless they shall stand fast in the faith of_____.",
    "answer": "Christ",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4701",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Captain Moroni had finished with his words; he gathered together all the people who were desirous to maintain their liberty, to stand against_____.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4702",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:28",
    "question": "Those Nephites who had dissented and were with Amalickiah were called_____.",
    "answer": "Amalickiahites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4703",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:29",
    "question": "The_____were more numerous than the Amalickiahites, and Amalickiah feared them; therefore, he took his people with him and departed into the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4704",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:30",
    "question": "Captain Moroni knew that_____would stir up the Lamanites to anger against him and his people and to do battle with them, so that he could gain his purposes.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4705",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:31",
    "question": "Because of the things Amalickiah was doing; Captain Moroni thought it was expedient that he should take his armies, and enter into a_____to keep the peace.",
    "answer": "Covenant",
    "options": ["Treaty", "Alliance", "Covenant"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4706",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:31",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____took his army and marched out into the wilderness, to cut off the course of Amalickiah in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4707",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:33",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah fled with a small part of his army and the rest were delivered up into Captain Moroni and were taken back to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4708",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:34",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was appointed by the_____judges and the voice of the people, therefore; he had power over the armies of the Nephites to establish power and exercise authority over them.",
    "answer": "Chief",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4709",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:35",
    "question": "Captain Moroni gave the Amalickiahites prisoners the choice to enter a covenant to support the cause of freedom or to be put to death.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4710",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:35",
    "question": "And a lot of Captain Moroni’s prisoners denied to enter a covenant to support the cause of freedom and were put to death.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4711",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma46:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass Captain Moroni caused the title of_____to be hoisted upon every tower which was in all the land that was possessed by the Nephites",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4712",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:36",
    "question": "Captain Moroni planted the standard of liberty among the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Amalickiahites", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4713",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:38",
    "question": "And it came to pass the Nephites had peace in the land once again and_____and the high priests did also maintain order in the church.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["Amalickiah", "Helaman", "Zoram"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4714",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that many who died, firmly believed that their souls were redeemed by the Lord Jesus Christ; thus they went out of the world rejoicing.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4715",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:40",
    "question": "There were some of the Nephites who died with_____, which at some seasons of the year were very frequent in the land.",
    "answer": "Fevers",
    "options": ["Boils", "Fevers", "Leprosy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4716",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:40",
    "question": "The Lord had prepared excellent qualities of many plants and roots which were provided to remove the cause of_____.",
    "answer": "Disease",
    "options": ["Malaria", "Disease", "Spells"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4717",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma46:40",
    "question": "Many men were subjected to diseases because of the nature of the_____.",
    "answer": "Climate",
    "options": ["Climate", "Earth", "Sun"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4718",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma46:41",
    "question": "There were many of the Nephites who died of old age; and those who died in the faith of Jesus Christ are happy with him, as we must suppose.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4719",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:1",
    "question": "Amalickiah stirred up the Lamanites against the people of Nephi, that the king of the Lamanites sent a_____throughout the land.",
    "answer": "Proclamation",
    "options": ["Newsflash", "Text Message", "Proclamation"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4720",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:1",
    "question": "The proclamation that the king of the Lamanites sent throughout his land was for the Lamanites to gather themselves to do battle against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4721",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:2",
    "question": "The Lamanites were afraid to go to battle against the_____, and it came to pass that they would not obey the commandments of the king.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4722",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the king of the Lamanites gave_____the command of that part of his army which was obedient unto his commands.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4723",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:4",
    "question": "Amalickiah was a subtle man to do evil, therefore he laid the plan in his_____to dethrone the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Head", "Heart", "Chest"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4724",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:5",
    "question": "Amalickiah sought to gain the favor of those who were not obedient to the king of Lamanites and they were in a place called Onidah.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4725",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:6",
    "question": "The Lamanites who were afraid to go to battle against the Nephites had appointed a man to be a king and a leader over them; so that they would not be subjected to go against the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4726",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:8",
    "question": "Amalickiah’s intention was to gain favor with the armies of the Lamanites, that he might place himself at their head and dethrone the king and take possession of the_____.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["Land", "Kingdom", "Palace"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4727",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass when the night came Amalickiah sent a_____embassy into the mountain where the leader of the disenchanted Lamanites were.",
    "answer": "Secret",
    "options": ["Secret", "Delegation", "Proclamation"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4728",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:10",
    "question": "The name of the leader of the disenchanted Lamanites was called_____, and Amalickiah wanted him to come down from the mountain so that he could speak to him.",
    "answer": "Lehonti",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4729",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Lehonti came down from the mountain to speak with Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4730",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:11",
    "question": "Amalickiah sent a message",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": [
      "(1st Time) How Many Times For Lehonti To Come Down From The Mountain So That He Could Speak To Him?  1",
      "2",
      "3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "4731",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:12",
    "question": "Because Lehonti would not come down from the mountain; _____went up the mountain to speak with Lehonti.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4732",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:13",
    "question": "Amalickiah did not betray his own army so that he could become 2nd in command of a larger Lamanite army by delivering his army to Lehonti.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4733",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____came down with his men and surrounded the men of Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "Lehonti",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4734",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:15",
    "question": "Amalickiah’s men pleaded with him that he would not let the Lamanite armies destroy them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4735",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____delivered his men contrary to the commands of the king so that he could accomplish his designs in dethroning the king.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4736",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:17",
    "question": "It was not the custom among the Lamanites if their chief leader was killed, to appoint the second leader to be their chief leader.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4737",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass Amalickiah had one of his servant administer_____by small amounts to Lehonti, that he died.",
    "answer": "Poison",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4738",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:19",
    "question": "When Lehonti died; the_____appointed Amalickiah to be their leader and their chief commander.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4739",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah marched with his armies to the land of Nephi, to the city of_____, which was the chief city.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4740",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:21",
    "question": "And the king came out to meet him with his guards, for he supposed that Amalickiah had fulfilled his commands.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4741",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:22",
    "question": "As the king came out to meet him, Amalickiah caused that his_____bowed themselves before the king, as if to reverence him because of his greatness.",
    "answer": "Servants",
    "options": ["Boys", "Servants", "Body Guards"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4742",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the king put forth his hand to raise them, as was the custom with the_____, as a token of peace, which custom they had taken from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4743",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the king raised his hands, a servant of_____stabbed him in the heart and he fell to the earth.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4744",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:25,26",
    "question": "After the king fell to the ground his servants fled and the servants of Amalickiah said it was his servant that had stabbed the king.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4745",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah commanded that his armies should march forth and see what had happened to the_____.",
    "answer": "King",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4746",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:27",
    "question": "Amalickiah pretended to be angry, and said: “Whosoever loved the king, let him go forth, and pursue his servants that they may be slain”.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4747",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:29",
    "question": "The servants of the king were frightened and fled into the wilderness, and came over into the land of Zarahemla and jo1ned the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4748",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:30",
    "question": "The army which pursued the servants of the king returned empty handed; and thus_____, by his fraud, ga1ned the hearts of the people.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4749",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the queen, when she had heard that the king was slain—sent a message to Amalickiah desiring him to spare the city of Nephi and also the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4750",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:33",
    "question": "The queen desired that Amalickiah would come and see her and also wanted him to bring_____with him to testify concerning the death of the king.",
    "answer": "Witnesses",
    "options": ["Men", "Guards", "Witnesses"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4751",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:34",
    "question": "Amalickiah took the same servant that had killed the king and all others that were with him at the time and testified to the_____ that it was the king’s own servants that had killed him.",
    "answer": "Queen",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4752",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:34",
    "question": "After Amalickiah and his servants testified of how the king had been killed the queen was not satisfied with their testimonies.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4753",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:35",
    "question": "Amalickiah sought the favor of the_____, and took her unto him to marry her and make her his wife.",
    "answer": "Queen",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4754",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma47:35",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah by his fraud, and by the assistance of his cunning servants, obta1ned the_____.",
    "answer": "Kingdom",
    "options": ["Empire", "Kingdom", "Land"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4755",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:35",
    "question": "Amalickiah was made king throughout all the land, among all the people of the_____, who consisted of Lemuelites, Ishmalites, and all the dissenters of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4756",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma47:36",
    "question": "The Nephites who had dissented had been instructed in the same knowledge of the Lord became more hardened, wild, and ferocious than the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4757",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma47:36",
    "question": "The Nephites who had dissented to the Lamanites began drinking in the traditions of the Lamanites; giving way to indolence; entirely forgetting the_____ their God.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4758",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as soon as Amalickiah became the king of the Lamanites he began to appoint people to speak unto the Nephites from their towers.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4759",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:2",
    "question": "Amalickiah inspired the hearts of the Lamanites against the Nephites because he sought to_____over all the land.",
    "answer": "Reign",
    "options": ["Have Control", "Reign", "Ownership"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4760",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:2",
    "question": "Amalickiah wanted to reign over all the people that were in the land; both the_____and the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4761",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:3",
    "question": "Amalickiah accomplished his design, for he had hardened the hearts of the Lamanites and_____their minds, and stirred them up to anger against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Blinded",
    "options": ["Close", "Opened", "Blinded"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4762",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:4",
    "question": "Amalickiah was determ1ned because of the greatness of the number of his people, to overpower the_____and bring them into bondage.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4763",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:5",
    "question": "Amalickiah appointed_____as chief captains of his armies, because they were more acquainted with the strength of the Nephites, and they knew the weakest parts of their cities.",
    "answer": "Zoramites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Lemuelites", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4764",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah was obtaining his power by fraud and deceit; _____on the other hand, had been preparing the minds of the people to be faithful unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4765",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:8",
    "question": "Captain Moroni had the Nephites erecting small forts, building walls of stones, all around their borders of lands and their cities.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4766",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni place a greater amount of_____around the weakest parts of their cities.",
    "answer": "Men",
    "options": ["Forts", "Walls", "Men"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4767",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not strengthen and fortify his armies and cities which were possessed by the Nephites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4768",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni made preparations to support the liberties of the Nephites; that they might maintain that which was called by their enemies the cause of the_____.",
    "answer": "Christians",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4769",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was not a very strong and mighty man.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4770",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was a strong and mighty man; he was a man of a_____understanding; a man whose soul did have joy in the liberty and the freedom of his country.",
    "answer": "Perfect",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4771",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did also have joy because he wanted his brethren to be free from_____and slavery.",
    "answer": "Bondage",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4772",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:12",
    "question": "Moroni’s_____did swell with thanksgiving to his God, for the many privileges and blessings which he bestowed upon his people.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Head", "Heart", "Chest"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4773",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not labor exceedingly for the welfare and safety of his people.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4774",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was a man whose was firm in the_____of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "Faith",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4775",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not ever swear an oath to defend his people from their enemies.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4776",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni had sworn an oath to defend his people, his rights, and his country, and his religion, even to the loss of_____from their enemies.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Arms", "Legs", "Blood"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4777",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:14",
    "question": "The Nephites were not taught to defend themselves against their enemies, even to the shedding of blood if it were necessary.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4778",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:14",
    "question": "The Nephites were taught to never give an offense, and never to raise the_____except it were to preserve their lives.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4779",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:15",
    "question": "The Nephites had faith in their_____that he would prosper them in the land if they were faithful in keeping his commandments.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4780",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:15",
    "question": "The Nephites had faith in their God that he would prosper them in the land and to warn them to flee from their enemies, to prepare them for war, according to their danger",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4781",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:16",
    "question": "The Nephites had faith in God that he would make it know unto them where they should go to defend themselves against their_____.",
    "answer": "Enemies",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4782",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:16",
    "question": "Captain_____had faith in the Lord that he would deliver them from their enemies; and his heart did glory in it; not in the shedding of blood but in doing good.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4783",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma48:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did have joy in preserving his people and keeping the_____of God and resisting iniquity.",
    "answer": "Commandments",
    "options": ["Statues", "Commandments", "Constitution"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4784",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:17",
    "question": "Verily I say unto you, if all men had been, and were, and ever would be, like unto Moroni, behold the very powers of_____would have been shaken forever.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4785",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:17",
    "question": "Mormon writes and tells us if we were more like Captain Moroni; the_____would never have power over the hearts of the children of men.",
    "answer": "Devil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4786",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:18",
    "question": "Behold_____; was a man like unto Ammon, the son of Mosiah, and even the other sons of Mosiah, and also Alma and his sons, for they were all men of God.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4787",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:19",
    "question": "Helaman and his brethren were no less serviceable unto the people than was Captain Moroni; for they did preach the word of God, and did baptize many.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4788",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:20",
    "question": "The Nephites did humble themselves because of the words of the Lord, insomuch that they were highly favored of the_____; and did not have a war for the space of four years.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4789",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:23",
    "question": "The Nephites were sorry to take up arms against the Lamanites, because they did not delight in the shedding of_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4791",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni’s Nephites were sorrowful because of those who had dissented from their church, and had left them and had gone to destroy them by joining the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4792",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma48:25",
    "question": "Captain Moroni’s people could not bear that their brethren should rejoice over the_____of the Nephites as long as there were any who should keep the commandment of God.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4793",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:1,2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites were approaching towards the land of Ammonihah; and Captain Moroni had rebuilt the city and stationed and army there.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4794",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites though that the city of_____ would be an easy target to destroy because they had destroyed it once before.",
    "answer": "Ammonihah",
    "options": ["Nephi", "Lehi", "Ammonihah"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4795",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma48:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites had destroyed the city of Ammonihah once before because of the iniquity of the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4796",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:4",
    "question": "The Nephites had dug a ridge of _____around the city of Ammonihah and it was so high that the Lamanites’ stones and arrows could not have any effect on them.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["Rocks", "Stones", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4797",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:5",
    "question": "The chief captains of the Lamanites were not astonished exceedingly because of the wisdom of the Nephites in preparing the places of security.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4798",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:6",
    "question": "The_____supposed that they could overcome the Nephite cities because of the greatness of their numbers.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4799",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:6",
    "question": "The Lamanites prepared themselves with garments of skins, which were very thick garments to cover their nakedness.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4800",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:7",
    "question": "The_____supposed that they could easily overpower the Nephites and subject them to the yoke of bondage, or slay and massacre them according to their pleasure.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4801",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:8",
    "question": "The Nephites were very well prepared for battle against the Lamanites because of the instructions of Captain_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4802",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites; or Amalickiahites were exceedingly astonished at the manner the Nephites had prepared themselves.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4803",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:10",
    "question": "King_____did not come down from the mountain to the head of his army because he did not care for the blood of the people.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4804",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:12",
    "question": "Because of the fortifications of the Nephite city of Ammonihah, the Lamanites retreated into the_____ and marched towards the land of Noah.",
    "answer": "Wilderness",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4805",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:13",
    "question": "The chief captains of the Lamanites came forward and took an oath that they would destroy the people of the city of Noah.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4806",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:14",
    "question": "The city of Noah had been a weak city before; but to the astonishment of the Lamanites; because of the means of Captain Moroni, the city of Noah was even stronger than the city of Ammonihah",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4807",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:15",
    "question": "It was according to the desires of Captain_____ that the Lamanites were afraid of the city of Noah because it had been the weakest part of the land of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4808",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni appointed_____to be the chief captain of the city of Noah and he was the same person who fought with the Lamanites in the valley on the east of the river Sidon.",
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4809",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:17",
    "question": "The Lamanites feared the chief captain Lehi, exceedingly; nevertheless their chief captains had sworn with an_____to attack the city.",
    "answer": "Oath",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4810",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:18",
    "question": "The only way the Lamanites could enter the city of Lehi was through the entrance; because Captain Moroni had his men dug a deep ditch all away around it.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4811",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:20",
    "question": "A group of the_____men of the Nephites were prepared to defend the city of Noah with their swords and with their slings.",
    "answer": "Strongest",
    "options": ["Strongest", "Weakest", "Smartest"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4812",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:21",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the captains of the Lamanites fought with the_____before the place of the entrance of the city of Noah.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4813",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:22",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to dig down the banks of the city of Noah in order to obtain a pass to the Nephite armies.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4814",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:22",
    "question": "Instead of filling up their ditches by pulling down the banks of earth, they were filled up in a measure with the dead and_____bodies of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Wounded",
    "options": ["Hurt", "Wounded", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4815",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:23",
    "question": "The Nephites did not get an opportunity to slay all of the chief captains of the Lamanites because some of them fled.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4816",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:23",
    "question": "More than a_____of the Lamanites were slain during the battle for the city of Noah; and there was not a single soul of the Nephites slain.",
    "answer": "&&&",
    "options": ["Hundred", "Thousand", "Ton"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4817",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:24",
    "question": "There were about_____men of the Nephites’ army who were wounded during the battle of the city of Noah.",
    "answer": "50",
    "options": ["50", "60", "70"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4818",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:24",
    "question": "The 50 wounded men of the Nephites’ army were wounded in the legs but their wounds were not severe.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4819",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass, that when the Lamanites saw that all of their_____captains were killed; they fled into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Chief",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4820",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites returned to the land of Nephi, to inform their king, _____, who was a Nephite by birth, concerning their great loss.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4821",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah was exceedingly angry with his people, because he could not obtain his desires to bring the Nephites to the yoke of bondage.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4822",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:27",
    "question": "Amalickiah was exceedingly wroth but he did not curse God neither Moroni.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4823",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:27",
    "question": "Amalickiah swore with an oath that he would drink the_____of Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4824",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:27",
    "question": "Amalickiah was angry with Captain Moroni because he had kept the commandments of God in preparing for the_____of his people.",
    "answer": "&&&",
    "options": ["Good", "Safety", "Battle"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4825",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma49:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites thank the Lord their God, because of his_____power in delivering them from the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "Matchless",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4826",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma49:30",
    "question": "The Nephites had exceeding great prosperity in the_____because of their heed and diligence in the word of God.",
    "answer": "&&&",
    "options": ["Land", "Church", "Synagogues"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4827",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma49:30",
    "question": "The word of the Lord was declared unto the Nephites by Helaman, Shiblon, Corianton, and Ammon and his brethren.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4828",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____did not stop making preparations for war, or to defend his people against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4829",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that the Nephites dig heaps of earth all around their cities in the land and had timbers of the height of a_____, all around their cities.",
    "answer": "Man",
    "options": ["Woman", "Man", "Sasquatch"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4830",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that upon these works of timbers there should be a frame of pickets built upon the timbers.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4831",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused_____to be erected that overlooked those works of pickets.",
    "answer": "Towers",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4832",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused the Nephites to build places of security to be built upon those towers, that the stones of the_____could not hurt them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4833",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:6",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not prepare strongholds against the coming of the enemies of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4834",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that his armies should go forth into the east wilderness and drove all the_____that were there, into their own lands.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4835",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:8",
    "question": "The land of_____did run in a straight course from the east sea to the west.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["Mormon", "Amalickiah", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4836",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni caused that the inhabitants who were in the land of_____go forth into the east wilderness and possess the land.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4837",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni cut off all the strongholds of the Lamanites in the east wilderness and also in the west by erecting fortifications.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4838",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:11",
    "question": "The_____possessed all of the land northward, and even all the land which was northward of the land of Bountiful, according to there pleasure.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4839",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:12",
    "question": "The armies of Captain Moroni did not increase daily because of the assurance of protection which his works did bring forth unto the Nephites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4840",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites began the foundation of a city, and they called the name of the city_____and it was by the east sea.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4841",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:14",
    "question": "The Nephites also began to build a city between the city of Moroni and the city of Aaron and named it Nephihah.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4842",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:15",
    "question": "And the Nephites began to build many cities on the north, one in particular manner which they called_____which was in the north.",
    "answer": "Lehi",
    "options": ["Lehi", "Nephi", "Lamuel."]
  },
  {
    "id": "4843",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:17,18",
    "question": "The twenty and first year of the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi was exceedingly prosperous and they did multiply and were strong in the land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4844",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:19",
    "question": "Mormon writes that we can see how merciful and just are all the dealings of the Lord, to the fulfilling of all of his_____unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "Words",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4845",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:19,20",
    "question": "The Lord’s words were verified when he spoke unto Lehi that his seed would be blessed inasmuch as they shall keep his_____.",
    "answer": "Commandment",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4846",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:21",
    "question": "The Nephites were quarreling and had contentions among themselves, which brought upon them their wars and their destructions.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4847",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:21",
    "question": "Because the_____were murdering, plundering.and doing other abominations among themselves; it brought upon them their wars and destructions.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4848",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:22",
    "question": "Those who did not keep the commandments were consigned to bondage, or to perish by the_____, or to dwindle in unbelief, and mingle with the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4849",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:23",
    "question": "During the days of Captain Moroni there have never been such a happier people; even since the days of Nephi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4850",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there was a contention among the_____concerning the land of Lehi and the land of Morianton.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Ishmaelites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4851",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:26",
    "question": "The Nephites who possessed the land of Morianton did not claim a part of the land of Lehi.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4852",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people in the land of Morianton took up arms against their brethren, and they were determ1ned by the_____to slay them.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["Sword", "Knife", "Gun"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4853",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:27",
    "question": "The Nephites in the land of Lehi fled to the camp of Captain_____, and appealed unto him to assist them; for behold they were not in the wrong.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4854",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:28",
    "question": "The Nephites in the land of Morianton were led by a man named_____.",
    "answer": "Morianton",
    "options": ["Amalickiah", "Teancum", "Morianton"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4855",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:29",
    "question": "Because Morianton and his people were afraid of Captain Moroni’s army, they fled to a land that was northward, which was covered with large bodies of_____.",
    "answer": "Water",
    "options": ["Rivers", "Water", "Snakes"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4856",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:29",
    "question": "Morianton and his people did not want to take possession of the land northward which was covered with large bodies of water.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4857",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:30",
    "question": "Morianton was a man of great_____, therefore he was angry with one of his maid servants, and he fell upon her and beat her a lot.",
    "answer": "Passion",
    "options": ["Strength", "Passion", "Moxie"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4858",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:31",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the maid servant that was beaten by Morianton came over to the camp of Captain_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4859",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:31",
    "question": "Mormon never writes the name of the maid servant that was beaten by Morianton in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4860",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:31",
    "question": "The maid servant that was beaten by Morianton told Captain Moroni all things concerning Morianton and his intentions to flee into the land_____.",
    "answer": "Northward",
    "options": ["Westward", "Southward", "Northward"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4861",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:32",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was concerned that the people who were in the land of Bountiful would hearken to the words of Morianton and unite with his people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4862",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:32",
    "question": "Captain Moroni sent an army to cut off the people of Morianton and to stop their flight into the land northward.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4863",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:32",
    "question": "If the people of Morianton would unite with the people of the land of Bountiful it would not lay a foundation for serious consequences among the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4864",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:32",
    "question": "By the uniting of the people of Morianton and the people of Bountiful it would lead to the overthrow of the liberty of the people of _____.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4865",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:34",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the army of Captain Moroni cut off the peoples’ flight by the borders of the land called _____.",
    "answer": "Desolation",
    "options": ["Isolation", "Desolation", "Probation"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4866",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:34",
    "question": "The land of Desolation was by the narrow pass which led by the sea on the west and on the east.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4867",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:35",
    "question": "The army that Captain Moroni sent to cut off the peoples’ flight into the land northward was led by a man named_____.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["Teancum", "Gadianton", "Gideon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4869",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:35",
    "question": "And it came to pass that a battle commenced between both of the armies and Morianton was slain by_____.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4870",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Morianton were taken prisoners, and returned to the camp of Captain_____where they coveted to keep the peace.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4871",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:37",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Nephihah, who was the chief judge of the land died, having filled the judgment-seat with a perfect uprightness before God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4872",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:37-4:16,17",
    "question": "The chief judge Nephihah succeeded was what other chief judge of the land of Zarahemla?",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4873",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:38",
    "question": "Nephihah did not refuse Alma1 when he was asked to take possession of the sacred records and those things which were in the hands of Alma1.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4874",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Nephihah went the way of the earth and his son_____was appointed to fill the judgment-seat.",
    "answer": "Pahoran",
    "options": ["Pahoran", "Ammoron", "Jacob"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4875",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:39",
    "question": "Pahoran took an oath and sacred ordinance to judge_____, and to keep the peace, and the freedom of the people.",
    "answer": "Righteously",
    "options": ["Wrongly", "Badly", "Righteously"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4876",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma50:39",
    "question": "Pahoran took and oath to grant unto the people their sacred privileges to worship the Lord their ____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4877",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:30",
    "question": "Pahoran the chief judge did not take an oath to support and maintain the cause of God all his days, and to bring the wicked to justice according to their crime.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4878",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the 25th year of the reign of the_____, there began to be a contention among the people concerning the chief judge Pahoran.",
    "answer": "Judge",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4879",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:2",
    "question": "In the beginning of Pahoran’s reign there was a part of the people who desired that a few particular points of the_____should be altered.",
    "answer": "Law",
    "options": ["Doctr1ne", "Gospel", "Law"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4880",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:3",
    "question": "Pahoran hearkened unto the voice of the people and let some of the Nephite laws to be changed.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4881",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:4",
    "question": "Pahoran would not let some of the people to alter their laws so they became angry with him and desired that he no longer be the chief_____.",
    "answer": "Judge",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4882",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:4",
    "question": "There arose a warm dispute among the people concerning the altering of the laws of the Nephites; but not into bloodshed.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4883",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:5",
    "question": "Those that desired that Pahoran should be dethroned from the judgment-seat were called_____.",
    "answer": "Kingmen",
    "options": ["Freemen", "Kingmen", "Knights Templar"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4884",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:5",
    "question": "The king-men desired that the law should be altered in a manner to overthrow the free government and to establish a king over the land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4885",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:6",
    "question": "Those that were desirous that Pahoran should remain chief judge over the land took it upon themselves the name of_____.",
    "answer": "Freemen",
    "options": ["Rightmen", "Freemen", "Wing-men"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4886",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:6",
    "question": "The_____ had sworn or covenanted to maintain their rights and the privileges of their religion by a free government.",
    "answer": "Freemen",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4887",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the matter of their contention was settled by the voice of the people and it was in the favor of the_____.",
    "answer": "Freemen",
    "options": ["Kingmen", "Freemen", "Free Lancers"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4888",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:7",
    "question": "Because Pahoran reta1ned the judgment-seat his brethren rejoiced and also many of the people of liberty.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4889",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:7",
    "question": "Because of the victory of the voice of the people; the king-men did not dare oppose the law and were obliged to maintain the cause of_____.",
    "answer": "Freedom",
    "options": ["Freedom", "Liberty", "God"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4890",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:8",
    "question": "Those who were in favor of kings were those of high birth, and they sought to be_____.",
    "answer": "Kings",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4891",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:8",
    "question": "The king-men sought to be kings over the land and they were supported by those who sought power and authority of the people.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4892",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:9",
    "question": "During the time of the king-men and freemen it was a critical time for the_____because Amalickiah was gathering together soldiers to fight with them.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Nephites", "Zoramites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4893",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:11",
    "question": "Amalickiah and his armies were not as great as they once were; nevertheless, he feared not to come down to the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["Zarahemla", "Mormon", "Waters Of Mormon"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4894",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____the chief captain of the Lamanite armies did come down at the head of his armies.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4895",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the king-men heard that the Lamanites were coming down to battle against the Nephites, they were glad in their_____.",
    "answer": "Hearts",
    "options": ["Heads", "Hearts", "Brains"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4896",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:13",
    "question": "The_____refused to take up arms against the Lamanites because they were angry with the chief judge, and also with the people of liberty.",
    "answer": "King",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4897",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:13",
    "question": "The king-men liked their chief judge Pahoran so much that they were more than glad to take up arms in defense of their country.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4898",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:14",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was exceedingly wroth with the people whom he had labored with so much diligence to preserve.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4899",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:14",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was exceedingly wroth at the people that his_____ was filled with anger against them.",
    "answer": "Soul",
    "options": ["Heart", "Soul", "Chest"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4900",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni sent a_____, with the voice of the people, unto the governor of the land.",
    "answer": "Petition",
    "options": ["Declaration", "Petition", "Text Message"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4901",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:15",
    "question": "Captain Moroni’s petition would give him power to compel those dissenters to defend their country or to put them to death.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4902",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:16",
    "question": "Contentions and_____among the Nephites had been a cause of all their destruction.",
    "answer": "Dissensions",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4903",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____was granted according to the petition of the voice of the people.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4904",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni commanded that his army should go against those king-men, to pull down their pride and nobility and level them with the earth.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4905",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma18,19",
    "question": "Captain Moroni’s army defeated the king-men with the sword and those that were not slain in battle were taken prisoners.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4906",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:19",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there was_____thousand of those dissenters who were hewn down with the sword.",
    "answer": "Four",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4907",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:19",
    "question": "Those dissenters who were taken prisoners were not given trials right away because of the time period the Nephites were in with the armies of Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4908",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:20",
    "question": "The remainder of the dissenters were compelled to hoist and yield the title of_____upon their towers, and in their cities, and to take up arms in defense of their country.",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4909",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:21",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni put an end to the king-men and their pride in professing their_____.",
    "answer": "Nobility",
    "options": ["Freedom", "Nobility", "Rights"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4910",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:21",
    "question": "The dissenters were brought down to humble themselves like unto their brethren, and to fight valiantly for their freedom from bondage.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4911",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that while Captain Moroni was taking care of the affairs of the_____and subjecting them to peace and civilization, the Lamanites came down to the land of Moroni.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4912",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:23",
    "question": "Amalickiah defeated the armies of Captain Moroni in the city of Moroni because they were not sufficiently strong and were driven from it.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4913",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:24",
    "question": "And those who were not driven out of the city of Moroni fled to the city of Nephihah, and also the people of the city of Lehi gathered themselves together to battle.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4914",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____the chief Lamanite commander would not suffer his armies to go against the people of the city of Nephihah.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4915",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Amalickiah took possession of all of the Nephite cities that were on the east borders by the seashore.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4916",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:27",
    "question": "And thus the Lamanites obta1ned, by the cunning of_____, so many cities by their numberless hosts which were strongly fortified after the manner of the fortifications of Moroni.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4917",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the armies of Amalickiah marched to the borders of the land Bountiful, driving the_____before them and slaying many.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4918",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:29",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the armies of Amalickiah were met with the army of_____; who was the same person who had slain Morianton in battle.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4919",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:30",
    "question": "Amalickiah was marching forth with army that he might take possession of the land of Bountiful and also the land northward.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4920",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:31",
    "question": "Amalickiah was met with a disappointment by being repulsed by_____and his men because they were great warriors.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4921",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:31",
    "question": "Teancum men did exceed the_____in their strength and in their skill of war, insomuch that they did gain advantage over the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Nephites", "Lamanites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4922",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the night came Teancum and his _____went out in the night to the camp of Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "Servant",
    "options": ["Maid", "Servant", "Assistant"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4923",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:33",
    "question": "Amalickiah and his men were overcome with sleep because of their fatigue; which was caused by the labors and_____of the day.",
    "answer": "Heat",
    "options": ["Heat", "Humidity", "Partying"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4924",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:34",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Teancum went privily into the tent of Amalickiah and put a_____into his heart; and did cause the death of him immediately that he did not awake his servants.",
    "answer": "Javelin",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4925",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma51:34",
    "question": "What kind of weapon of war did Teancum use to slay king Amalickiah?",
    "answer": "Javelin",
    "options": ["Sword", "Spear", "Javelin"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4926",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:36",
    "question": "It is interesting to note that the word “javelin” only appears how many times in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "1",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4927",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma51:35",
    "question": "And_____returned to his own camp and his men were asleep, and he awoke them and told them all the things which he had done.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4928",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma51:37",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the 25th year of the reign of the judges over the people came to pass and so did the days of Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4929",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma50:35,51:34,62:36",
    "question": "Teancum is known not only for being a great Nephite warrior but also because he killed three prom1nent Lamanite leaders which were; Morianton, Amalickiah, and Ammoron.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4930",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:2",
    "question": "When the Lamanites awoke and saw that Amalickiah was dead they abandoned their design in marching into the land northward, and retreated into the city of Mulek.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4931",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the brother of Amalickiah was appointed king over the Lamanites and his name was_____.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4932",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma52:4",
    "question": "Ammoron did command that his people should maintain those cities which they had taken by the shedding of much_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Sweat", "Blood", "Skin"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4933",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:5",
    "question": "Because of the numerous Lamanite armies Teancum thought it was not expedient that he should attempt to attack_____and his men in their forts.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4934",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Teancum kept preparing himself and his army for war until Captain_____sent a large number of men to strengthen his army.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4935",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:8",
    "question": "Captain Moroni sent orders unto_____that he should retain all the prisoners who fell into his hands as a ransom for those whom the Lamanites had taken prisoner.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4936",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not send orders unto Teancum that he should be faithful in maintaining the land Bountiful and should not seek every opportunity to scourge the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4937",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma52:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni sent orders unto Teancum that he might take again by_____or some other way those cities which had been taken out of their hands.",
    "answer": "Stratagem",
    "options": ["Stratagem", "Cunning Or (c) Bribery"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4938",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:12",
    "question": "King Ammoron had departed out of the land of Zarahemla, and had made it known unto the_____concerning the death of his brother.",
    "answer": "Queen",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4939",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:13",
    "question": "Ammoron endeavored to harass the Nephites in every border which they possessed and to draw away a part of their forces.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4940",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni sent orders unto_____that he should make an attack upon the city of Mulek and retake it if it were possible.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4941",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:17",
    "question": "Teancum made preparations to attack the city of Mulek but because it was well fortified he abandon his designs and returned to the city of Bountiful.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4942",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma52:19",
    "question": "Captain Moroni and Teancum and many of the chief captains of the Nephites held a council of_____.",
    "answer": "War",
    "options": ["Thanksgiving", "War", "Peace"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4943",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:19",
    "question": "The council of war that Captain Moroni and Teancum held was so they could by some means flatter the Lamanites out of their strongholds and come to battle against them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4944",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Captain Moroni and his council sent embassies to the army of the Lamanites which protected the city of Mulek; and his name was Jacob.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4945",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:20",
    "question": "Jacob was the leader of the Lamanites who protected the city of Mulek and he was a_____and would not come out with his army to meet the Nephites upon the plains.",
    "answer": "Zoramite",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4946",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:21",
    "question": "Captain Moroni had high hopes that Jacob the Zoramite would meet them upon the plains which were fair grounds for a battle of war.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4947",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:22",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that_____and a small number of his men should march down to the seashore to provide a decoy for Jacob and his men.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4948",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:24",
    "question": "The guards of the_____discovered Teancum and his men and went and told Jacob their leader, and they took courage and pursued them with vigor because of their small numbers.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4949",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:25",
    "question": "While Teancum and his men were leading the Lamanites away from the city of Mulek; Captain_____went with his army and took possession of it and slew all those who had been left to protect it.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4950",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____did pursue Teancum until they came near the city of Bountiful, and then they were met by Lehi and a small army.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4951",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:28",
    "question": "When the Lamanites saw Lehi and his army coming against them they fled in confusion; because they were worn out because of their march, and the men of Lehi were fresh.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4952",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:30",
    "question": "Lehi and his army were desirous that they should overtake the Lamanites until they should meet Captain Moroni and his men.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4953",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____commanded his men that they should fall upon Jacob and his men and give them battle until they had given up their weapons of war.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4954",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma52:33",
    "question": "Because Jacob was a Zoramite and had an unconquerable_____, he led the Lamanites forth to battle with exceeding fury against Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["Demeanor", "Spirit", "Body"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4955",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:35",
    "question": "Jacob was determ1ned to cut his way through to the city of Mulek but Captain Moroni and his men were more powerful; and they fought with exceeding fury on both sides.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4956",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:35",
    "question": "During the battle with Jacob and his men; Captain Moroni was wounded and_____was killed.",
    "answer": "Jacob",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4957",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:36",
    "question": "Lehi and his men pressed upon the Lamanites in the rear with such fury with his strong men, that they were confused and knew not whether to go or to strike.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4958",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:37",
    "question": "Captain Moroni saw that the Lamanites were confused and said if they would deliver up their weapons of war they would forbear in shedding of their_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4959",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:38",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the chief captains of the Lamanites who were not slain came forth and threw down their weapons of war at the feet of Captain_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4960",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma52:39",
    "question": "There were many of the Lamanites who refused to lay down their weapons of_____and they were bound and their weapons of war were taken from them.",
    "answer": "War",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4961",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma52:40",
    "question": "The number of the Lamanites who were taken prisoners did not exceed the number that had been slain in battle on both sides.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4962",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanite prisoners were compelled to go forth and bury their dead and also the dead of the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4963",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni placed_____over the Lamanites while they should perform their labors.",
    "answer": "Guards",
    "options": ["Guards", "Servants", "Women"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4964",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni went to the city of Mulek with Lehi, and took command of the city and gave it to Lehi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4965",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:2",
    "question": "Lehi was a man who had been with Captain_____in the more part of all his battles; and he was a man like unto Moroni.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4966",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:2",
    "question": "Lehi and Captain Moroni rejoiced in each others safety and they were beloved by each other and also by all the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4967",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni caused that the Lamanite prisoners should commence in laboring in digging a ditch around the land, or the city, Bountiful.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4968",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that the_____prisoners build a breastwork of timbers and earth to encircle the city of Bountiful to an exceeding height.",
    "answer": "Lamanite",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4969",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the city of Bountiful became a stronghold ever after.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4970",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:5",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was compelled to cause the Lamanites to labor, because it was easy to guard them while they performed their labors.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4971",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni ga1ned a victory over one of the greatest of the_____armies and also of the city of Mulek which was one of their strongholds.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4972",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:6",
    "question": "The city of Mulek was one of the strongest holds of the Lamanites in the land of_____and Captain Moroni made it a stronghold to retain his prisoners.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4973",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did employ his men in delivering their women and their children from fam1ne and affliction, and providing_____for their armies.",
    "answer": "Food",
    "options": ["Shelter", "Food", "Rum"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4974",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the armies of the Lamanites did take possession of some of the cities of the Nephites in the absence of Captain_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4975",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:8",
    "question": "The reason some of the cities of the Nephites were taken over was because there was dissensions among them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4976",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:9",
    "question": "Because of iniquities amongst themselves; their dissensions and intrigue among themselves placed the_____in the most dangerous circumstances.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4977",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:10",
    "question": "The intrigue of the Nephites was because the people of Ammon, who in the beginning, were_____ refused to take up arms against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4978",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:10",
    "question": "The people of Ammon had been converted unto the Lord; and they had been brought down to the land of Zarahemla, and had ever since been protected by the Nephites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4979",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:11",
    "question": "According to the_____the people of Ammon had taken they would never shed the blood of their brethren anymore; or they would perish.",
    "answer": "Oath",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4980",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:11",
    "question": "The people of_____ would have suffered themselves to have fallen into the hands of their brethren, had it not been for the love which Ammon and his brethren had had for them.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4981",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:13",
    "question": "The people of Ammon saw the danger and the many afflictions and tribulations which the Nephites bore for them and they were moved with compassion.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4982",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:13",
    "question": "Because the people of_____were moved with compassion for the Nephites; they were desirous to take up arms in the defense of their country.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4983",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:14",
    "question": "The people of Ammon were overpowered by the persuasions of Helaman and his_____, and they were about to break the oath that they had made.",
    "answer": "Brethren",
    "options": ["Sisters", "Wives", "Brethren"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4984",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:15",
    "question": "Helaman feared that the people of Ammon would lose their_____if they were to break the oath they had made concerning the taking up of arms against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4985",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Ammon had many sons who had not entered into a covenant that they would not take their weapons of war to defend themselves.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4986",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:17",
    "question": "The sons of the people of_____entered into a covenant to fight for the liberty of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4987",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:17",
    "question": "The sons of the people of Ammon entered a covenant that they never would give up their_____, but they would fight in all cases to protect the Nephites and themselves from bondage.",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4988",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:18",
    "question": "Now behold, there were_____thousand of those young men, who entered into this covenant and took their weapons of war to defend their country.",
    "answer": "Two",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4989",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:19",
    "question": "The two thousands sons of the people of Ammon desired that_____be their leader.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["Captain Moroni", "Helaman", "Amalickiah"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4990",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma53:20",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of Helaman were all_____men, and they were exceedingly valiant in courage, and also for strength and activity.",
    "answer": "Young",
    "options": ["Tall", "Skinny", "Young"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4991",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:20",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of Helaman were men who were true at all times in whatsoever thing they were entrusted.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4992",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:21",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of_____were men of truth and soberness, for they had been taught to keep the commandments of God and to walk uprightly before him.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4993",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:21",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of Helaman were men of craft1ness and cunning, who were taught to take advantage of anyone when the opportunity arose.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4994",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____did march at the head of his two thousand stripling soldiers.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4995",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:22",
    "question": "The two thousand young men of Helaman were known as the two thousand_____soldiers of Helaman.",
    "answer": "Stripling",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4996",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____, king of the Lamanites sent a message unto Captain Moroni desiring to exchange prisoners.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4997",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:2",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni was not happy and did not feel to rejoice exceedingly because of the request of king Ammoron.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4998",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:3",
    "question": "The Lamanites had taken many women and children as prisoners, and there was not a woman neither a child among all the prisoners of Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "4999",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:3",
    "question": "One of the differences between the Nephites armies and the Lamanites armies; is that the Nephites never took women or children as prisoners.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5000",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni resolved upon a_____to obtain as many prisoners of the Nephites from the Lamanites as it were possible.",
    "answer": "Stratagem",
    "options": ["Stratagem", "Spell", "Trick"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5001",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote an_____, and sent it by the servant of Ammoron, the same servant who had brought an epistle to him.",
    "answer": "Epistle",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5002",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:5",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote concerning the war that Ammoron and his brother_____had waged against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Amilickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5003",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:6",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote concerning the justice of God, and the sword of his almighty wrath, except Ammoron and the Lamanites would repent.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5004",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told Ammoron that an awful_____awaited to receive such murderers as him and his brother.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["Death", "Hell", "Trial"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5005",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni thought that Ammoron was not capable of hearkening unto his words",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5006",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked_____to repent and withdraw his murderous purposes, and return with his armies to their own lands.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5007",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:8",
    "question": "Ammoron rejected the request of Captain Moroni; and he had fought against the people of the_____, and Captain Moroni knew that he would do it again.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5008",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni and his armies were not prepared to receive Ammoron and his armies except he would withdraw his purposes.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5009",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to Ammoron the he would pull down the wrath of that_____who he had rejected upon him, even to his utter destruction.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5010",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that he and his armies would retain their cities and their lands; and would maintain their_____and the cause of their God.",
    "answer": "Cities",
    "options": ["Lands", "Cities", "Churches"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5011",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni supposed that his words to Ammoron were in vain and he supposed that Ammoron was a child of_____.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5012",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni closed his_____to Ammoron by telling him that he would not exchange prisoners.",
    "answer": "Epistle",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5013",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni closed his epistle to Ammoron by telling him that he would exchange prisoners of war.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5014",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that if Ammoron would exchange a man and his wife and his children for one prisoner, he would do it.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5015",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said he would arm his women and his_____and he himself would come against Ammoron and follow him into his own land.",
    "answer": "Children",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5016",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told Ammoron that he would follow him into his own land and it shall be blood for____; and he would give him battle even until he was destroyed from the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5017",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma53:13",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told Ammoron that he was angry because he sought to murder him and his people and they had only sought to defend themselves.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5018",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma53:13",
    "question": "Moroni said that if_____seeked to destroy him and his people he would seek to destroy him, and would follow him into the land of their first inheritance.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5019",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:14",
    "question": "Moroni closed his epistle to Ammoron by writing that his name was Moroni and that he was the_____of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Leader",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5020",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:15",
    "question": "When Ammoron received the epistle from Moroni he was not angry.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5021",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:15",
    "question": "Ammoron was angry when he received the epistle that Moroni had written unto him; and he wrote another_____unto Moroni.",
    "answer": "Epistle",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5022",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:16",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote another epistle unto Moroni informing him that he was the king of the Lamanites and was the brother of_____who he accused Moroni of murdering.",
    "answer": "Amalickiah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5023",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:16",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote that he would avenge the_____of Amalickiah and would come upon Moroni with his armies.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Name", "Blood", "Honor"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5024",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:16",
    "question": "Ammoron feared the so called threatening's of Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5025",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:17",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote that Moroni’s fathers did wrong their brethren, insomuch that they did rob them of their right to the_____when it rightly belonged to them.",
    "answer": "Government",
    "options": ["Vote", "Government", "Kingdom"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5026",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:18",
    "question": "Ammoron told Moroni if they would lay down their weapons and subject themselves to be governed by those whom the government rightly belong to, he would stop the war.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5027",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:20",
    "question": "Ammoron did not grant Moroni to the exchange of prisoners according to the way he had requested.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5028",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:20",
    "question": "Ammoron gladly granted Moroni his request to the exchange of prisoners so that he could preserve his food for his men of_____.",
    "answer": "War",
    "options": ["War", "Liberty", "Beauty"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5029",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:21",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote that he would wage a war which shall be eternal, either to the subjecting the_____to their authority or to their eternal extinction.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5030",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:21",
    "question": "Ammoron said that he knew that there was no such being as a God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5031",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma54:21",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote that if there was such a being as a God; they knew not, but that he had made him and his people as well as the Nephites",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5032",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma54:22",
    "question": "Ammoron said if there was such a thing as a devil and a_____; he would also send Moroni there to dwell with his brother who he had murdered.",
    "answer": "Hell",
    "options": ["Heaven", "Hell", "Bad Planet"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5033",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:23",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote to Moroni by saying that he was a descendant of_____, whom his fathers pressed and brought out of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Zoram",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5034",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:23",
    "question": "Ammoron wrote to Moroni by saying that he was a descendant of Zoram, whom his fathers pressed and brought out of the city of_____.",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5035",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma54:24",
    "question": "Ammoron said that he was a bold_____; and that this war had been waged to avenge the wrongs of the Lamanites, and to maintain and to obtain their rights to the government.",
    "answer": "Lamanite",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5036",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Captain Moroni received the latest epistle from Ammoron he was angrier than the first time.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5037",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was angry because he knew_____had a perfect knowledge of his fraud.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["Zoram", "Amalickiah", "Ammoron"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5038",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni knew that Ammoron did not have a just cause that had caused him to wage a war against the people of_____.",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5039",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni would not exchange prisoners with Ammoron unless he would withdraw his purpose as he had stated previously in his_____.",
    "answer": "Epistle",
    "options": ["Letter", "Proclamation", "Epistle"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5040",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni would not grant unto_____any more power that he had already had by uniting the forces of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5041",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said he knew where the Lamanites had his people and if Ammoron would not grant him his wishes, he would seek death among them until they would sue for peace.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5042",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni caused that a search should be made among his men that perhaps he might find a man who was a descendant of_____ among them.",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lemuel", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5043",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni found a man who was a descendant of Laman and his name was_____; and he was one of the servants of the king who was murdered by Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5044",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:5",
    "question": "Laman was not a servant of the king who was murdered by Amalickiah.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5045",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni knew the name of the city where the Lamanites had his people prisoners and he caused that Laman and a small number of his men should go to the city of Gid.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5046",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:8",
    "question": "Laman went and told the Lamanites who were guarding the people of Captain Moroni that he was a_____; and had escaped from them.",
    "answer": "Lamanite",
    "options": ["Lamanite", "Zoramite", "Ishmaelite"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5047",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:8",
    "question": "Laman told the Lamanites that not only had he escaped from the Nephites but he had also taken some of their_____.",
    "answer": "W1ne",
    "options": ["Swords", "W1ne", "Sacred Scriptures"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5048",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:9",
    "question": "The Lamanites received Laman with joy and wanted to drink from his w1ne because they were_____.",
    "answer": "Weary",
    "options": ["Lamanites", "Weary", "Happy"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5049",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:10",
    "question": "Laman told the Lamanites that they should save there_____and keep it until they went to battle and that made them more desirous to drink it.",
    "answer": "W1ne",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5050",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:12",
    "question": "Laman did not give the Lamanites a choice of when they were to drink the w1ne he had taken from the Nephites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5051",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass the Lamanites drank of the w1ne freely; and it was_____to their taste because it was strong, having been prepared in its strength.",
    "answer": "Pleasant",
    "options": ["Pleasant", "Awful", "Bitter"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5052",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites did not drink of the w1ne and were not merry and by and by they all did not become drunk.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5053",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:15",
    "question": "When Laman and his men saw the Lamanites had become drunk and had fallen asleep, they returned to Captain_____and told him all the things that had happened.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5054",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni did not plan that the Lamanites drink of the Nephites w1ne so that they would become drunk and fall asleep.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5055",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:16",
    "question": "Captain_____prepared his men with weapons and had them give them to the prisoners that were in the city of Gid so they could fight the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5057",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:18",
    "question": "Captain Moroni could have awakened the Lamanites who were drunk and slayed them; but he did not delight in murder or bloodshed.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5058",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:19",
    "question": "Captain Moroni delighted in the saving of his people from destruction; and for this cause he did not have the Lamanites slain, because it would bring an injustice upon him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5060",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:23",
    "question": "When the Lamanites saw the predicament they were in they brought their weapons of war to the feet of the Nephites and pleaded for_____.",
    "answer": "Mercy",
    "options": ["Forgiveness", "Mercy", "Repentance"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5061",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites who were in the city of Gid surrendered to Captain_____and those Nephites who were once prisoners jo1ned his army and it was a great strength to it.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5062",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni had the Lamanite prisoners’ labor in strengthening the fortifications of the city of Gid and Bountiful.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5063",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____began again to be victorious, and to reclaim their rights and privileges.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5064",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:29,30",
    "question": "The Lamanites tried many times to encircle the Nephites with their armies and attempted to administer their w1ne to them to poison them or get them drunk.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5065",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:31",
    "question": "The Nephites were slow to remember the Lord their God in this time of affliction and could be taken in the snares of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5066",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma55:32",
    "question": "The Nephites were cautious that no poison should be administered among them; for if their w1ne would poison a Lamanite it would also poison a_____.",
    "answer": "Nephite",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5067",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma55:33",
    "question": "The Lamanites were continually bringing new forces into the city of Morianton; and because of their labors it had made it an exceeding stronghold.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5068",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:1",
    "question": "Captain_____received an epistle from Helaman stating the affairs of the people in that quarter of the land.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5069",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:2",
    "question": "Helaman referred to Captain Moroni as a dearly beloved brother of his.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5070",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:3",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni concerning the two thousand men whom Ammon brought down from the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5071",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:3",
    "question": "The two thousand stripling warriors of Helaman were descendants of what son of Lehi?",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "options": ["Laman", "Lemuel", "Nephi"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5072",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:4",
    "question": "Helaman knew that Captain Moroni knew concerning the_____or the unbelief of the two thousand stripling warriors.",
    "answer": "Traditions",
    "options": ["Ceremonies", "Traditions", "Religion"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5073",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:5",
    "question": "Helaman wanted Captain Moroni to know that the two thousand young men have taken their weapons of war, and wanted him to be their_____.",
    "answer": "Leader",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5074",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:6",
    "question": "Helaman said that the two thousand stripling warrior’s fathers’ had made a covenant that they would not take their_____of war, and take them up against their brethren to shed blood.",
    "answer": "Weapons",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5075",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:8",
    "question": "Helaman would not let his stripling warriors break the covenant which they had made, supposing_____would strengthen them and himself.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5076",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:9",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni that they should have joy in the fact that he had marched in front of his two thousand warriors to assist Antipus in the city of Judea.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5077",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:10",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni that his two thousand warriors were not worthy to be called his sons.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5078",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:11",
    "question": "Antipus’ army had been reduced by the Lamanites because their forces had slain a vast number of them; nevertheless they had died in the cause of their country and their_____.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5079",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:12",
    "question": "The Lamanites had reta1ned many_____, all of whom are chief captains.",
    "answer": "Prisoners",
    "options": ["Prisoners", "Women", "Men"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5080",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:16",
    "question": "Helaman wrote to Captain Moroni and said that many Nephites were depressed in body as well as in_____.",
    "answer": "Spirit",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5081",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:16",
    "question": "Helaman said that many of the Nephite had fought valiantly by day and toiled by night to maintain their cities and had suffered great afflictions of every kind.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5082",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:18",
    "question": "The Lamanites were determ1ned to conquer the city of Judea or die; but because Antipus had received more help they were order by_____not to come against it.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5083",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:19",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni that they were not favored of the Lord because the Lamanites had come upon them in their weakest point and they had been preserved.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5084",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites kept_____all around the cities that they mainta1ned to watch the movements of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Spies",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5085",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:25",
    "question": "The Lamanites did not dare to march down against the city of Zarahemla; neither did they dare cross the head of the river_____, over to the city of Nephihah.",
    "answer": "Sidon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5086",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma55:27",
    "question": "Helaman was brought many provisions from the fathers of those_____thounsand men.",
    "answer": "2",
    "options": ["2", "3", "4"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5087",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:28",
    "question": "Helaman received help with the aid of two thousand men from the land of Zarahemla; therefore his was prepared to fight the Lamanites with ten thousand men.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5088",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:29",
    "question": "The Lamanites began to fear_____and his army because of the many provision brought unto his army and also because his army was increasing daily.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5089",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:34",
    "question": "The city of Antiparah was stationed by the_____army of the Lamanites and the most numerous.",
    "answer": "Strongest",
    "options": ["Weakest", "Strongest", "Largest"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5090",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:35,36",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites came forth with their army against Helaman and his army and they did lead away the most powerful army of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5091",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:37",
    "question": "The Lamanites pursued Helaman and his army even though they were being pursued in the rear by the army of_____.",
    "answer": "Antipus",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5092",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:38",
    "question": "Because Antipus could see the danger Helaman and his army were in; he speedily marched his army forward but could not overtake the Lamanites because it was nightfall.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5093",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:39",
    "question": "And it came to pass that before the dawn of the morning the_____ were pursuing Helaman and his two thousand stripling warriors.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5095",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:45",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni that he had never seen so great of courage among the_____as he had seen among his two thousand stripling warriors.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5096",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma56:46",
    "question": "Helaman's warriors said unto him:  “_____, behold our God is with us, and he will not suffer that we should fall”.",
    "answer": "Father",
    "options": ["Daddy", "Captain", "Father"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5097",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:47",
    "question": "Helaman’s stripling warriors were seasoned fighters because of all the previous battles they had been through.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5098",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:47",
    "question": "Helaman’s stripling warriors did not fear_____ and they did think more upon the liberty of their fathers than they did upon their own lives.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5099",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:47",
    "question": "The two thousand stripling warriors had been taught by their_____, that if they did not doubt, God would deliver them.",
    "answer": "Mothers",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5100",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:48",
    "question": "Helaman’s warriors rehearsed unto him the words of their mothers, saying:  “We do not doubt our_____knew it”.",
    "answer": "Mothers",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5101",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:50",
    "question": "The army of Antipus would have fallen unto the Lamanites had it not been for the return and help of_____and his stripling warriors.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5102",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:51",
    "question": "Antipus had fallen by the sword, and many of his leaders because of their wear1ness of the speed of their march and the rest of his army became confused and give way into the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5103",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:52",
    "question": "The Lamanites took courage because of the fall of Antipus and started to pursue the Nephites.  And when they saw_____and his warriors they turned around and pursued them.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5104",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:54",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the people of Nephi, the people of Antipus, and Helaman and his warriors surrounded the army of the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5105",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:54",
    "question": "Because the Lamanite were surrounded on all sides, they were compelled to deliver up their weapons of_____and also themselves as prisoners of war.",
    "answer": "War",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5106",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:55,56",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman began to count how many of his stripling warriors had fallen by the sword that had fought with him; and to his great surprise, none had been killed.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5107",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma56:56",
    "question": "Only ten stripling warriors that had fought with Helaman had been slain in battle.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5108",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma56:56",
    "question": "Because of the miraculous strength and such mighty power of the stripling warriors, it caused the_____to deliver themselves up as prisoners of war.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5109",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman received an epistle from _____the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5110",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:1",
    "question": "The epistle stated that if Helaman would deliver up those prisoners of war whom he had taken, he would deliver up the city of Antiparah unto him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5111",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:2",
    "question": "Helaman sent an epistle unto Ammoron saying that he was sure that he had sufficient forces to take the city of Antiparah.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5112",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:3",
    "question": "Ammoron refused the_____from Helaman, and he would not exchange prisoners; therefore Helaman began to make preparations to go against the city of Antiparah.",
    "answer": "Epistle",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5113",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman received a supply of provisions and also an addition of six thousand men to his army.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5114",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:6",
    "question": "Helaman received an additional_____men of the sons of the Ammonites who had come to join their brethren; the two thousand stripling warriors of Helaman.",
    "answer": "60",
    "options": ["40", "50", "60"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5115",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:9",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____and his army camped around the city of Cumeni for many nights; and Lamanites attempted many times to come upon Helaman but were held back.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5116",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:10",
    "question": "Helaman and his army stole the provisions the Lamanite army were about to receive; but the Lamanites were still determ1ned to take the city of Cumeni.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5117",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites began to lose all hopes of succor; therefore they yielded up the city into the hands of_____and his army.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5118",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:13",
    "question": "Because Helaman’s prisoners were so numerous, he was obligated to employ all his forces to keep them, or to put them to_____.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["Work", "Death", "Sing"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5119",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:14",
    "question": "The Lamanite prisoners would break out in great numbers and would fight Helaman and his army with anything they could get their hands on.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5120",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:14",
    "question": "Because of the many attempted breakouts by the Lamanites; Helaman and his army killed upwards of two thousand of them after they had surrendered themselves prisoners of war",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5121",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:15",
    "question": "It became expedient for Helaman and his army that they should put an end to the lives of the_____, or guard them; sword in hand, down to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5122",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:16",
    "question": "Because of the critical circumstances Helaman and his army were in; it became a very serious matter to determ1ne what to do with his prisoners of war.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5123",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Ammoron sent to the support of the prisoners of war more provisions and also a numerous army of_____.",
    "answer": "Men",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5124",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:19",
    "question": "Helaman and his little band of two thousand and sixty fought very desperately and they were firm before the_____, and did administer death unto all that opposed them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5125",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:19",
    "question": "Helaman’s army of two thousand and sixty did not obey and observe to perform every word of command with exactness.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5126",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:21",
    "question": "Helaman did not remember the words which his two thousand stripling warriors said unto him concerning what their mothers had taught them.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5127",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____and his army did retain the city of Cumeni and were not all destroyed by the sword, but they did suffer a great loss of men.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5128",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:24",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after the Lamanites had fled, Helaman immediately gave_____that his men who had been wounded should be taken from among the dead.",
    "answer": "Orders",
    "options": ["Orders", "Commands", "Gestures"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5129",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:25",
    "question": "And it came to pass that there were_____hundred, out of Helaman’s two thousand and sixty, who had fainted because of the loss of blood.",
    "answer": "Two",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5130",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:25",
    "question": "Two hundred out of Helaman’s two thousand and sixty, fainted because of the loss of_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5131",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:25",
    "question": "Because of the goodness of God, and to Helaman’s astonishment, there was not one soul of them who did perish; neither was there one soul among them who had not received many wounds.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5132",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:26",
    "question": "The preservation of the stripling warriors was astonishing to Helaman’s whole army because they had been spared; while a thousand of their brethren had been slain.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5133",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:26",
    "question": "Helaman justly ascribe the survival of the stripling warriors to the miraculous power of_____, because of their exceeding faith in that which they had been taught to believe.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5134",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:26",
    "question": "The stripling warriors had been taught to believe that there was a just God, and whosoever did not doubt, that they should be preserved by his marvelous power.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5135",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:27",
    "question": "Helaman said that the stripling warriors were young, and their minds _____; and they do put their trust in God continually.",
    "answer": "Firm",
    "options": ["Sluggish", "Firm", "Awful"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5136",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:28",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman inquired of Gid concerning the prisoners whom they had started to go down to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5137",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:29",
    "question": "Gid was the_____captain over the band who was appointed to guard the Lamanite prisoners of war down to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Chief",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5138",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:32",
    "question": "Gid told Helaman that the Lamanite prisoners of war had heard the cries of his spies and took courage, and did rise up in rebellion against him and his band.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5139",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:33",
    "question": "Gid told Helaman that because of the rebellion of the Lamanite prisoners; he caused that their_____should come upon them.",
    "answer": "Swords",
    "options": ["Swords", "Arrows", "Javelins"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5140",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:33",
    "question": "Gid told_____that the Lamanite prisoners came in one body against their swords and many were killed and the remainder of them broke through and fled from them.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5141",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma57:35",
    "question": "Gid told Helaman that the Lord once again had preserved him and brethren out of the hands of their enemies.  And blessed is the name of our God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5142",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma57:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass when Helaman heard the words of_____, he was filled with joy because of the goodness of God in preserving them that they might not all perish.",
    "answer": "Gid",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5143",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma57:36",
    "question": "Helaman said that he had_____in God that the souls of those who have been slain have entered into the rest of their God.",
    "answer": "Trust",
    "options": ["Confidence", "Trust", "Belief"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5144",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:1",
    "question": "Helaman tried to trick or decoy the Lamanites away from their strongholds in the city of Manti but he could not because they remembered what he had done before to them",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5145",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____sent an embassy to the governor of their land, to acquaint him concerning the affairs of the land.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5146",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:4",
    "question": "One of the reasons Helaman sent an_____to the governor was so that they could receive provisions and strength from the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "Embassy",
    "options": ["Embassy", "Band", "Army"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5147",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites were also receiving provisions for their army and would resolve by_____to destroy Helaman and his army from time to time.",
    "answer": "Stratagem",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5148",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:7",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman waited for many_____, even until they were about to perish for the want of food.",
    "answer": "Months",
    "options": ["Seasons", "Months", "Years"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5149",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:8",
    "question": "But it came to pass that Helaman and his people did receive food, which was guarded to them by an army of two thousand men to their assistance.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5150",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:9",
    "question": "Helaman knew the reason why he and his army did not receive more men and more provisions for his people.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5151",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:9",
    "question": "Helaman and his people were grieved and also filled with fear, lest by any means the judgments of God should come upon their land, to their overthrow and utter_____.",
    "answer": "Destruction",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5152",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:10",
    "question": "Helaman and his people did pour out their_____in prayer to God; that he would strengthen them and deliver them out of the hands of their enemies.",
    "answer": "Souls",
    "options": ["Bodies", "Souls", "Heads"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5153",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lord their _____did visit the Nephites with assurances that he would deliver them.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5154",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:11",
    "question": "The Lord did speak_____to Helaman and his peoples souls, and did grant unto them great faith, and did cause them that they should hope for their deliverance in him.",
    "answer": "Peace",
    "options": ["Love", "Peace", "Loudly"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5155",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:12",
    "question": "Helaman did take courage with his small force which he had received, and was fixed with a determination to conquer their enemies.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5156",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:13",
    "question": "Helaman and his army went forth with all their might against the Lamanites, who were in the city Manti; and they did pitch their_____by the wilderness side.",
    "answer": "Tents",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5157",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass when the Lamanites saw that Helaman and his army were by the wilderness; they sent_____to see how large and strong his army was.",
    "answer": "Spies",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5158",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the Lamanites saw the Helaman and his army was not that strong, they began to make preparations of war with their numerous hosts.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5159",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____caused that his army should not sleep and did march to the city of Manti by night.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5160",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:28",
    "question": "Helaman and his army used a stratagem and did take possession of the city of Manti without the shedding of_____.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["Skin", "Blood", "Hair"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5161",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:30",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites did flee out of all the quarter of the land and carried with many women and children out of the land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5162",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:33",
    "question": "Helaman and his army did not trust in the Lord therefore, they did not receive any help from God and he did not granted unto them any victories.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5163",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:34",
    "question": "Helaman did not know why the_____government would not grant them more strength; neither did the men who came up to help him.",
    "answer": "Nephite",
    "options": ["Nephite", "Lamanite", "Zoramite"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5164",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:35",
    "question": "Helaman and his army did not murmur why the Nephite government would not send them more strength, but they wondered why they could not.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5165",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:36",
    "question": "Helaman feared that there was some_____in the government; that would not send them more assistance because he knew that the Nephites were more numerous than what they had sent.",
    "answer": "Faction",
    "options": ["Portion", "Faction", "Neither A Or B"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5166",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma58:37",
    "question": "Helaman and his army put their_____in God that he would deliver them, notwithstanding the weakness of his armies.",
    "answer": "Trust",
    "options": ["Trust", "Faith", "Heart"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5167",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:38",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman and his armies were in possession of their lands; and the_____had fled to the land of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5168",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:39",
    "question": "Helaman and his stripling warriors of the people of_____; were with him in the city of Manti.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5169",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:39",
    "question": "Helaman told Captain Moroni the Lord had supported his stripling warriors from falling by the_____; insomuch that not even one soul had not been slain.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5170",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:40",
    "question": "Helaman said that his stripling warriors had received many wounds; nevertheless they stand fast in that liberty wherewith God has made them free.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5171",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma58:40",
    "question": "Helaman said his warriors were strict to remember the Lord their God from day to_____; and they do observe to keep his statutes, and his judgments, and his commandments continually.",
    "answer": "Day",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5172",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:40",
    "question": "Helaman said his warriors’ faith is strong in the prophecies concerning that which is to come.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5173",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:41",
    "question": "Helaman told his beloved brother Moroni; “May the Lord our God, who has redeemed us and made us free, keep you continually in his presence”.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5174",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma58:41",
    "question": "Helaman closed his epistle to Moroni by writing that he was son of Alma2.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5175",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that after Moroni had received and read Helaman’s epistle, he was exceedingly rejoiced because of the welfare, and the exceeding success of_____.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5176",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma59:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was exceedingly happy that Helaman had been successful in obtaining the lands they had lost unto the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5177",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma59:2",
    "question": "Moroni let it be known among all his people in the lands round about of Helaman’s success that they might_____also.",
    "answer": "Rejoice",
    "options": ["Smile", "Rejoice", "Gossip"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5178",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni immediately sent an_____to Pahoran, desiring that he should cause men to be gathered together to strengthen Helaman.",
    "answer": "Epistle",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5179",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass when_____had sent his epistle to the land of Zarahemla, he began again to lay a plan that he might obtain the remainder of cities which the Lamanites had taken.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5180",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that while Moroni was making preparations for war, the_____attacked the people of Nephihah, who were gathered together from other cities.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5181",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma59:6",
    "question": "Those who had been compelled to flee from the land of Manti, and from other lands, had come over and jo1ned the Lamanites in this part of the Land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5182",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:7",
    "question": "The people of Nephihah were slain with an exceeding great slaughter because the Lamanites were numerous and had received strength from day to day on the orders of_____.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5183",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:8",
    "question": "The Lamanites were so numerous that the people of_____were obliged to flee before them; and they came over and jo1ned the army of Captain Moroni.",
    "answer": "Nephihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5184",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites took possession of the city of Nephihah and Captain_____was exceedingly sorrowful.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5185",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma59:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni began to doubt, because of the wickedness of the people, whether they should not fall into the hands of their_____.",
    "answer": "Brethren",
    "options": ["Brethren", "Captors", "Adversaries"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5186",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:12",
    "question": "Because of the wickedness of the Nephites; their_____captains doubted and marveled also of the success of the Lamanites over them.",
    "answer": "Chief",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5187",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma59:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain_____was angry with the government, because of their indifference concerning the freedom of their country.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5188",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____wrote again to the governor of the land which was Pahoran; who was the chief judge in the city of Zarahemla and the land.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5189",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:1",
    "question": "Captain Moroni only wrote and directed his epistle to Pahoran and not to those who had been chosen by the people to govern and manage the affairs of their war.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5190",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:2",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote his epistle by way of condemnation to those that were in charge of the affairs of their war.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5191",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that he himself, and also his men and also Helaman and his men had suffered_____sufferings.",
    "answer": "Great",
    "options": ["Small", "Great", "A Lot Of"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5192",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:3",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that his men and others had suffered hunger, _____, and fatigue, and all manner of afflictions of every kind.",
    "answer": "Thirst",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5193",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that if hunger, thirst, and fatigue, were all that they had suffered; they would not_____neither complain.",
    "answer": "Murmur",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5194",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:5",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that there had been a great slaughter among his people; while it might have otherwise been if the government would have rendered unto their armies sufficient strength.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5195",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:5",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that because the government had not rendered sufficient strength and_____; and had neglected them, they had suffered much.",
    "answer": "Succor",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5196",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:6",
    "question": "Captain Moroni and his army desired to know the cause of this exceeding great neglect; and desired to know the cause of the government’s great_____ state towards them.",
    "answer": "Thoughtless",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5197",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:7",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government concerning their thoughtless stupor, while their enemies were spreading the work of_____among them.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5198",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:8",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that the people had placed the people in the government there and looked up to them for protection, and placed them in a situation that they might have_____them.",
    "answer": "Succored",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5199",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government saying that they had withheld their provisions from them and many had fought and_____out their lives.",
    "answer": "Bled",
    "options": ["Taken", "Bled", "Sold"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5200",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:9",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that many Nephites had suffered greatly because of the great desire which they had for the_____of the people.",
    "answer": "Welfare",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5201",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told his beloved brethren that they should have stirred themselves more_____for the welfare and freedom of the people.",
    "answer": "Diligently",
    "options": ["Diligently", "Often", "Frequently"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5202",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government telling them that the blood of thousands of Nephites would come upon their_____for vengeance.",
    "answer": "Heads",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5203",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:10",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government telling them that_____had heard all the cries and sufferings of those that had been slain.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5204",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:11",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that if the government could sit upon their thrones; and think that God would deliver them because of his exceeding goodness, while they did nothing; was in vain.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5205",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:12",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote that many who had fallen by the sword were not wicked; and it was a condemnation upon those that sat in the government upon their_____.",
    "answer": "Thrones",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5206",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:13",
    "question": "For the Lord suffers the_____to be slain that his justice and judgment may come upon the wicked.",
    "answer": "Righteous",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5207",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:14",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the government not to suppose that those that had been slain were lost; but entered into the_____of God.",
    "answer": "Rest",
    "options": ["Mansions", "Rest", "Houses"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5208",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:14",
    "question": "Captain Moroni feared exceedingly that the_____of God would come upon this people because of the exceeding slothfulness and neglect of the government towards the people.",
    "answer": "Judgments",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5209",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:15",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that if it was not for the wickedness which first commenced at the head of the people, they could have withstood their_____that they could have had no power of them.",
    "answer": "Enemies",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5210",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that the_____were the cause that a war broke out among themselves; and caused much bloodshed.  King-",
    "answer": "men",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5211",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said the king-men desired power and_____among the people; and were not true to the freedom that united them.",
    "answer": "Authority",
    "options": ["Wealth", "Authority", "Riches"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5212",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:16",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said if the people would have gone out in the strength of the_____, they would have dispersed their enemies, according to the fulfilling of his word.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5213",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:17",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said the Lamanites were murdering the people and carrying their women and children captive and away, causing them to suffer all manner of afflictions.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5214",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:17",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said his people had suffered much because of great_____of the king-men who were seeking power and authority.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["Sufferings", "Swordsmanship", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5215",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:18",
    "question": "Captain Moroni would not elaborate much concerning the king-men and those that were of the head of the government because he knew that they themselves were seeking for authority.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5216",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:20",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked the heads of the government if they had forgotten the_____of the Lord their God.",
    "answer": "Commandments",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5217",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:20",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked the heads of the government it they had forgotten the many times the Lord had delivered them out of the hands of their_____.",
    "answer": "Enemies",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5218",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:22",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked the heads of the government it they supposed that they could sit upon their thrones and do nothing while tens of thousands of their brethren were being slain.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5219",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni asked the heads of the government if they supposed that God would look upon them as_____while they sit and behold the things that were happening to the people.",
    "answer": "Guiltless",
    "options": ["Guiltless", "Thoughtless", "Useless"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5220",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that God would find the heads of the government guiltless while that sat upon their thrones and did nothing while their brethren were being slain.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5221",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:23",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that they should clean their inward_____first, and then the outer vessel should be cleaned also.",
    "answer": "Vessel",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5222",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said the head of the government should repent and send forth food and men unto him and_____.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5223",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:24",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that if the head of the government would not repent and help him and Helaman; they would stop contending with the_____and cleansed the inward vessel.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5224",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:25,27",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the head of the government that unless they grant unto him his_____he would personally come after them himself.",
    "answer": "Epistle",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5225",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:27",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that he would stir up insurrections among the head of the government until all those that desired to usurp power and authority shall become_____.",
    "answer": "Extinct",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5226",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:28",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the head of the government that he did not fear their power neither their_____but that he did fear God.",
    "answer": "Authority",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5227",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:28",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that he did take his_____to defend the cause of his country, and that it was because of the iniquity of the head of the government that they had suffered so much loss.",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5228",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:29",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the head of the government that the time was at hand that the sword of_____would fall upon them and visit them even to utter destruction.",
    "answer": "Justice",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5229",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:30",
    "question": "Captain Moroni wrote to the head of the government that unless they would administer relief unto them; he would smite them with the sword.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5230",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:31",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that the Lord would not suffer that the head of the government should wax strong in their iniquities to destroy his righteous_____.",
    "answer": "People",
    "options": ["Humans", "Men", "People"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5231",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:32",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said it was the traditions of the_____fathers' that has caused a hatred towards the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5232",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:32",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said it was the traditions of the Lamanites and that their iniquity was for the love of glory and the_____things of the world.",
    "answer": "Vain",
    "options": ["Rich", "Vain", "Glorious"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5233",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:33",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that the head of the government transgressed the laws of God, and that they did know that they trampled them under their_____.",
    "answer": "Feet",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5234",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:34",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was constra1ned, according to the covenant which he had made to keep the_____of his God.",
    "answer": "Commandments",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5235",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma60:34",
    "question": "Captain Moroni told the head of the government that they should adhere to the word of God, and send speedily unto him their provisions and their men, and also help for Helaman.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5236",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma60:35",
    "question": "Captain Moroni said that the Lord would not suffer that he and his men should perish with_____.",
    "answer": "Hunger",
    "options": ["The Sword", "Hunger", "Thirst"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5237",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:36",
    "question": "Moroni told the head of the government that he was their chief captain and that he seeked not for power but to_____it down.",
    "answer": "Pull",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5238",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma60:35",
    "question": "Moroni said that he did not seek for honor of the world, but for the glory of his_____, and the freedom and welfare of his country.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5239",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that as soon as Captain Moroni had sent his epistle unto the chief governor, he received an epistle from_____.",
    "answer": "Pahoran",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5240",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:1",
    "question": "Pahoran was the chief governor of the Nephites’ land.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5241",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:2",
    "question": "Pahoran told Moroni in his_____that he did not rejoice in his great afflictions, and that it grieved his soul to read about them.",
    "answer": "Epistle",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5242",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:3",
    "question": "Pahoran told Moroni that there were those who did have joy in his afflictions.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5243",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:3",
    "question": "The people who rejoiced in the afflictions of Moroni rose up in rebellion against_____and his people who were freemen.",
    "answer": "Pahoran",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5244",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:3",
    "question": "Pahoran told Captain Moroni in his epistle that those that had risen up in rebellion against him and his people were not very numerous, and that he could take care of them.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5245",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:4",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that those that had rebelled against him were trying to take away the_____-seat from him; and were the cause of great iniquity among the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Judgment",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5246",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:4",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that those that rebelled against him used great_____, and have led away the hearts of many people; which was the cause of sore afflictions among them.",
    "answer": "Flattery",
    "options": ["Words", "Flattery", "Speeches"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5247",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:4",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that the kingmen withheld provisions, and have daunted the freemen; that was the reason they had not been able to help Captain_____and his army.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5248",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:5",
    "question": "The kingmen had driven_____from the land and he had fled to the land of Gideon, with as many men as it was possible.",
    "answer": "Pahoran",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5249",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:6",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote in his epistle to Moroni that he has sent out a_____into the land of Gideon.",
    "answer": "Proclamation",
    "options": ["Text Message", "Declaration", "Proclamation"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5250",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:7",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that the kingmen were defiant and were afraid to come to battle with him and his army.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5251",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:8",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that the kingmen had taken possession of the city of Zarahemla and had appointed a_____over them; and he had written unto the king of the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "King",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5252",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:8",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that the king of the city of Zarahemla was planning to be king over all the land after the_____would conquer all of the remaining land.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5253",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:9",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that Captain Moroni had censored him in his epistle.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5254",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:9",
    "question": "Pahoran was not angry with the words Moroni had written in his epistle; but rejoiced in the greatness of his_____.",
    "answer": "Heart",
    "options": ["Body", "Heart", "Intelligence"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5255",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:9",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that he did not seek for_____, only to retain his judgment-seat that he may preserve the rights and liberties of the people.",
    "answer": "Power",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5256",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:9",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni stating that his soul stands fast in that liberty which God had made him and his people_____.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["Free", "Better", "Victorious"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5257",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:10",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that he and his people would resist_____, even unto the shedding of blood.",
    "answer": "Wickedness",
    "options": ["Temptations", "Riches", "Wickedness"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5258",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:11",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that they would not shed the_____of their brethren if they would not rise up in rebellion and take the sword against him and his people.",
    "answer": "Blood",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5259",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:12",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that he and people would subject themselves to the yoke of_____if it was requisite with the justice of God, or if he should command them to do so.",
    "answer": "Bondage",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5260",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:13",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that God had commanded him and his people that they should put their_____in him, and he would deliver them.",
    "answer": "Trust",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5261",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:14",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni in his epistle that they should resist_____, and whatsoever evil they could not resist with their words, they should resist with their swords.",
    "answer": "Evil",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5262",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:14",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni saying that they should resist evil, and things such as rebellions and dissensions; they should resist with their_____.",
    "answer": "Swords",
    "options": ["Mouths", "Words", "Swords"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5263",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma71:14",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that they should retain their freedom; that they may rejoice in the great privilege of their church, and in the cause of the Redeemer their God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5264",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:15",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Captain_____telling him to come speedily unto him with a few of his men and leave the remainder in charge of Lehi and Teancum.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5265",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:15",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni telling him to leave Lehi and Teancum in charge to have power to conduct the war in that part of the land, according to the_____of God.",
    "answer": "Will",
    "options": ["Good", "Spirit", "Will"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5266",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:15",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote in his epistle to Moroni that the Spirit of God is also the Spirit of_____which was in both of them.",
    "answer": "Freedom",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5267",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:17",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni that they would go speedily unto the dissenters, in the strength of their God according to the faith which was in them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5268",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:18",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni that they would go forth unto Lehi and Teancum against the dissenters, and put an end to the great iniquity that was among them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5269",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:15-18, 21-62:3",
    "question": "Who was the supreme commander or the commander-in-chief of the Nephite armies?",
    "answer": "Pahoran",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5270",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:15-18, 21",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was the supreme commander or the commander-in-chief of the Nephite armies.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5271",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:19",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Moroni that he did have_____in receiving his epistle; and was concerned in what they should do, whether it should be just in him and his people to go against their brethren.",
    "answer": "Joy",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5272",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma61:20",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote in his epistle that Moroni had written that unless the kingmen and their people would repent; that they should go against them.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5273",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:21",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote to Captain Moroni that he should see to strengthen Lehi and Teancum in the_____.",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5274",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma61:21",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote the Captain Moroni should see to it that Lehi and Teancum and their people should not fear the_____, because God would deliver them.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5275",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:21",
    "question": "Pahoran wrote that God would deliver those that stood fast in that liberty wherewith God had made them_____.",
    "answer": "Free",
    "options": ["Precious", "Good", "Free"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5276",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma61:21",
    "question": "Pahoran closed his epistle to Moroni say that Moroni was his beloved_____.",
    "answer": "Brother",
    "options": ["Friend", "Brother", "Comrade"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5277",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when Moroni received the epistle from Pahoran, his heart took_____.",
    "answer": "Courage",
    "options": ["Courage", "To Beating Faster", "Sick"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5278",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:1",
    "question": "After Moroni received the epistle from Pahoran, his heart took courage, and was filled with exceeding great joy because of the faithfulness of_____.",
    "answer": "Pahoran",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5279",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:1",
    "question": "Moroni was filled with great joy because he knew that Pahoran was not a_____to the freedom and cause of their country.",
    "answer": "Traitor",
    "options": ["Man", "Traitor", "Warrior"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5280",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:2",
    "question": "Moroni did mourn exceedingly because of the iniquity of those who had driven Pahoran from the judgment-seat.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5281",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:2",
    "question": "Moroni did not mourn exceedingly because of those who had rebelled against their country and also their God.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5282",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni took a small number of men, according to the desire of Pahoran, and gave Lehi and Teancum command over the remainder of his army.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5283",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni took a small number of his men and began marching towards the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Gideon",
    "options": ["Zarahemla", "Gideon", "Neither"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5284",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:4",
    "question": "Captain Moroni raised the standard of_____in whatsoever place or land he did enter; and ga1ned whatsoever force he could in all his march towards the land of Gideon.",
    "answer": "Liberty",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5285",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:5",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____, did flock unto Captain Moroni’s standard of liberty, and did take up their swords in the defense of their freedom.",
    "answer": "Thousands",
    "options": ["Hundreds", "Thousands", "Millions"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5286",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:5",
    "question": "Thousands did flock unto Captain Moroni’s standard of liberty to defend their freedom that they might not come into_____.",
    "answer": "Bondage",
    "options": ["Slavery", "Bondage", "Prison"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5287",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:6",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni arrived in the land of Gideon and united his forces with those of_____.",
    "answer": "Pahoran",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5288",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:6",
    "question": "By uniting his forces with that of Pahoran’s, the Nephites force became stronger than those of the dissenters who had driven the freemen out of the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5289",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:6",
    "question": "What is the name of the king that the kingmen appointed to be their king?",
    "answer": "Pachus",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5290",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Pahoran and his army with down to the land of Zarahemla, and_____was slain and his men were taken prisoners, and Pahoran was restored to the judgment-seat.",
    "answer": "Pachus",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5291",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:9",
    "question": "The men of Pachus did not receive a trial according to the law of the Nephites; and also those king-men who had been taken and cast into prison.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5292",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:9",
    "question": "Those that received a trial and were found guilt of war crimes were executed according to the law.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5293",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:9",
    "question": "Those men of Pachus and those king-men who would not take up arms in the defense of their country; but would fight against it, were put to_____.",
    "answer": "Death",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5294",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:10",
    "question": "And it became expedient that the law should be strictly observed for the safety of their country; and whosoever was found denying their freedom was speedily_____according to the law.",
    "answer": "Executed",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5295",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:11",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni and Pahoran did not restore peace to the land of Zarahemla.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5296",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:11",
    "question": "After Captain Moroni and Pahoran restored peace to the land of Zarahemla; they inflicted death upon all those that were not true to the cause of freedom.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5297",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:12",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni caused that an army of six-thousand men should be sent to_____, to assist him in preserving that part of the land.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5298",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:13",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni also caused that an army of six-thousand men with food should be sent to the armies of Lehi and_____to fortify the land against the Lamanites.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5299",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni and Pahoran took a large body of men towards the land of Nephihah, being determ1ned to overthrow the_____in that city.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5300",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:15",
    "question": "Captain Moroni and Pahoran took a large body of_____of the Lamanites, and slew many of them, and took their provisions and their weapons of war.",
    "answer": "Men",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5301",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:16",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni caused that the surviving Lamanites enter a_____that they would not take up their weapons of war against the Nephites.",
    "answer": "Covenant",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5302",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:17",
    "question": "And after the surviving Lamanites had entered into this covenant; they were sent to dwell with the people of Ammon.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5303",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:17",
    "question": "The surviving Lamanites that entered into the covenant of Captain Moroni were numbered about_____thousand who had not been slain.",
    "answer": "Four",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5304",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:18",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni and his armies pitched their_____in the plains of Nephihah, which was near the city of Nephihah.",
    "options": ["Sombreros", "Hats Or (c) Tents"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5305",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:19",
    "question": "Captain Moroni was not desirous that the Lamanites should come to battle with his armies among the plains of Nephihah.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5306",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:19",
    "question": "The Lamanites did not dare come up to battle against the_____because of the greatness of their numbers and because of their exceeding great courage.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5307",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:20",
    "question": "And it came to pass that when the night came; _____went forth in the darkness of the night, to spy upon the Lamanites and also to spy in what part of the city they were in.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5308",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:21",
    "question": "When Moroni spied on the Lamanites; what direction were the Lamanites camped at which was by the entrance of the city Nephihah.",
    "answer": "East",
    "options": ["North", "West", "East"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5309",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:21",
    "question": "Moroni found out that the Lamanites were not asleep and neither were they camped out in the eastern part of the city of Nephihah which was also by its entrance.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5310",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:22",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni caused that his men marched forth into the city of_____and went over the walls, and let themselves down into the city.",
    "answer": "Nephihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5311",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:23",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni’s men used strong cords and ladders to let themselves down into the city of Nephihah; and when the morning came they were all within the walls of the city.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5312",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:24-25",
    "question": "When the Lamanites awoke and saw that they were surrounded by the Nephites; they fled out by the pass, and some were taken prisoners and others fled to the land of Moroni.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5313",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:26",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni and Pahoran obta1ned the possession of the city of_____without the loss of one soul; and there were many of the Lamanites who were slain.",
    "answer": "Nephihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5314",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:26",
    "question": "When Moroni and Pahoran obta1ned the city of Nephihah, how many Nephites were slain?",
    "answer": "None",
    "options": ["None", "Two", "Three"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5315",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:27",
    "question": "And it came to pass that many of the Lamanites who were taken prisoners by Captain Moroni and Pahoran were desirous to join the people of_____and become a free people.",
    "answer": "Ammon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5316",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:28",
    "question": "All the prisoners that were desirous to join the people of Ammon were granted according to their desires.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5317",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:29",
    "question": "All the Lamanites that jo1ned the people of Ammon did begin to labor exceedingly, tilling the ground, raising all manner of grain, and_____of every herd.",
    "answer": "Flocks",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5318",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:30",
    "question": "Because Captain Moroni had taken so many Lamanite prisoners, their armies were reduced exceedingly.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5319",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:31",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni took his army from the land of Nephihah to the land of Lehi; when the_____saw that Moroni was coming against them, they fled.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5320",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:32",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Lamanites were pursued to city to city, until they were met by Lehi and_____armies.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5321",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:33",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the armies of the Lamanites were gathered together in one body in the land of Moroni, and_____their king was also with them.",
    "answer": "Ammoron",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5322",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:34",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Moroni, Lehi and Teancum did encamp with their armies around the borders of the land of_____.",
    "answer": "Moroni",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5323",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:35",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding march of both the Nephites and Lamanites; both of their armies were not weary.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5324",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:35",
    "question": "What chief captain of one of the Nephites armies was exceedingly angry with Ammoron and blamed him and his brother for the cause of the war?",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5325",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:35",
    "question": "Teancum was exceedingly angry with Ammoron, and Amalickiah his brother, and blamed them for the great and lasting war between the Nephites and the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5326",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:35",
    "question": "The exceedingly great war between the Nephites and Lamanites caused much bloodshed and much_____among the people.",
    "answer": "Fam1ne",
    "options": ["Sickness", "Injuries", "Fam1ne"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5327",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:36",
    "question": "And it came to pass that_____went forth with a cord over the walls of the city and cast a javelin into the king’s heart and killed him.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5328",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:36",
    "question": "What was the name of one of Captain Moroni’s chief captain that put a javelin into the heart of king Ammoron and killed him?",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5329",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:36",
    "question": "One of the king’s servants pursued Teancum and killed him.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5330",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma50:35,51:3462:36",
    "question": "How many times in the Book of Mormon are we told by Mormon that Teancum slew how many kings?",
    "answer": "3",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5331",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:37",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni and Pahoran were exceedingly sorrowful when they found out the Teancum had been slain.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5332",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:37",
    "question": "Mormon writes that_____had been; a man who had fought valiantly for his country, and a true friend of liberty.",
    "answer": "Teancum",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5333",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma62:37",
    "question": "Mormon writes that Teancum not only was a man that fought valiantly for his country; but had also suffered very many exceedingly great_____.",
    "answer": "Afflictions",
    "options": ["Sores", "Fevers", "Afflictions"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5334",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:38",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni marched forth with his armies towards the_____, and did slay them with a great slaughter.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5335",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:39-40",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites had wars, and bloodshed's, and fam1nes, and afflictions, for the space of many years; and were spared because of the_____of the righteous.",
    "answer": "Prayers",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5336",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:40",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the Nephites had many murders, contentions, and dissentions, and all manner of_____among them; but were spared because of the prayers of the righteous.",
    "answer": "Iniquity",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5337",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:40",
    "question": "Because the prayers of the righteous, the Nephites were spared of many things.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5338",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:41",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding great length of the war between the Nephites and the Lamanites many of the people had become hardened.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5339",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:41",
    "question": "Because of the exceeding great length of the war between the people; many were softened because of their afflictions, insomuch that they did humble themselves before God.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5340",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:42-43",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni and Helaman, and Pahoran established peace among the people of Nephi; and Moroni yielded up the command of his armies to Moronihah.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5341",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:43",
    "question": "What was the name of the man that Captain Moroni yielded up the command of his armies to?",
    "answer": "Moronihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5342",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:43",
    "question": "Moronihah was not a son of Captain Moroni but was the son of one of his chief captains.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5343",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:43",
    "question": "Captain Moroni retired unto his own house that he might spend the remainder of his day’s in_____.",
    "answer": "Peace",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5344",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:44",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Pahoran did return to his judgment-seat, and _____did take it upon himself to preach the word of God unto the people.",
    "answer": "Helaman",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5345",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:45",
    "question": "Helaman and his brethren did declare the word of God with much_____unto the convincing of many people of their wickedness, which did cause them to repent and be baptized.",
    "answer": "Power",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5346",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:46-47",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the church of God was established throughout the land and regulations were made concerning the law.  And their judges and chief judger were chosen.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5347",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:48",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the_____began to prosper again in the land, and began to multiply and to wax exceedingly strong.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5348",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:49",
    "question": "Notwithstanding their riches, or their strength, or their prosperity, the Nephites were not lifted up in the pride of their eyes.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5349",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:49",
    "question": "The Nephites began to not be lifted in the pride of their eyes; neither were they slow to remember the Lord their _____; but they did humble themselves exceedingly before him.",
    "answer": "God",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5350",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma62:50",
    "question": "The Nephites did remember how great things the Lord had done for them; delivering them from death, and from bonds, and from prisons.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5351",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:51",
    "question": "The_____did pray unto the Lord continually, insomuch that the Lord did bless them, according to his word, so that they did wax strong and prosper in the land.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5352",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma62:52",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Helaman died and went the way of the earth in the 35th year of the reign of the_____over the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Judges",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5353",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:1",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Shiblon took possession of those sacred things which had been delivered unto Helaman by_____.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5354",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:2",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that_____was a just man, and did walk uprightly before God; and he did observe to do good continually.",
    "answer": "Shiblon",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5355",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:2",
    "question": "Mormon wrote that Shiblon was not a just man, and did not keep the commandments of the Lord his God; and neither did his brother.",
    "answer": "false",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5356",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:3",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Captain Moroni died. And thus ended the 36th year of the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5357",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:4",
    "question": "And it came to pass that a large company of men and their families departed out of the land of_____ into the land which was northward.",
    "answer": "Zarahemla",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5358",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:5",
    "question": "Mormon writes that_____was an exceedingly curious man.",
    "answer": "Hagoth",
    "options": ["Helaman", "Alma", "Hagoth"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5359",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:5",
    "question": "Hagoth is known to us as an exceedingly curious man, and also a_____.",
    "answer": "Ship Builder",
    "options": ["Carpenter", "Ship Builder", "Great Warrior"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5360",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:5",
    "question": "What is the name of the ship builder that built a ship and launched it forth into the west sea?",
    "answer": "Hagoth",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5362",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:6",
    "question": "Hagoth and many Nephites did enter the ship and did sail forth with many provisions; and they took their course_____.",
    "answer": "Northward",
    "options": ["Westward", "Southward", "Northward"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5363",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:7",
    "question": "And the first ship that Hagoth built did return and many more people did enter into it; and they also took many provisions, and set out again to the land northward.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5364",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:8",
    "question": "After the second trip that many of the Nephites took to the land_____; they were never heard of again.",
    "answer": "Northward",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5365",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:8",
    "question": "Mormon writes that he supposed that the second ship did go down in the depths of the_____and drowned.",
    "answer": "Sea",
    "options": ["River", "Sea", "Ocean"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5366",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:8",
    "question": "And it came to pass that another ship did sail forth and Mormon writes that where she went we do not know of.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5367",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Shiblon died and his younger brother_____, did go forth to the land northward to carry provisions unto the people who had gone forth into the land.",
    "answer": "Corianton",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5368",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:10",
    "question": "It became expedient that Shiblon confer those_____things, before his death, upon the son of Helaman, who was called Helaman.",
    "answer": "Sacred",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5369",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:11",
    "question": "Shiblon entrusted Helaman with the sacred things of the Nephites; and he was called Helaman after the name of his father.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5370",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:12",
    "question": "Mormon writes that the engravings which were in the possession of Helaman were written and sent forth among the children of_____ throughout the land.",
    "answer": "Men",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5371",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:12",
    "question": "Mormon writes that the engravings were sent forth among the children of men, except those parts which had been commanded by_____; that they should not go forth.",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5372",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:13",
    "question": "Mormon writes that the sacred things were to be kept sacred, and handed down for one generation to_____.",
    "answer": "Another",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5373",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:14",
    "question": "And it came to pass that in the 39th year of the reign of the judges; there were some dissenters who had gone forth unto the_____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5374",
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Alma63:14",
    "question": "The dissenters of the Nephites went forth among the Lamanites to stir them up again to anger against the_____.",
    "answer": "Nephites",
    "options": ["Zoramites", "Amalickites", "Nephites"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5375",
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Alma63:15",
    "question": "And it came to pass that an army of Lamanites came down with a numerous army to war against the army of_____and they suffered a great loss.",
    "answer": "Moronihah",
    "options": ["fill"]
  },
  {
    "id": "5376",
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Alma63:16-17",
    "question": "And it came to pass that the account of Alma, and Helaman his son, and also Shiblon, who was his son, ended in the 39th year of the reign of the judges over the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "true",
    "options": ["true", "false"]
  }
]
